Oh no,
I don't remember the recipe.
If only there was somewhere I could find that information!
And now there is! It's called... book!
Did you say book?
Why I did!
Here you go!
How convenient!
I feel suffocated by the weight of my past mistakes and the hurt I've caused my friends.
If only there was a way to atone for what I've done.
Did someone say "book"?
– No! I said-
– Yes you did, you said book, we all heard. You're welcome!
I'm bored.
I'm cured!
So, in conclusion, read a book!
Because no matter the problem,
books fix everything!
- I love books, but I wouldn't say they fix everythi-
- EVERYTHING!
And that's...
Good to know!
Good to know?
Hey guys! Check out this weird book I found buried under a dead oak tree.
"Necronomicon: Open at your own peril!"
Heh, that's a funny name for a book.
Ruby, no!
Well this is mysterious...
Sky fish?
Score!
I did not expect that.
Lights on.
Lights off.
What's up with the flippin' sun?
I didn't do it!
Cool!
Wanna get some noodles then take a long nap?
It's like you read my mind.
This is awesome!
We're gonna be best friends and do everything together and be the coolest guys ever-
Yeah, I'm not really looking for commitment right now, I'm kinda just focusing on my career.
Oh...
Really?
It's not you, it's me.
But... you is me...
What is this?
Are you challenging me, button?
Very well, I accept your shiny red challenge!
Ha-ha!
Check and mate, button.
Neo...
Do you realize what this means?
I can use this mysterious red button as a weapon to finally defeat that nosy Red!
All I have to is... whoops!
Hey look!
A mysterious red button that we don't know what it does or anything about it!
LET'S PUSH IT!
Are you sure that's a good idea?
Come on! What's the worst that could happen?