Man, Marty, I feel like an idiot. No humans are gonna fall for this.
Mike, trust me, humans will believe anything.
Oh! Here comes some now.
Quick, get in character.
Hey there!
I'm just a human dude.
Me too! I'm also a people.
Riiight...
Uh, we took a wrong turn, do you guys know where the bank is?
Sure!
We can... show you the way.
All you have to do is...
let us in.
That is a super hard pass.
Nice try, "human" dudes.
I told you it wouldn't work, Marty!
Of course not! You came on too strong.
I'm just so hungry for violence and evil!
Oh, here comes another car.
Be cool this time?
Hi there boys. Can I offer you a lift?
I've got...
...candy?
Hey, isn't that...?
Shh!
Don't ruin this for us, she's got candy!
We'd love a ride!
My nefarious scheme is going exactly as planned!
What a coincidence, so is ours.
Wait a minute...
Mangy dingoes!
How do I keep running into such losers?!
Ahem...
So you guys want to share a taxi car?
That sounds reasonable!
No!!
Come on, Weiss! I need to pick up my new coat from the tailor.
Or... so it "seams."
Y'know, come to think of it, I actually do need some new boots.
Yeah, one of those isn't...
..."right!"
Oh, that was good.
That...
that wasn't even... "punny!"
Hm, she does have a...
"point!"
Okay!
That's all I can take now.
Huh, I guess she just wasn't...
"feline" it?
Oh, you've gotta be "kitten" me!
That was purrfect!
Literally!
Hello, everyone.
We have a lot of fun here on RWBY Chibi,
but one thing's for certain,
and that's that puns are no laughing matter.
If you or someone you care about is known to use puns,
please seek professional help.
It's never too late to change.