Zwei, you gotta take your medicine, buddy.
Dog! This stuff is more expensive than anything I take! You chew this up or so help me...
Dad, you can't just shove the pill in his mouth like a reverse-piñata, there's a method.
You mean using peanut butter?
You're so primitive.
No, let me demonstrate.
Zwei, you are a loved and valued member of this family, we need to take action so that you can live your best life.
You think that's gonna work on a dog?
No, it's just supposed to distract him.
Now! Take the shot!
One shot...
...one pill.
Direct hit! I repeat, direct hit!
Did you see that?!
Woah, you girls are so sneaky. I'm impressed!
Yeah, you should see how we sneak a peek at our birthday presents early every year.
You... what?!
Uh oh... Secondary target!
Take the shot, Ruby! Take the shot!
I can't believe you, girls-
Release that book at once!
You probably don't even read.
Don't worry, you can borrow it afterward.
I'm underlying all the "good" parts.
I demand noodles of a delicious nature and in a timely manner.
This is unacceptable!
It's a shame you didn't get here a litte...
...sooner.
I think you'll find my report quite thorough, if disturbing.
I spared no grisly detail.
Rampant bookstore chaos and...
...noodle-related mayhem?
It got pretty wild there towards the end.
Oh I'm sorry, did you want some?
Shameful. Just shameful.
I couldn't agree more!
I propose a leash and random electric shocks to modify his behavior.
I'm referring to the time and energy you two waste fighting with each other.
You do realize you're on the same side?
I suppose... technackly.
Whatever.
Qrow!
Okay, fine! Go team!
Can I leave now?
I want you both to shake hands and apologize.
I will if she will.
Due to my professionalism and... incredible self control, I'm willing to let bygones be bygones.
Too slow, Ice Queen!
That does it! You're DEAD MEAT!
You know, flirting was a lot less destructive in my day.
Stop messing with my hair!
Like you can't even tell!