- [Narrator] This is how the war begins.
- [Commander] All wings engage!
Interceptors three and four,
take bogeys 2 o'clock, angel six.
- [Male Pilot] Ma'am, do you see that?
- [Female Pilot] I see it.
- [Male Pilot] Contact. Hostile nanotech.
- Shit.
- [Pilot] Seal your cockpits!
Do not engage!
- [Narrator] This is not a skirmish.
This is not airspace confusion.
This is not a terrorist action.
This is it.
The Union's making their play.
Stay close, move fast
The darkness cannot last
No hope, no path
But we’ve got a dream to catch
And we can not wait
Trust the way we’re made
The sparrow’s born to fly
The mountains tower
The river knows to reach the sea
Rain will help the flowers be
We’re the same you and me
The lightning doesn’t take advice from anyone
The willow doesn’t need to learn to stand
As sun seeks day
We'll find our way
And we’ll catch that dream together someday soon
We’re rising like the moon
- I was relieved to hear
that you came to your senses, Miss Schnee.
Many of us were devastated when we heard
you would be attending Beacon Academy.
Knowing that you'll be returning to Atlas
just warms my old heart.
- [Weiss] It was time
to get my act together
and go back to my roots.
- Oh I can't wait to see you
follow in your sister's footsteps.
- Absolutely.
- I'm sending two of my best guards
to personally escort you.
Make sure General
Ironwood hears that part.
- Allow me to assist you with your bag.
My, what a heavy bag!
- That's alright.
- Nonsense.
- Allow me to assist as well!
- I can take care of it by myself.
- Just like we practiced.
Oh no!
Look at that,
he's just going to miss you so much!
You should hurry on out of here.
- A crying child?
- We must console it!
- That was close.
- [Ruby] Is everything okay?
- [Maria] Call me heavy.
It's all muscle!
I'll show them a thing or two about heavy.
- We're on board.
- Alright, we'll all watch our scrolls.
The second Weiss is out of
range of the Comm Tower,
that'll mean she's out of
range of the radar too.
- [Yang] And that's when Blake steps in.
We're almost at the drop off.
- Okay, remember.
One, the radar box is separate
from the rest of the
communications equipment.
So if you disconnect it properly,
it won't take out comms
for the rest of the city.
Two, this conversation never happened.
- Don't worry, this isn't the first time
I've disabled Atlas security.
- Never happened.
- You sure I shouldn't come with?
- More intruders means we're
more likely to be seen.
Besides, stealth isn't exactly your, um...
I mean, you're great and I'll hurry back!
- Go.
- [Blake] Heading in
on foot, won't be long.
- Yes, it's all going to plan!
I mean, roger.
- Hey, this is gonna work.
- [Ruby] Yeah.
- [Guard] Miss Schnee!
For your own safety, we must request...
What?
Traitor!
This parachute won't excuse
you of your treachery!
- And you're sure you can fly this?
- Missy, I was the Grimm Reaper!
What part of best
huntress of her generation
don't you understand?
- Right, but your eyes.
- You were saying.
- That you said your eyes were
in desperate need of repair!
- Bup bup bup.
- But!
- Bup!
- Alright guys, this is it.
Blake, you're up.
Blake?
Yang, what's going on?
- I don't know.
- Ma'am, we've got something on radar.
- And who would be foolish enough
to enter our airspace unannounced?
- Apparently us, ma'am.
Manta 5-1, this is Argus Base.
We see you've circled back.
What's your status, over.
- Why can they see us?
- Somebody dropped the ball.
Don't worry, I've worked
with Atlas forces before.
I know their jargon.
Argus Base, this is Manta 5-1.
Feel free to gaff off.
Thought we were going to scrub due to FOD,
but we're back up and green
across the board, over.
- [Man] Manta 5-1 return
to base immediately,
or you will be treated as hostile, over.
- I thought you said
you knew their jargon!
- [Man] Jargon was fine,
but our pilots aren't elderly women.
- Huh, well they got me there!
My mind really is going!
Why would you kids let me fly this thing?
- [Cordovin] Calavera!
You and those insolent children
are up to something, aren't you?
You thought you could
undermine my authority?
If you don't return my ship this instant,
I will make an example out of you.
I will show you the true might of Atlas!
- You hear that, Cordo?
That's the sound of me not caring!
- Ruby, we're in trouble.
Cordo's onto us, and Maria isn't helping!
Why is the radar still up?
- We don't know.
Blake isn't responding.
- What do we do?
- [Yang] Keep the ship in one piece.
- Maybe we should fly over
to help Yang and Blake first?
- Damn it!
Cordo's gonna scramble her fighters.
We've got maybe 90 seconds
before they're in the air,
and all over Weiss and Maria.
This is all my fault.
- What are you talking about?
Your semblance?
- Every choice I've ever
made has led me here,
and I've dragged you along with me.
Oz, myself, the others.
We're responsible for the
mess the world's in now.
I shouldn't have come, shouldn't
have let any of you come.
What was I thinking?
- We're all in this together,
and we're all going to do the best we can.
That's all anyone can do.
And I know it's what
you've always aimed for.
We would've come whether
or not you'd let us,
so stop talking like
we're your responsibility!
We're not!
But we could still use
Qrow Branwen on our side.
- Hm.
How did you grow up so fast?
- I had good role models.
- [Weiss] Guys?
She's not sending fighters.
- [Cordovin] Clearly the
people have forgotten
that they live in peace thanks to
the awesome might of Atlas!
- Is Cordovin piloting that?
- Consider this a reminder!
- Are you okay?
- I am, but she's clearly lost her mind!
- And that was merely a warning shot!
All Atlas personnel standby,
and watch how your leader maintains order!
- It's time you asked
yourselves, children.
Do you truly wish to defy me?
- Hurry back, Weiss.
I need you on the ground if we're gonna
take this thing down.
- Why is the radar up?
- It's nice to finally
have time to ourselves.
Don't you think?
- Leave me alone!
- But I've waited so long.
For you to be away from them.
- Why did you have to come into
my life and ruin everything?
- You stalked me across Anima!
I don't want anything
to do with your life!
- Let go of the past, Adam.
Do it for yourself.
- Just forget it all?
Is that what you did to me?
You just threw our memories away?
- Adam!
- I let you go once already, Blake.
I'm never making that mistake again.