Stay close, move fast
The darkness cannot last
No hope, no path
But we’ve got a dream to catch
And we can not wait
Trust the way we’re made
The sparrow’s born to fly
The mountains tower
The river knows to reach the sea
Rain will help the flowers be
We’re the same you and me
The lightning doesn’t take advice from anyone
The willow doesn’t need to learn to stand
As sun seeks day
We'll find our way
And we’ll catch that dream together someday soon
We’re rising like the moon
(suspenseful music)
(gasping for breath)
(eerie music)
(footsteps)
- Gods, are you okay?
Where did you?
(gasps)
(basket hitting ground)
- [Ruby] We need to
take the relic to Atlas?
- That's what Oz said.
- You've got to be joking?
- [Nora] I mean bright side
we finally get out of this house.
(sighs)
- Well trust me, I'm not
crazy about it either.
And without the Spring
Maiden here to seal the relic
back in its vault, it's our best option.
- Atlas may be the safest
kingdom we have at the moment,
but their borders are closed.
General Ironwood called everyone back.
- Eh, not everyone.
The city of Argus is a ways north of us
and it's the primary trading
port between Anima and Solitas.
They've got the largest Atlas
military base outside of the kingdom.
There's no way they'd leave it abandoned
and if we play our cards right
I think there's a good chance
we could convince them
to escort us straight to Ironwood.
- I mean we do have the missing Heiress
to the Schnee Dust Company.
- Ex-heiress actually.
- True, true.
But if there's a chance of
reward money I say we go for it.
(frustrated sigh)
- [Oscar] Hopefully the
first option will suffice.
- Glad to see you're feeling better.
- Likewise, and while
I'm sure we could all use
more time to recover, I'm
afraid time is of the essence.
- Right, as long as that
thing's out in the open
its power could fall
into the wrong hands.
- Speaking of, what does it do exactly?
Qrow never really told us.
- Of course.
The relic of knowledge has a wonderful,
and incredibly dangerous ability.
Its user can ask any question,
and the lamp will provide an answer.
- Intriguing.
- That's incredible.
- Indeed, however it's
not without drawbacks.
The lamp cannot tell you of events
that have yet to happen.
And it will only ever
answer three questions...
every 100 years.
- Well, I guess that's not so bad.
Adds a lot of pressure though.
- Then let's put it to a vote.
What should we ask first?
Oh!
Can we ask for more questions?
- They're not wishes.
- (chuckles) I'm afraid
you won't be able to ask
it anything at the moment.
The questions were used
before I sealed it away.
- Well, at least now we know what it is.
And we'll be sure to keep it safe.
- Great, this is just great.
We're stranded.
We lost a third of our party.
And we have gained a defenseless old lady.
- My name is Maria Calavera,
and I am not defenseless.
I'm just a little hard of hearing
and blind without my eyes.
That are in desperate need of repair.
Okay, I'm starting to see your point.
- Yang, knock it off, will ya?
If we lose our cool now
we'll just be inviting even more Grimm.
- Does that even matter?
Apparently we've been attracting
Grimm since we left Haven.
- Oh and how could I forget about that?
What happened to no more
lies and half-truths?
- Yeah, I think it's time
we got an explanation.
I did not lie to you.
- Well you certainly didn't tell us
everything about the relic.
- Please, now is not the time.
- No, we're past that.
I wanna know why you're still
not telling us everything.
- It is true that the Grimm
are attracted to the relics.
It's faint, but undeniable.
I believe it has to do with their origin,
but I'm not entirely sure.
Regardless, I feared
that making you all aware
would only add anxiety and negativity.
It seemed like the safer option.
- You know, I'm getting real tired
of people choosing what's best for me.
- Is that why you chose to lie to everyone
about Lionheart too?
- Yes, as a matter of fact, I believed
the Kingdom of Mistral
deserved better than the truth.
And I believed Leonardo
deserved to be remembered
for his lifetime of service,
and not the unfortunate missteps he made
in his final years.
- Missteps?
- What professor Lionheart
did was reprehensible.
I am not here to argue differently,
but does one lapse in
judgment truly negate
all of his good?
Do we not all have regrets?
You may have met Professor Lionheart,
but you never met the man he
was before Salem found him.
- Look we're supposed
to be in this together.
You can trust us.
We're not gonna turn our backs on you.
- Do you really think Leo was the first?
That he didn't say those
exact same words to me?
I'm sorry but you have
to understand that my
behaviors are backed by experience.
I'm not saying that I have reason
to think you will betray me.
I'm saying that I have reasons
for the things that I do.
The secrets I keep.
The reason I...
Where's the relic?
- Right here.
It got scattered in the crash.
- Please, hand it over.
- So all those times
you talked about having
faith in humanity, that
was just for everyone else?
(sighs)
- That's not what I meant to suggest.
Miss Rose, the relic is a
powerful item and I simply
feel as though it is my burden to bear.
- But you said it couldn't
do anything right now.
- Why does it matter who carries it?
- I need you to listen to me.
- Oz?
- Hurry.
He's trying to stop you.
- Stop her from what?
- He's afraid
you'll find out what he's...
hiding.
Ugh!
Her name is Jinn.
Say her name to summon her.
- Her name?
(wind howling)
Jinn.
- What?
(mystical music)
(moans)
- Wonderful.
Tell me, what knowledge do you seek?
(footsteps)
(suspenseful music)
-[Newscaster] The perpetrators, Cinder Fall,
Hazel Rainart, Emerald Sustrai, and Mercury Black,
have still not been seen since the attack
and are presumed to have fled the city.
The Mistral police department is offering a reward to any citizen...
(rain and thunder)
(market chatter)
(foreboding music)
(animal screeching)
(footsteps)
(creaking floorboards)
- That's far enough.
(liens clatter)
- Okay.
- You're Lil' Miss Malachite?
- I'm Lil' Miss Gon'-Skin-You-Alive
if you ever take that tone with me again.
Looks like your life's savings.
- It was somebody's.
- (laughs) Cute.
What do you want for it?
(electronic beep)
- [Cinder] I'm looking
for these travelers.
- Well sweetheart, you
came to the right place.
(gasps)
(chuckles) A little jumpy today, hmm?
You know I used to be afraid of spiders.
Want to know what I did about it?
- Learn to kill them?
- Oh no, the world needs spiders.
I just made the spiders work for me.
Give us a week.
We'll find your travelers.
(footsteps)
- Lil' Miss, we already
know where they are.
That big guy asked about 'em last week.
- I know we know,
but what we don't know
is who here in Mistral
might be asking about her.
(clicking)
(electronic flutter)
- I am Jinn.
A being created by the God
of Light to aid humanity
in its pursuit of knowledge.
I've been graced with
the ability to answer
three questions every 100 years.
You're in luck, as I am
still able to answer--
- That's enough!
-- two questions this era.
- (chuckles) It's a pleasure
to see you again old man.
- Ruby, please.
Don't.
- Hey.
Do whatever you think is right kiddo.
- Jinn?
What is Ozpin hiding from us?
- No!
-(gasps)
- Wha-- what?
Weiss?
Yang?
- Blake?
- Ruby?
Ruby?
- Yang?
- [Jinn] Once upon a time
there stood a lonely tower
that sheltered a lonely girl.
Named,
Salem.