- [Narrator] This is how the war begins.
- All wings engaged.
Interceptors Three and Four:
Take bogies two o'clock, angel six.
- Ma'am, do you see that?
- I see it.
- [Man] Contact, hostile nanotech.
- Shit.
- Seal your cockpits.
Do not engage!
- [Narrator] This is not a skirmish.
This is not airspace confusion.
This is not a terrorist action.
This is it.
The Union's making their play.
Stay close, move fast
The darkness cannot last
No hope, no path
But we’ve got a dream to catch
And we can not wait
Trust the way we’re made
The sparrow’s born to fly
The mountains tower
The river knows to reach the sea
Rain will help the flowers be
We’re the same you and me
The lightning doesn’t take advice from anyone
The willow doesn’t need to learn to stand
As sun seeks day
We'll find our way
And we’ll catch that dream together someday soon
We’re rising like the moon
- I hate being kept in the dark like this.
- Yeah, Cinder was a pain,
but at least she kept us filled in.
- Can I ask you something?
- You're gonna (grunts).
- Why did you come with us,
the night Cinder and I found you?
- Why are you asking--
- Just answer the question.
- (grunts) Just made sense.
- [Emerald] It made sense?
- All my life, my father
trained me to be a killer,
an assassin like him.
And then moments after
I killed him (grunts),
you two showed up looking for someone
with my exact skills (grunts).
Just felt like it was
meant to be (grunts).
- [Emerald] That's it?
- Hey, what's your problem?
- I mean, there has to
be something you want
from this, right?
- Salem's promised us everything.
We win this thing for her,
we'll be top dogs in her new world.
What more do you want?
- I just...
(sighs) Cinder was the
only family I ever had.
She cared about me, taught me things.
But without her here,
I don't know if what we're doing--
- Wake up, already.
Cinder doesn't care about you.
She doesn't care about either of us.
- You don't know what
you're talking about!
- You're in denial.
And if you're gonna start having a crisis
of identity or some crap,
keep me out of it.
I'm sorry you didn't have
a mommy that loved you.
But I had a father who hated me (grunts).
He never went easy on me.
Every day of training was a beating.
And when I unlocked my semblance,
he stole it with his.
"This is a crutch."
"This makes you weak."
He told me I could have
it back when I was strong.
So I got strong.
But I never got it back.
I've had to work harder than anyone
to get where I am.
You may not like it here without Cinder,
but I think I'm right
where I'm supposed to be.
- (laughing)
- Oh yes, the world is mean,
and I'm a big, bad man
now just like the others.
- How long have you been standing there?
- All you ever learned
was pain and violence,
and now you're too afraid to leave it.
Such a tragedy.
- You don't know me.
- Hey!
- Shh, shh, shh, shh, shh.
I want to tell you both a little secret.
Your question is all wrong.
- (laughs)
- What?
- What do you want from this?
Children, please, if you're not loving
what you're doing, then
you're in the wrong field.
- So, what?
Are you saying we should just leave?
- (gasps) Oh no, no, no, no (laughs),
you can't do that.
- Then what did you come here for?
- To say farewell.
There's been a change in plans.
Her Grace must act swiftly
if we are to prevail.
If General Ironwood comes to his senses
and calls upon aid from Vacuo,
all may be lost for us.
And so the good doctor
and I are being sent
to Atlas to prepare.
- Prepare for what?
- Tyrian!
It's time.
- Do what makes you happy, children.
(sighs) Please?
I'm begging you.
(ominous music)
- [Jaune] Oscar!
- Oscar!
- The city's enormous.
He could've gone anywhere.
- This is all my fault.
I overreacted.
- I still don't really
understand what happened.
Was it about the mission?
- It's kind of hard to talk about.
- I know, I know.
Top secret.
Did he do something wrong?
- No, he didn't.
We just got some new information,
and it's going to be a lot
harder than we thought.
- I mean, if it was easy,
then it wouldn't be important, right?
- [Ren] I think we're
all just a bit unsure
of what to do next.
- You could stay in Mistral,
get your licenses at Haven
and come back to Argus.
There's a lot of good you can do here.
I know your mission is important.
But it's not like you're
the only ones who can do it.
It's not the only
mission that needs doing.
- It's not that simple.
- Well (sighs), I should go
pick up Adrian from daycare.
I'll let Terra know what's happened,
and we'll meet you later.
Good luck.
- Hey, there's a cafe over there.
Why don't we get something to warm up?
- I'm okay.
You two go on ahead.
- You don't want anything?
- We'll be right back.
Once like a dream
You looked at me
And everything
Felt new
Some people fall in love for life
Others never get it right
Love's fickle when it calls
One thing that I know for sure
Longer than our lives endure
- [Woman] It's really beautiful, isn't it?
You're my
Forever Fall
- Yeah.
Why here?
- She trained here, Sanctum Academy.
Everyone was crushed when
she chose Beacon over Haven.
No one wanted to see her go,
but it was where she wanted to be.
I'm just glad she was surrounded
by such amazing people.
- She should be standing here.
- She is.
She understood that she had
a responsibility to try.
I don't think she would regret her choice,
because a Huntress would understand
that there really wasn't a choice to make.
And a Huntress is what
she always wanted to be.
- Pyrrha never got the chance to graduate.
But she was a Huntress.
- Thank you.
- [Ren] Jaune!
- [Nora] Jaune, why did you--
- I'm sorry.
I've been a terrible leader
and a terrible friend, and I--
- Jaune, this has to stop.
- We heard what you said
to Cinder, at Haven.
You're not being fair to yourself.
We love you, just like we loved Pyrrha.
We're teammates, family.
- We don't want to lose you too.
- I think --
I think she knew she wasn't going to win,
that she might not come out alive,
but she also knew she was
the only one that could try.
- So she did.
- Maybe we should too.
- Yeah, we should.
- Pyrrha may not be by our side anymore,
but we can fight like she is.
- And in a way,
she will be.
- We should check back in, at the house.
Come on.
- Thank you.
- [Yang] I've never seen him this bad.
- Come on, let's get him up.
- Why am I on the stairs?
- Probably because no
one's home, Uncle Qrow.
We've been out looking for Oscar.
- Oscar?
- I'm sure this looks
great to the neighbors.
- No luck?
- No, you?
- Don't worry.
We aren't going to Atlas without him.
- We?
- Sorry we won't be staying.
- No, you're not.
- How about we get out of the cold?
- [Oscar] Oh, I was wondering
when you'd get back.
- [All] Oscar!
- Huh?
- You had us worried sick.
- Are you okay?
- What are you wearing?
- Uh--
- Is something cooking?
- Oh, uh, yeah,
I thought maybe you guys
would appreciate a hot meal
after spending all day
looking for me, apparently.
- It's my fault we were all
out there in the first place.
Oscar, I am so sorry for earlier.
I was way, way out of
line, and what I said--
- No, it's okay.
These past few days, I've been scared
of the same things you were.
I don't know how much
longer I'm going to be me.
But I did some thinking,
and I do know that I want to
do everything I can to help
with whatever time I have left.
- Good.
This team isn't the
same without you, Oscar.
(alarm blares)
- (gasps) The casserole!
- We're on it, chef.
(alarm blares)
- Uh, combat gear looks good.
Where are you going now?
- I don't want to get in
the way of your celebration.
- You've been gone all day.
Just sit with us.
- (sighs) Look, Ruby,
I'm glad you kids worked out, uh,
whatever all that was.
But the fact is, we're not a
single step closer to Atlas.
- Actually, I think I have an idea.
But it's sort of a
no-going-back kind of idea.
- Well, let's hear it.
- With Cordo on watch,
only Atlas airships have the clearance
to leave for Solitas.
So we steal an Atlas airship.
- That's not just breaking the law.
That's, that's definitely worse.
- How would we even get onto the airfield?
- That part I haven't
quite figured out yet.
But I--
- Okay, stop!
Just stop!
Look, if this thing goes south,
it's not something we can
just fight our way out of.
This is the Atlas military
we're talking about.
(sighs) For your sake,
just drop this.
- I want to hear him out.
- Ruby--
- I want to hear him out!
I know you're trying to protect us,
that you're afraid we can't do it,
but right now, I don't
really care what you think!
Just because you don't have an idea,
doesn't mean we're out of options.
Oz hasn't been here to tell us what to do,
but we still managed
to get this far anyway.
We've been in bad situations before,
and we didn't need an
adult to come save us
or tell us what to do.
We just did it our way.
And I say we do it our way.
And if you think you can
keep up with us kids,
we'd be happy to have you.
- Looks like you didn't give
her enough credit either.
Once like a dream
You looked at me
And everything
Felt new