Stay close, move fast
The darkness cannot last
No hope, no path
But we’ve got a dream to catch
And we can not wait
Trust the way we’re made
The sparrow’s born to fly
The mountains tower
The river knows to reach the sea
Rain will help the flowers be
We’re the same you and me
The lightning doesn’t take advice from anyone
The willow doesn’t need to learn to stand
As sun seeks day
We'll find our way
And we’ll catch that dream together someday soon
We’re rising like the moon
- It should get us to Solitas.
After that you might
want to try materializing
yourself some snow boots.
You know, Neo,
someone once asked me if
I believed in destiny.
And I'm happy to say I still do.
- [Air Control] All units be
advised, Leviathan-class Grimm
has submerged but is still on approach.
Preparing hard light shields, over!
- [Pilot] We're getting
slammed by hostiles out here!
Where is Cordovin?
- [Cordovin] This is your fault!
Do you hear me?
- [Yang] Ruby!
- Yang, Blake!
Are you okay?
- [Blake] What happened?
- Was that a giant Grimm?
- Yes, and we just ruined the only
thing capable of stopping it.
- This is your fault!
Your fault!
- [Soldier] Ma'am, what's your status?
We need an answer, over.
- Your fault.
- [Blake] I'm so sorry.
- Don't be.
This isn't on you.
- But--
- You're safe, that's all that matters.
- I suppose I have to be
the bad guy and say it.
Getting the lamp to Atlas
is still our top priority.
And right now we have
the perfect opportunity
to head straight for it.
We may not get another chance like this.
- No way!
- We can't leave, not like this.
- It's like you said,
a Huntress is supposed
to protect others to the bitter end.
- We need to head for the Leviathan.
Jaune, can you and Ren be
ready to mask our ship?
- I think we can manage.
- Got a few ideas?
- I've got one.
- Eyes up, everybody, it's back.
- [Pilot] Argus Base, this is Manta 3-4.
Leviathan has hit the
shallows and resurfaced.
We need those shields up now, over!
- [Pilot] Target stopped, engaging, over!
- It tore straight through.
- [Air Control] All squadrons,
fall back to evacuation procedures.
Disengage Leviathan!
I repeat, disengage, over!
- No, wait!
- [Qrow] Ruby!
- We can stop it!
- [Air Control] Who is this?
Identify yourself!
- I'm a Huntress.
My team and I are heading to the Leviathan
and can weaken it for you to attack.
- We can?
- I can.
- Ruby, when I said trial by fire--
- I did it at Beacon and at the farm.
- You really think you can do it now?
- I don't have a choice.
- [Air Control] Manta 5-1,
your ship is currently flagged as hostile.
You will receive no support, over.
- Fine, we'll do it alone if we have to.
We can hit it while it's
stopped at the next barrier.
Ren, you're up!
- We're too late, pull up!
- Damn it!
- That's all I've got!
- It's on the move again.
We need to stop it!
- What do we do?
- Eyes on us, ugly!
- Is it working?
- Unfortunately, yes, hang on!
- Okay, okay, you can do this.
You have to do this.
- [Yang] Ruby?
Ruby, hurry, something--
(earpiece clicking)
- What?
- Why'd it turn away?
- No, no, no, no!
Jinn!
I'm sorry.
I don't have a question for you.
I just,
I just needed a little more time.
- I know.
And while you don't seek knowledge,
just this once, I shall give it freely.
I will not allow you to use
me without a question again.
Even if this was clever.
There's a light that shines
And it's power is mine
Though our body's weak and breakable
The spirit is indomitable
- Whew!
- No!
- I'll take it from here!
After all, I was sworn
to protect the people!
- Thank you.
And I'm sorry.
- The Atlas military
can handle the stragglers.
- What, what are you saying?
- I'm saying I don't
think anyone would notice
if one more ship went
missing in my lengthy report.
- [Maria] We should have
just enough fuel to make it.
- Thanks, Miss Calavera.
- Hey, Ruby?
You did great out there today, kid.
Just don't go giving me heart
attacks like that again.
- I love you, too.
- [Maria] You weren't half
bad yourself today, Qrow.
- I feel like they did
all the heavy lifting.
- But you were there to
help when they asked for it.
And you were there to
catch them when they fell.
Literally, if I recall.
- Thanks.
You know, it was pretty incredible getting
to see the Grimm Reaper in action.
- Huh, you should have seen
me when I was your age!
- I'm sorry you went
through that nightmare.
But, I'm glad Yang was
there for you in time.
- We were there for each other.
- Took the words right out of my mouth.
- Hey, stop it!
- You petrified a Leviathan
after diving down the barrel of a cannon!
- Don't act like you all
haven't done crazy stuff before!
I mean, Oscar made a
successful crash landing!
He's a 14 year old farm hand!
- That was seriously impressive.
- We'd have been stranded without you.
- I,
thanks but, I've been
meaning to tell you guys.
I didn't land the ship on my own.
We're gonna crash, we're gonna crash!
- [Ozpin] Stay calm,
it's going to be okay.
- [Nora] Ozpin took control?
- No, he guided me.
And then he was gone again.
- Does that mean he's been
watching us this whole time?
- I don't know, but,
it at least means he
was looking out for us.
- If you've never seen Atlas in person before
you don't wanna miss this.
- Is it weird that I'm sorta nervous?
- No, I'll believe we've made
it to Atlas when I see it.
- Well, believe it.
- Wow!
- You know, you make the trip
up to Atlas over and over,
but you never get used to that view.
Oh, come on!
- Weiss, what is it?
- [Weiss] The Atlas air fleet.
I knew all of our ships
were called back, but...
- They're set up like
they're expecting an attack.
- [Air Controller] Manta 5-1, welcome home.
Nevermore
Will I be afraid
Nor will I run away
It's behind me
Freedom is finally here
You may have taken the lead
But I'll even the score
You won the battle
You won't win the war
Not now and nevermore
You talked of subjugation
I answered your violent plea
Youth and infatuation
Kept me too blind to see
You think you're someone's hero
You're hiding more than your eyes
I challenge your weak manifesto
The goal of a savior is not to be lionized
Back when it started
I thought that justice was your goal
Then in the darkness
You lost your mind
I lost my soul
That's in the past and I won't be controlled
Nevermore
You'll torture my heart and my head
Will I be afraid
Nor will I run away
It's behind me
Freedom is finally here
You may have taken the lead
But I'll even the score
You won the battle
You won't win the war
Not now and nevermore
You had me down, defeated
A state that I can't allow
It's over, my fear's retreated
I'm more like an army now
You offered hope, salvation
Gave me a place to be
But your vision of liberation
Was all about you
It would never apply to me
I won't stay a martyr
It's my turn to take back what you stole
And this time I'm smarter
I made a vow
I'm not alone
Not dying now we're protecting our own
Nevermore
You'll torture my heart and my head
Will I be afraid
Nor will I run away
It's behind me
Freedom is finally here
You may have taken the lead
But I'll even the score
You won the battle
You won't win the war
Not now and nevermore
There's no cause to celebrate
Another soul consumed by hate and spite
Another destroyed life
There's no pleasure, there's no joy
It's just a story of a boy who lost his way
Into shadows strayed
He'll see the light of day
Nevermore
You'll torture my heart and my head
Will I be afraid
Nor will I run away
It's behind me
Freedom is finally here
You may have taken the lead
But I'll even the score
You won the battle
You won't win the war
Not now and nevermore
- Mercury, I wanted to...
What is she doing?
- [Hazel] There's an old saying.
If you want something done right,
Do it yourself.