(wind howling)
(train horn blares in the distance)
(dramatic music)
(train rumbling)
(loud whooshing)
(gun fires)
(Grimm crashing)
- Ya!
Got him, now who's next?
Whoa!
- Thank me later!
Ya!
Ha!
- Incoming!
Ya!
- Good to see you're not rusty.
- [Ruby] Ya!
- Why is it always something?
Just keep it towards the back.
(guns fire)
Ren!
Ah!
(weapon clashes)
- Tunnel!
- Huh?
- Go!
(rock music)
- Ahh!
- Thank me later!
- [Woman] I can't believe
he turned his back on us.
He just--
- [Adam] Step away from my
throne, we have work to do.
- [Man] We?
Everyone knows what you did.
You abandoned your brothers at Haven.
- [Adam] Step away from my--
- [Man] We're not taking
orders from you anymore.
We heard you folded
the moment you got sass
from the Belladonna girl.
I guess she's got more
control over you than you--
(sword shings)
- What, no.
(swords slashing)
(people grunting and yelling)
- [Man] No!
(swords slashing)
(people grunting and yelling)
(body thuds)
- The Belladonna girl.
Blake.
(sword slashing)
(metal clatter)
(Adam screams)
(tense music)
(light music)
- It's been two weeks
since the attack on Haven.
The official report states
that the plot to destroy
Mistral's CCT Tower was
thwarted by Ghira Belladonna
and the Faunus militia
group from Menagerie.
A Huntsman and some students
coincidentally visiting the headmaster
were also able to lend some assistance.
Unfortunately, Leonardo
Lionheart lost his life
while trying to defend his school.
And those responsible
for organizing the attack
managed to escape.
As I'm sure you can guess,
there's a lot more to this report
than I'm willing to say in this letter.
But for now, what I'm trying to say
is that we're on our way to Atlas, James.
There's a good chance we'll get there
before this letter does,
but in case we don't,
I need you to know that we're bringing
a lot more than bad news with us.
See you soon, Qrow.
Hey, what's with the running?
- What's with the standing?
It's almost time!
(bright music)
- Huh?
(Ruby laughs)
- And?
- Ahh!
- What an absolute waste of time--
- What did you get me?
- You'll have to wait and see.
- [Yang] No fair.
- Oh, I can't believe we're
taking the train to Argus!
The beautiful northern coastline...
You think it's too early for beach season?
(seagulls cawing)
(ball pops)
- Unfortunately, but we will
be one step closer to Atlas.
- Well, I'm glad you're all excited.
But I don't think you
appreciate the trouble
I went through to leave Atlas.
- I know you're worried,
Weiss, but trust us.
Team RWBY won't leave your
side for a second! I promise.
- No one's gotta be
worried with us around.
(theatrical music)
- And you are?
- Why Dee and Dudley of course.
The Argus Limited's very own Huntsmen.
We'll be keeping everyone safe
as we pass through Grimm territory.
- But for a generous tip, we can make sure
your passenger car gets
extra special attention
should things get dangerous.
- Yeah, I got a tip for you.
- Huh?
- Buzz off.
Looks like Mistral's really scraping
the bottom of the barrel these days.
- Hey, you're talking to a--
- A professional Huntsman, right.
Well, it seems like one of you heroes
left the staff entrance
to the caboose wide open.
It'd be a shame to lose your
job before it even started.
- I didn't do it.
- Come on, dummy.
Well, I didn't do it either.
- [Ozpin] I do hope those
weren't Beacon graduates.
- You know sometimes the burden
of saving the world feels overwhelming.
But then people like that come along
and make me grateful that
it's our job and not theirs.
- Uh-huh.
- Yeah.
- So, you kids ready to
go? Bike all loaded up?
- Yep!
- Just waiting on Blake.
As usual.
(gentle piano music)
- I still don't feel like
I deserve the freedom
you and your family granted me.
- Well, you're going to
have to get over it, Ilia.
Saving Haven had a huge impact
on how Faunus are seen in Mistral.
Now it's up to you all
to take the progress
and keep running with it.
- Right.
The White Fang may have been a failure,
but with your father
starting up a new movement,
I've got more faith than ever before.
Thank you, Blake, for everything.
I wish you didn't have to go.
- I know, but my team needs me.
We're going to track down
the people responsible
for the attack on Haven
and the fall of Beacon.
- Always trying to save the world.
- More than you realize.
- Hey, I know your parents
already saw you off,
but where's--
- Sun?
Oh, he's right here.
(playful music)
What? You didn't think I was gonna miss
your big send-off, did you?
- He definitely overslept and
absolutely almost missed this.
- Shh.
(Blake laughs)
- Hey, Blake.
Now would you hurry up?
Need I remind you we have
our own trip to plan?
Oh.
I didn't know Ilia was gonna be here.
I'll give you two a moment.
Hey, almost didn't see you there
'cause, you know, the camouflage?
- Wrong tree...
- He'll figure it out.
- So, you're really going to Vacuo?
- That's right, seeing
you reunited with the rest
of team RWBY really made
me realize something.
I'm like the worst team leader ever.
Me and the boys were cool
with a little hiatus,
but we gotta make up for lost time.
Shade Academy's not
dealing with any problems
like Haven right now.
Plus, that means I can show the guys
around my old stomping grounds.
- I have to admit. I think I was kind of
getting used to having you around.
- I go where I'm needed!
And... you don't need me anymore.
(emotional music)
- Well, when you say it
like that, it sounds sad.
- Look... despite the drama and the fighting
and the numerous attempts on
my life, I had a lot of fun.
But you're with who
you're supposed to be now.
- Sun...
I don't think I'll ever be
able to thank you enough.
I'm still--
- You're still working a
lot of things out, I know.
But you can do it with them.
And in the future, who knows?
I've got a feeling you
haven't seen the last of me.
- I certainly hope not.
(light music)
- I don't know, man.
It feels like you're just letting her go.
- It was never about that, braniac.
Besides, now that your leader's back
and hardened from battle,
I've gotta focus all of my time
into getting you boys
ready for the wastelands.
(Neptune groans)
(light music)
(passengers chatting)
(Ruby groans)
(video game chattering)
(peaceful music)
- [Ruby] All right
girls, I think it's time
for an official team exercise.
Who wants to play video games?
- [Yang] I mean if you want me
to kick your butt, yeah sure.
Let me grab my scroll.
- Here, let me help you with that.
- Blake, you don't have to do that.
- I don't know what you're talking about.
- I'm fine, we're gonna be fine.
It's just gonna be a bit before
things are back to normal.
But...
I am glad we're all back together.
- Yeah, okay.
- [Qrow] How touching.
- Oh hey, Uncle Qrow.
You wanna play too?
- (chuckles) Kick your butts?
Sure.
(loud rumbling)
(glass shatters)
- [Blake] What was that?
- Exactly what it sounds like.
- Just my luck.
- It's not yours... grab your weapons!
(tense music)
(passengers shouting)
(dramatic music)
(Grimm growling)
(Grimm roars)
(Dee yells)
(Dee groans)
- Dee!
(Dee screams)
(Grimm roars)
- What's the plan, Ruby?
- Don't let anyone else die.
(Grimm growling)
- [Ozpin] Shall I?
- No, I'm keeping control.
- What's going on?
(passengers scream)
(dramatic music)
(weapons slashing)
(Qrow grunting)
(weapon slashing)
(Dudley panting)
(fireball crashes)
(Dudley screams)
- [Dudley] Come on, come on.
(metal clanking)
(baby cries)
(turret whirls)
(turrets fire)
Ah, yes!
(Qrow grunting)
(weapon slashing)
(turrets fire)
(Grimm screeches)
(loud boom)
(passengers scream)
(guns fire)
- [Qrow] Hey! What are you doing?
- Why is it always something?
- How can I help?
- You can get that idiot
to shut off the turrets.
They're just drawing the
Grimm toward the passengers.
- Right.
(loud boom)
(Oscar panting)
(dramatic music)
Stop! You've gotta shut the turrets off!
- Are you crazy? No way!
(turrets fire)
Yes! Another one down!
- Stop! We have to lure
the Grimm to the back.
- What does it matter if they're dead?
(Grimm screeches)
(ominous music)
Where are they going?
- Tunnel!
- Huh?
(dramatic music)
(bone snaps)
(Dudley screams)
(Dudley groaning)
- I said, turn those damn things off.
- [Dudley] Those things
are keeping us alive.
- [Qrow] Us, sure, but they're putting
the passengers in danger.
- [Dudley] I'm the one they hired for this job, okay?
I'm in charge here!
- [Qrow] Forgive me if
I'm not exactly reassured.
(baby cries)
(passengers murmuring)
(Qrow and Dudley argue)
- [Qrow] Look, if you bozos
had been doing your job
instead of shaking down passengers,
maybe we wouldn't be in this--
(Dudley panting)
- Please just shut off the turrets.
- [Jaune] Trust us, we know what we're doing.
- Fine.
- Ren, could you use your Semblance
to mask everyone on this train?
With the guns off and emotions hidden,
they might lose track of us!
- I've never attempted to
affect this many people.
- Well, you've never
had Jaune's help before.
- He could amplify your aura.
- [Qrow] Yeah, that's an alright plan.
- [Ozpin] May I?
- [Nora] Don't look so worried, Ren.
You can totally do this.
- I'm afraid
there's one complication...
The Grimm are also attracted to this.
- What's that?
- None of your business.
Oz, are you serious?
- Why wouldn't you tell us that?
- I--
- It doesn't matter right now.
Every second we're on board this train,
we're putting everyone else in danger.
Get the passengers to the front cars.
You'll still mask the
emotions and kill the turrets...
we just can't come with you.
If we cut the back cars with
us and the relic on them,
we can deal with the Grimm.
You just make sure the rest of the train
makes it safely to Argus.
(emotional music)
- Only if you'll promise
you'll meet us there.
- Promise.
Time and time again it seems
We've reached the point where all our dreams
Are crumbling all around us
Every outcome unjust
Every step it seems has led
Us further from our goal instead
(Grimm screeching)
Our triumphs haven't mattered
We're drifting ever backward
And we're running out of time
- Now!
Nowhere near the finish line
And it's growing ever clear
That a reckoning is near
And we'll have to make a choice
Is this path right?
Or is it made of lies?
(Grimm growls)
(Oscar gasps)
We're looking in ourselves
(Oscar grunting)
(weapon slashing)
And trusting in the light
A miracle is all we needed
(weapons slashing)
But there isn't one in sight
(Yang grunting)
(weapon slashing)
(Grimm roars)
Each and every passing day
Our world's in further disarray
Confidence descending
Where's our happy ending?
On the path but still we strayed
(Grimm roars)
Our aspirations quickly fade
(Grimm crashing)
Desperation's risin'
(guns fire)
On hopeless bleak horizons
(Qrow grunting)
(weapon slashing)
Every life is on the line
(Grimm growls)
(fireball whooshing)
Can't wait here for a sign
And just like the blood that's shed
(Grimm roars)
(weapon fires)
Every cancer's sure to spread
- We need to ground it!
- On it!
And the time to act is short
Yang!
(Yang grunting)
We know inside
(guns fire)
We're born to do what's right
Desire to preserve life
(weapon spinning)
- Ahh!
(Yang grunting)
Is powering the light
(Grimm roars)
(Yang grunting)
We're praying for a miracle
(Blake grunting)
But for now we'll stand and fight
(Grimm screeches)
- Ya!
(Grimm roars)
(weapons slashing)
(fireball whooshing)
(Oscar gasps)
(Weiss gasps)
(fireball explodes)
(train crashes)
(thunderous noise)
(wind howling)
- Is everyone okay?
- I'm fine.
- Yeah.
- [Maria] Still alive!
(bright music)
That sure was a close one, huh?
Stay close, move fast
The darkness cannot last
No hope, no path
But we’ve got a dream to catch
And we can not wait
Trust the way we’re made
The sparrow’s born to fly
The mountains tower
The river knows to reach the sea
Rain will help the flowers be
We’re the same you and me
The lightning doesn’t take advice from anyone
The willow doesn’t need to learn to stand
As sun seeks day
We'll find our way
And we’ll catch that dream together
Someday soon
We’re rising like the moon
Time and time again it seems
We've reached the point where all our dreams
Are crumbling all around us
Every outcome unjust
Every step it seems has led
Us further from our goal instead
Our triumphs haven't mattered
We're drifting ever backward
And we're running out of time