Stay close, move fast
The darkness cannot last
No hope, no path
But we’ve got a dream to catch
And we can not wait
Trust the way we’re made
The sparrow’s born to fly
The mountains tower
The river knows to reach the sea
Rain will help the flowers be
We’re the same you and me
The lightning doesn’t take advice from anyone
The willow doesn’t need to learn to stand
As sun seeks day
We'll find our way
And we’ll catch that dream together someday soon
We’re rising like the moon
- [Jinn] Locked away
by her cruel father,
Salem was a girl who
desired but one thing:
freedom.
She lived in a time
when kings and their
kingdoms were plentiful,
when men and women were
capable of greatness,
and magic was a gift from the
gods that all could wield.
And yet, there she sat within her tower.
Until one day, a legendary hero
came to brave the challenges
within the tower's walls.
The people of the lands knew him...
as Ozma.
Unlike those who had come before,
this warrior was not driven
by the prize of the young maiden's hand.
He fought only for righteousness.
And his pure heart and
courageous soul prevailed.
They escaped the wretched fortress,
and yet, something bound them together.
Ozma had been ready to
give his life for justice
countless times but now saw
a woman worth saving it for.
And Salem, to her
surprise, found her freedom
not in the outside world
she had yearned for
but in the eyes of the
man that had saved her.
- So where should we go now?
- Wherever you'd like.
- [Jinn] The two fell deeply in love,
planned adventures around the world,
and lived happily ever after.
Or at least that's what should have been.
Ozma, the infallible
hero of legend, fell ill.
And where all of the beasts
and blades of the world
had fallen short, a
single sickness prevailed.
(Salem sobs)
- How could the gods let this happen?
- [Jinn] The gods,
brothers of light and darkness,
creation and destruction.
Salem prayed they would see the injustice
that had befallen her love
and make things right.
The Domain of Light was a sacred place.
It was here the elder brother dwelled
beside his fountain of life and creation.
It was here where mankind
would fall to ruin.
(dramatic music)
- Please.
Please bring him back to me.
- I understand your pain,
but you demand of me
that which I cannot make so.
Life and death are part
of a delicate balance.
- So you won't do it then?
- To disrupt the cycle of --
- But that's not fair.
That's not fair!
- Let him rest.
- No.
- [Jinn] The God of Darkness.
None dare to enter his home
as men knew what monstrosities emerged
from his blackened pools of annihilation.
And so you must understand
the Dark Lord's surprise
when he found a lone
woman kneeling before him.
(dramatic music)
Salem understood it well.
She told him of the loss and professed
that she knew only he
could answer her prayers,
all while careful to make
no mention of his elder.
- Rise, child.
And let your faith in me be rewarded.
(Ozma gasps)
- Where am I?
What is this?
Where am I?
- It's okay.
Everything's going to be okay.
(thunder rumbles)
- What have you done?
- I have done what I please, brother.
You may bask in the powers of creation,
but you do not own them.
- This is not creation.
- Do not lecture me!
- I will do what I must to maintain order.
(dramatic music)
- No!
No!
What did you do?
Bring him back!
- You dare enter my domain
and show such disrespect!
- Ozma!
- I am abiding by the
rules we agreed upon.
- Rules that I now see
are ever in your favor.
And yet, the day a mortal
comes to pray at my feet
before your own, so do you arrive
to lay your judgment upon me.
(explosion blasts)
- I know we have our differences,
but I have not come here
with the aim to control you.
The same, however, cannot be said for her.
This woman came to you only
after I denied her pleas,
pleas that would have
disrupted the balance
that you and I created.
Together.
- Then it seems I owe you an apology.
Allow me to correct my mistake.
- No!
You,
you monsters!
Give him back to me!
Give him back!
(God of Light roars)
- When you first came
to me, I did pity you.
But it is clear now
that your selfishness and
arrogance have led you astray.
- What did you do to me?
- [God of Light] I have made you immortal.
- Immortal?
- You cannot die.
You cannot be with your beloved.
- [Gods of Light And Darkness]
So long as this world turns,
you shall walk its face.
- [God of Light] You
must learn the importance
of life and death.
Only then may you rest.
- [Jinn] Salem was
a prisoner once again.
Her fruitless attempts
to reunite with Ozma
eventually became nothing more
than acts of spite and
defiance against the gods.
(Salem groans)
But perhaps the gods were not
as powerful as they seemed.
She had lied to them, turned
them against one another.
They were fallible.
If she were to turn humanity
against light and darkness,
she could rid herself of their
curse.
Or at the very least...
she could make them suffer.
Salem traveled from
one kingdom to another,
telling tales of how she stole
immortality from the gods,
welcomed any swordsman to cut her down,
and demonstrated her powers.
With the kings and queens in awe,
she pulled them deeper into her scheme.
She painted them pictures of a time
when they would no longer
have to watch their loved ones
wither and die, when they
could claim the powers
of their creators for themselves,
and in turn, perfect their own design.
(crowd cheers)
All they needed to do was
destroy their old masters.
The gods had hoped that Salem would learn
from her eternal curse, and she did.
She learned that the hearts
of men are easily swayed.
- [God of Light] Who has
led you down this path?
- You.
(suspenseful music)
My own gift to them...
used against me.
- No.
No.
(Salem grunts)
- You thought there was
no greater punishment
we could bestow upon you?
- I'll come back.
I'll tell the rest of the
world of this massacre,
build a new army.
- You do not understand.
There is no one left.
You are all that remains of humanity.
- This planet was a beautiful experiment,
but it is merely a remnant
of what it once was.
We will learn from this failure.
I hope that you will learn from yours.
- No, you can't leave.
You can't leave!
Come back!
- Still demanding things of your creators.
(explosion blasts)
- [Jinn] Once again, Salem was alone.
She cursed the gods.
She cursed the universe.
She cursed everything,
everything but herself.
She wandered the face of the planet,
awaiting a death that would never come...
Until fate led her back
to the land of darkness.
This was it.
This had to be it, the brothers
Grimm, the pools of black
that continued to give rise
to horrific nightmares.
If the fountain of life
granted her immortality,
then surely, the pools of Grimm
will finally take it away.
She was wrong.
This force of pure destruction
could not destroy a
being of infinite life.
Instead, it created a
being of infinite life
with a desire for pure destruction.
And in time, she would find her adversary.
(dramatic music)
- [God ff Light] Ozma.
- Where am I?
- We are between realms.
I'm afraid a tragedy
has befallen your home
at the hands of my brother.
We have chosen to depart this
world, but in our absence,
I would like to offer you
the chance to return to it.
- I don't understand.
- Mankind is no more,
yet your world remains.
And in time, your kind will grow
to walk its face once again.
However, without our presence,
they will be but a fraction
of what they once were.
Creation, destruction,
choice and knowledge
were the ideals upon
which humanity was made.
Now I leave them behind with the hope
that you will learn to remake yourselves.
If brought together, these four relics
will summon my brother
and I back to your world,
and humanity will be judged.
If your kind has learned to
live in harmony with one another
and set aside their differences,
then we shall once again
live among you, and humanity
will be made whole again.
But if your kind is unchanged,
if you demand our blessings
while still fighting amongst yourselves,
then man will be found irredeemable
and your world will be
wiped from existence.
Until your task is complete,
you will reincarnate,
but in a manner that
ensures you are never alone.
- I'm sorry, but that world
just isn't as dear to me without her.
If I may, I'd rather return
to the afterlife to see Salem.
- [God of Light] You
will not find her there.
- You mean she isn't gone?
- Salem lives, but the woman you hold dear
in your memories is gone.
Heed this warning...
where you seek comfort,
you will only find pain.
So, will you--
- I'll do it.
- Very well.
Our creation rests within your hands.
- [Jinn] And so Ozma was reborn.
(crowd screams)
- Where am I?
(man screams)
- Help!
Thank you.
Please, tell me your name.
Who are you?
- He didn't know.
- [Jinn] Ozma had found himself
in a world completely unfamiliar to him.
Cities looked different.
Creatures known as the
Faunus wore fangs and claws
and were locked away in cages.
And without the blessing of the gods...
no one could perform magic like
mankind was once capable of,
no one but himself and a
woman known as...
the witch.
During his years of travel,
he heard the same frightened whispers
that spoke of a terrifying
sorceress who commanded
dark powers in the wilds
among the beasts and monsters.
Ozma was convinced that
this witch was Salem...
and decided he needed to
see what she had become.
Call it magic or call
it something stronger,
but in that moment, the two knew exactly
who it was that stood before them.
- What do we do now?
- Whatever we like.
- [Jinn] As Salem and
Ozma recounted the events
which had brought them back together,
each withheld parts of their story.
Salem, fearing Ozma would reject her,
blamed the end of the world on the gods.
Ozma, still unsure of where the truth lay,
kept his task and the relics a secret.
Though time passed and all
seemed well, Ozma's conversation
with the God of Light
still lingered in his mind.
He had found happiness,
but humanity seemed more
divided than ever before.
- Are you surprised?
This world is quite literally godless.
These humans have no one to guide them.
Perhaps that's all they need.
- What are you saying?
- We could become the gods of this world.
Our powers surpass all others.
Our souls transcend death.
We can mold these lands
into whatever we want,
what you want, create the paradise
that the old gods could not.
The hearts of men...
are easily swayed.
(crowd screams)
(Nevermore growls)
- [Jinn] The two amassed a following.
That following grew into
a prosperous kingdom.
And at the head of that kingdom blossomed...
a family.
(dramatic music)
- [Ozma] Are we sure this is right?
- You said we needed to
bring humanity together.
In order to do that, we
have to spread our word
and destroy those who will deny it.
- What are we doing?
This isn't what he asked of me.
- [Salem] What did you say?
- Mother, father, look!
- [Jinn] It was a miracle.
Their children could perform magic.
But what should have been a
joyous occasion was short lived.
Ozma told Salem
everything, the true reason
the God of Light had brought him back,
the relics that lay
scattered around the world,
and the day of judgment he
had been told to prepare for.
- Don't you see?
None of that matters anymore.
Why spend our lives trying
to redeem these humans
when we can replace them with
what they could never be?
- Mommy?
(dramatic music)
(Grimm growl)
- We finally had freedom.
- I...
- [Jinn] Thus began
a long and painful cycle
of death and rebirth for Ozma.
Some lives were spent in mourning.
Many were spent attempting
to forget it all.
But no matter what, his mind
would eventually turn back
to the task he had been burdened with.
And as the centuries went on,
Ozma began to learn the
importance of living
with the souls with
which he had been paired.
But no matter where or how he lived,
her presence was always felt.
If humanity were ever to stand
a chance of being united,
one thing was clear.
- He had to destroy Salem.
- [Jinn] Knowing he could
never rid the world of her
through any mortal means,
Ozma sought out the power of the relics.
Armed with my knowledge, he
believed he could fulfill
his promise to the God of Light.
- Where are the other relics?
- [Jinn] He asked me his questions.
- What powers do they possess?
- [Jinn] And though
I gave him my answers--
- How do I destroy Salem?
- [Jinn] Not all of them were to his liking.
You can't.
(wind howls)