Stay close, move fast
The darkness cannot last
No hope, no path
But we’ve got a dream to catch
And we can not wait
Trust the way we’re made
The sparrow’s born to fly
The mountains tower
The river knows to reach the sea
Rain will help the flowers be
We’re the same you and me
The lightning doesn’t take advice from anyone
The willow doesn’t need to learn to stand
As sun seeks day
We'll find our way
And we’ll catch that dream together someday soon
We’re rising like the moon
- Storm's cleared up for now.
We should be able to leave by morning.
- That's good.
- No.
I don't have a good
feeling about this place.
Especially with me around.
- Are you okay?
- (scoffs) Sure.
Tell everyone to get some sleep.
I'll wake you guys up just before sunrise.
(liquid swishes)
(gulping)
(Qrow sighs)
(fire crackling)
- [Oscar] It's a diary?
- The head of this household, Bartleby.
Apparently he and several other families
founded this little settlement
to try and live on their own.
It sounds like it worked,
at least for a spell.
- Grimm?
- Just one of many hardships.
Slowed down their farming,
made everything harder.
It's a shame, really.
He seemed like quite the ambitious fellow.
Always thinking of new
schemes to overcome the odds.
- Hey, guys.
Qrow said we should get some sleep.
We're gonna head out early tomorrow.
- Thank goodness.
- The last thing you'll catch me doing
is letting some kid tell me what to do.
"Go to bed!" (scoffs)
(bottle clatters)
(screams)
- Close the window!
- Uncle Qrow?
Come on, get up.
- (groans) Leave me alone.
- [Ruby] We overslept.
(groans)
(bottle shatters)
- (groans) What?
Oh, right.
Sunrise.
- You know, you can
talk to me about stuff.
Yang, too.
- Let's just get out of here.
- [Weiss] There.
- Can we just go back to bed?
- If we're all so tired, maybe
we should make breakfast?
- You wanna make it?
- Not really.
(trailer clatters)
- You guys got the bike ready?
- Well, it's done now.
So let's hook this thing up.
(tires hissing)
(groans)
- You people are just beacons
for bad luck, aren't you?
- I'm starting to think the universe
just doesn't want us getting to Atlas.
- It's just a flat tire,
I'm sure there's a spare.
- It's not just that, it's everything.
Storms, crashes, monsters...
I'm so tired.
- Me too.
It feels like we're always
having to fight to get by.
- Yeah.
But that's what we signed up for.
- We signed up to try and save the world,
not just delay the inevitable.
- Last night I,
I couldn't stop thinking.
Why are we even going to Atlas?
- Weiss, we have to.
- Why?
Ozpin hid the relics behind giant doors
under enormous schools.
But how long would it
take Salem to find a lamp
in the middle of nowhere?
- What?
The Grimm might--
- They'd find it eventually,
sure, but bury it or just
throw it down the well...
it would take years.
It might not even happen in our lifetime.
But we could be done with it now.
(snow crunches)
- I am really tired.
(sighs)
(dramatic instrumental music)
(Ruby screams)
No, no, no, I didn't mean to!
- Ruby, it's okay.
- No!
No, there's something down there.
I saw it, it was looking at me.
- Hey, it's okay.
You just said you're tired.
It's probably nothing.
Now let's go.
- What's wrong with you?
We can't just leave, we
have to go down there.
We have to get the lamp back!
What was I thinking?
- [Qrow] All we have to
do is fix this trailer.
Hey, farm boy, check the shed for a spare.
- I'm not leaving without the lamp!
- (sighs) I'll go down with you.
- We'll go down together.
- Fine!
Get the stupid lamp.
Oscar, fix the stupid tire.
- Where are you going?
- Where do you think?
- Stupid.
(water splashing)
- Maybe the current carried it away.
- Oh, come on, where is it?
- Turn off your lights and
just look for the glow.
- Okay.
(dramatic instrumental music)
- There.
(water splashing)
- Guys, I.
(dramatic instrumental music)
(screaming)
- Ruby?!
What is it?
(dramatic instrumental music)
(weapon firing)
(Grimm groan)
What is this?
- My weapon feels heavy.
- Run!
Now!
(dramatic instrumental music)
- Go, go!
- This way!
(dramatic instrumental music)
- Can't do this.
Can't.
(groaning)
- An exit.
An exit!
- Come on!
Blake,
get up.
It's fine.
Blake!
(Grimm hissing)
- I've got her.
What just happened?
(doors clatter)
- They're locked!
- Out of my way!
(groaning)
No, no!
(dramatic instrumental music)
- [Maria] Ruby,
what color are your eyes?
- They're silver.
- You have a family, friends?
- What?
- Don't think about them.
Think about the people who love you.
Focus on the thought of them,
the way they make you feel.
Focus!
Life is beautiful.
It is precious.
And it must
be protected.
(Grimm shrieks)
(dramatic instrumental music)
- We're back in the house?
- Uncle Qrow, get up!
- Hey, get off me!
What are you doing here?
- We're leaving, you idiot!
Come on.
- Not yet.
- Oscar!
Oscar!
We have to go, now!
(bottles shattering)
- Hey!
Hey, what are you doing?
(flames crackling)
- Now we can leave.
- Stop it, stop!
What's wrong with you?
What's...
(dramatic instrumental music)
(engines revving)
(flames crackling)
- The Apathy.
They're not strong or ferocious.
They drain your will to go on.
Bartleby's estate was hemorrhaging
money towards the end.
He wanted to cut costs
on Huntsman protection.
But in order to do that
he needed everyone calm...
always.
- Managed to get two away from their pack.
Hike back was miserable, but
got the bastards in the cellar.
Wife thinks I was out sealing
the waterway entrance.
I'll do it tomorrow and tell her the truth
once these things take
the edge off of everyone.
I'm tired.
- The next page proves that he did,
but not before the rest of the pack
followed their missing
pair all the way home.
My guess is they made their
way beneath the estate
through the water tunnels.
That Bartleby sealed up the next morning.
Bartleby's plan worked.
No one was angry or sad or scared.
No one was anything.
And then no one was left.
- I'm sorry for what I said.
about giving up.
- Me too.
We can't quit until the lamp is safe.
- It's not your fault.
It was those things.
- I should have known.
The signs were all there.
But I'd never seen an entire settlement
withered away like that.
I suppose my mind just
isn't what it used to be.
- Miss Calavera?
How do you know so much about the Grimm?
And in the tunnels you
knew exactly what to say
to make me... to make my eyes do that.
How?
- Well, isn't it obvious, girl?
I had silver eyes.