(dramatic music)
We did not seek this conflict.
But we will rise to meet it.
The Vanguard will do everything
we can to protect those
who have put their trust in us.
Be strong, and we
will get through this.
For the people.
Stay close, move fast
The darkness cannot last
No hope, no path
But we’ve got a dream to catch
And we can not wait
Trust the way we’re made
The sparrow’s born to fly
The mountains tower
The river knows to reach the sea
Rain will help the flowers be
We’re the same you and me
The lightning doesn’t take advice from anyone
The willow doesn’t need to learn to stand
As sun seeks day
We'll find our way
And we’ll catch that dream together someday soon
We’re rising like the moon
- Now you understand.
I've got to get the relic before
it can be secured in Atlas.
It's the only way that Salem...
(sighs) It's the only way
we can accomplish our goal.
You're not the only one
who wants Ruby dead.
But unfortunately, Salem
does not feel the same way.
I've been instructed not to kill her,
but you,
you have no such orders.
You can do as you please.
Help me get to Atlas.
Help me find her.
And the rest is up to you.
- Well, that's a fancy trick now, innit?
'Fraid it comes with
a price, though, love.
- I don't think you realize who I am.
- Course I do.
You're the Grimm Reaper.
And these are the last
60 seconds of your life.
(blades clanging)
- (sighs) It was a close call.
I'll give you that.
You know, the only reason
my master wants you dead is
'cause of your eyes (laughs).
But seein' as you ain't got 'em no more,
you might be able to convince
me to spare your life.
(chuckles) Well, I respect that.
A fighter to the end.
- [Maria] But I wasn't.
I went into hiding soon after.
- I can't believe it.
You, you're the Grimm Reaper.
You were a legend.
And then you disappeared.
- How exactly does a
legend just disappear?
- You never used your name,
never showed your face.
Lots of us thought you
were just layin' low.
Eventually, we came to accept
that you were probably dead.
But the stories about you,
I based my weapon off of yours.
- Well, I'm nothing but a disappointment.
So you're well on your way.
- How can you say that?
- Child, a Huntress is supposed
to protect others to the bitter end.
But after I lost my eyes,
I only ever looked after myself.
Even after my surgery, I
was too afraid to fight,
afraid someone would find me again,
finish what the others started.
You shouldn't aspire to be like me,
especially when some of you
are clearly stronger already.
It's comforting seeing that
your generation seems up
to the task of inheriting this world.
I'm just sorry I didn't do more
to leave it in better shape.
- Well, maybe you can do something now.
Teach me to use my powers the way you did.
(gasps) It's Jaune.
- How?
- Hello.
- [Jaune] Ruby (laughs), thank you!
I've been checking my
Scroll for your signal
since we made it to the city.
- The city?
Wait.
- Ladies and gentlemen,
we have arrived in Argus.
- Cute boy Oz!
(Oscar yells)
[Nora] Oh, come here!
- [Ren] Are you all okay?
We were so worried.
- [Nora] The most fun
for me there ever was.
- [Yang] It's been kind
of a crazy trip.
- [Weiss] That's an understatement.
- [Nora] Wait, who's the old lady?
- Hey.
I promised, didn't I?
- Yeah, you did.
It's good to see you guys.
- [Yang] It's a lot bigger
than I thought it'd be.
- [Ren] It's actually one of
the largest non-capital cities
in all of Remnant.
- (gasps) No way.
But wait, wouldn't it be hard
to settle something this big
away from the main kingdom?
- [Jaune] Well, it was, until
Mantle showed up.
Early settlement attempts
by Mistral didn't go well.
But colonists from Mantle were able
to help them brave the cold climate
and return for goods that
Solitas couldn't provide.
- [Ren] The two nations worked together
to create a hybrid city.
While it still falls under Mistral domain,
Atlas keeps a military presence here
to help keep the people
safe and to keep trade
between the two nations steady.
- Well, until recently.
- We should probably
start looking for a ship.
- So where have you guys been staying?
- Uh (chuckles)...
- There you are.
- [Yang] Is that--
- Hey, Saph.
-[Ruby] I can't believe I'm meeting your sister.
I have so many questions.
- [Nora] Oh, I can give
you the rundown later.
- [Jaune] Will you guys knock it off?
- What?
I love telling stories
about my baby brother.
- I am not a baby!
That is a baby.
- Aww, coochie-coochie!
- Aww, you're so cute!
Yes, you are.
- Aw, baby!
- Oh look at your little face.
- Oh my.
- So Saphron, you're the
only Arc living here?
(Jaune groaning)
- Yup,
moved the second I could.
Jaune and I are the only
two living away from home.
I guess he just wanted
to be like his big sis.
- I, uh -- (groans).
- Aw!
You didn't deny it.
Everyone, this is my wife Terra Cotta.
- Hello!
- Pleased to meet you.
- (chuckles) Why, hello there.
Wow, quite a party, you weren't kidding.
Hun, can I get some help please?
- [Blake] And you're sure it's all right
if we stay with you?
- [Saphron] Of course, we're happy to
house Huntsman and Huntresses.
You all risk so much to
keep people like us safe.
It's the least we can do,
especially for such an elite
Huntsman like yourself.
Although, I will say I was surprised
to learn you had students helping you.
Is that even legal?
- Uh, of course.
Think of it as an
extended training mission.
Trust me, I was a professor.
Even went to the same academy as them.
Let me tell ya, these kids are way better
than we were at their age.
Well, not better than me specifically,
but a lot of students.
- Shut up, there's food!
- (sighs) Excuse me, I'll be right back.
- Is everything okay?
- Oh, yeah, it will be.
Terra's a technician for
the town's relay tower.
Unfortunately, the military's radar system
is also housed there.
Guess what's been on the fritz lately
and who's getting falsely blamed.
- Me.
- So what's your plan for tomorrow?
- Well (sighs), we're trying
to make our way to Atlas.
We'll probably start
with the military base.
- So we kind of already tried that,
and it didn't go super great.
- Come on, it couldn't be that bad.