Stay close, move fast
The darkness cannot last
No hope, no path
But we’ve got a dream to catch
And we can not wait
Trust the way we’re made
The sparrow’s born to fly
The mountains tower
The river knows to reach the sea
Rain will help the flowers be
We’re the same you and me
The lightning doesn’t take advice from anyone
The willow doesn’t need to learn to stand
As sun seeks day
We'll find our way
And we’ll catch that dream together someday soon
We’re rising like the moon
- [Cinder] Do you have my information?
- Of course I do, darling.
Lil' Miss always delivers.
Although, I can't promise
you'll be pleased.
Word is they were seen boarding
the Argus Limited a few weeks back.
While that isn't exactly far from here,
Argus is rarely a destination for folks.
Chances are they'll be going straight to--
- Atlas.
- You know, you turned out to be
quite the interesting customer.
Cinder.
It's not often a single client
brings me double the business.
- [Cinder] Wait.
(intense music)
Neo?
- Maybe put away the good glasses.
Kill for kill
Eye for eye
- What are you doing?
Blood for blood it's time to die
Retribution tastes so sweet
(blows thudding)
Gone's the life
That he gave
Now revenge is all I crave
Retaliation's soon complete
I had one thing
And you've taken it from me
A single light
(table thuds)
A single friend
But you made that end
There was one thing
To help escape the misery
And now it's all disarrayed
You took my whole life away
(chair creaks)
You sent me back to nothing
Now you'll pay
Pay
- That's enough, ladies!
I love dinner and a show,
but it's time to take it outside.
(dramatic music)
(glass shattering)
- Hm.
Nice trick.
You've gotten stronger.
So have I.
I don't have time for your
misplaced blame, girl.
I didn't kill your boss.
If you want revenge, take
it up with "little red".
- You're not the only one
with a grudge against Ruby.
(blow thuds)
Listen!
We both want that girl dead.
(rumbling)
So quit wasting your time fighting me...
and let's discuss how
we kill her together.
Okay, then...
Let's talk.
Well?
(wind howling)
- [Ruby] I don't get it.
The empty towns I've passed
through were all damaged,
or unfinished.
But this place looks... fine.
- Maybe everyone left in a hurry.
Before things took a turn?
(loud clanging)
- (grunts) Stay on guard.
(loud banging)
(intense music)
- Close the door already!
It's cold enough in here as it is.
(low scraping)
- I saw a chimney from the outside.
Maybe we could get a fire going?
- Please.
I'll look for some blankets.
- [Qrow] Yang, go with her.
(suspenseful music)
(wind howling)
- [Oscar] Looks like a study.
Or, a library?
(footsteps thudding softly)
- What do you think?
- Something doesn't feel right.
- Let's look for some--
(terrified screaming)
- Weiss!
(Weiss breathing heavily)
(fire crackling)
(sudden banging)
(door opening)
(footsteps thudding)
- It's the same in every house.
- What?
- [Qrow] Bodies.
Every bed in every home.
It's like the whole
estate just went to sleep
and never woke up.
- Then we're not staying here, right?
- We don't have a choice.
Storm outside's only getting worse.
We'd freeze to death
before we made it anywhere.
- Well.
Might as well get comfortable.
- Yeah, fat chance.
- Okay, then.
Let's do something.
If this place wasn't abandoned
it might still have supplies we could use.
- Hey, yeah.
Maybe even a car.
- I'll do another sweep of the grounds.
(footsteps thudding)
No one else goes anywhere alone.
- Yang and I can search the
other buildings for vehicles.
- Fine.
Whatever gets me out of this house.
(loud scraping)
- Food always makes me feel
better. (chuckles nervously)
Just saying.
- Right.
- I'll tell you what.
You keep that fire fed...
and I'll find us a story
to read before bed.
(Oscar sighs)
(wind howling)
(loud scraping)
- Something tells me
that's not street legal.
- What do you think happened here?
- There's that well in the square.
Maybe water contamination?
- Yeah, maybe.
- Hey, are you okay?
- Yeah.
I mean, no.
But, I don't know.
I'm just tired.
- Yeah.
- Hey, I found something.
(intense music)
(Yang gasps)
(footsteps rattling)
- What is it?
- I...
(sighs)
I was just seeing things.
I'm sorry.
I still get flashes from that night.
Do you think Adam's still out there?
- I don't know.
If he went back to the White Fang
there would have been
serious consequences.
But, he never really liked
people telling him what to do.
Adam's strong, but his real
power comes from control.
He used to get in my
head, make me feel small.
But now I see he just wanted
to pull me down to his size.
Hey.
I'm not leaving.
And if we ever see him again,
I promise I'll be there.
And I'll protect you.
- What?
- [Yang] Forget it.
Let's just head back.
- [Blake] But what about--
- [Yang] We're fine.
We can hook that flatbed up
to Bumblebee in the morning.
Should carry everyone.
- Mission accomplished.
(soft, suspenseful music)
- There.
- On second thought, maybe we
should keep this room closed.
- Huh?
- I'm just...
Not sure how well my
uncle's taking all of this.
- Oh.
- Come on.
We'll never get to Atlas
on an empty stomach!
- Ruby?
Are we really still going to Atlas?
- Why wouldn't we be?
- I mean...
You heard what Jinn said.
If there's no way to kill Salem,
then what's the point in all of this?
- Weiss,
you can't be serious.
- (sighs) Sorry, I don't
know what I'm saying,
I'm just really tired and I
really, really hate this place.
Anything in there?
- More alcohol.
At least we'll never have
problems starting a fire.
- What's that?
A wine cellar?
Great.
(Ruby screams)
What?
What is it?
- Food!
- Canned food?
- Oh trust me, you put
enough salt on anything,
and it will taste just fine.
- Well, I guess it's better than nothing.
But I still seriously hate this place.
(low banging)
Kill for kill
Eye for eye
Blood for blood it's time to die
Retribution tastes so sweet
Gone's the life
That he gave
Now revenge is all I crave
Retaliation's soon complete
I had one thing
And you've taken it from me
A single light
A single friend