Stay close, move fast
The darkness cannot last
No hope, no path
But we’ve got a dream to catch
And we can not wait
Trust the way we’re made
The sparrow’s born to fly
The mountains tower
The river knows to reach the sea
Rain will help the flowers be
We’re the same you and me
The lightning doesn’t take advice from anyone
The willow doesn’t need to learn to stand
As sun seeks day
We'll find our way
And we’ll catch that dream together someday soon
We’re rising like the moon
- [Cordovin] You just couldn't keep
this rivalry between
us could you, Calavera?
You had to rope in
children to fail with you.
- Ruby!
- [Oscar] Ruby, can you hear me?
Are you guys okay?
- Are we okay?
- [Oscar] I know, we were
supposed to lay low, but listen.
I think I finally found a weakness.
- [Nora] Well, we're all ears.
- Guys!
- [Oscar] The cylinder on Cordo's cannon
rotates and locks in
a giant dust cartridge
every time she changes attack styles.
- [Weiss] We noticed.
- Right, but her missile launcher
doesn't lock in, it pops out!
Without her shields, one well-placed shot
could detonate the missiles while
they're still in the launcher!
- We could destroy the entire canon.
Oscar, that's brilliant!
- Can you make that kind of shot?
- We'll only get one chance
before she catches on.
I'd have to be practically staring
down the barrel of her cannon.
- [Maria] Well, I've got
a way to guarantee that.
- Ruby, what are you doing?
- [Maria] Hey, Cordo!
I've got one missile left and I know
exactly where I'm gonna stick it!
- One missile you say?
That's a shame Maria,
because I have plenty!
- Are you two crazy?
- Sometimes the best approach
is simply the most direct.
- You!
- [Cordovin] You thought you could fool me?
- Pull up!
- I can't see! My eyes!
- No, no, no!
- Take control.
- We're gonna crash. We're gonna crash!
- We're, we're still in one piece.
- [Cordovin] Very clever,
but even the smartest apes
can't compete with the intellect of man.
- Come on, come on!
- Ruby, stop.
- I need you to trust me.
- [Cordovin] Surrender for your crimes,
and accept your punishment.
- No!
We're going to Atlas.
Bigger people than you have
tried to stop us and failed,
but we're supposed to be on the same side.
We're supposed to use our
power to protect people,
but you just use yours
to look down on everyone.
We didn't want to steal from you.
We did it because you
gave us no other choice.
Now I'm giving you one
last chance to stand down
and hear us out.
- I've heard enough.
- What?
- She's nuts!
- The missile launcher springs out,
but the raw dust gets locked in.
- [Cordovin] What? No. No!
- Ruby? Ruby!
- Told ya.
- Oh don't tell me I missed it.
- You knew you couldn't
win two-on-one at Haven.
What makes you so sure you can win now?
- I don't have a choice.
I have people who actually care about me,
and I promised I'd never leave them again.
So I'm not dying now.
- You know she made a promise to me once.
That she'd always be at my side.
Huh, and look how well she's kept it.
- Did she make that promise to you,
or to the person you
were pretending to be.
- So I just wasn't good enough for you?
- You know it's so much more than that.
- I know you've made you
choice, and I've made mine.
- Blake!
- Moment of truth, Yang.
Do you think you're faster
than you were at Beacon?
Me neither.
Your aura's bound to be running low.
Hit me already!
What does she even see in you?
You're just a coward like her!
- Gotcha.
I may not be faster,
but I'm smarter.
- No!
- Oh.
- I am not going to break
my promise, I swear.
- I know you won't.
- [Cordovin] No! No, no , no, no!
You! You're never getting
to Atlas, do you hear me!
Never! All forces converge on my position
and eliminate these pests at once.
- Crap!
- Everyone on board!
We're making a run for it.
- What about Yang and Blake?
- [Atlas Soldier] Ma'am we've been
trying to reach you.
Argus is in danger.
- What?
- [Atlas Soldier] It's a Leviathan,
it began its approach during your battle.
We need you!