- [Narrator] This is how the war begins.
- [Female Pilot] All wings engage
interceptors three and four,
take bogeys two o'clock angel six.
- [Male Pilot] Ma'am, do you see that?
- I see it.
- Contact.
Hostile nanotech.
- Shit.
- [Man On Radio] Seal your
cockpits, do not engage.
- [Narrator] This is not a skirmish.
This is not air space confusion.
This is not a terrorist action.
This is it.
The Union's making their play.
Stay close, move fast
The darkness cannot last
No hope, no path
But we’ve got a dream to catch
And we can not wait
Trust the way we’re made
The sparrow’s born to fly
The mountains tower
The river knows to reach the sea
Rain will help the flowers be
We’re the same you and me
The lightning doesn’t take advice from anyone
The willow doesn’t need to learn to stand
As sun seeks day
We'll find our way
And we’ll catch that dream together someday soon
We’re rising like the moon
- [Weiss] You're joking, right?
You want to fight this thing?
- We've fought giant monsters before.
This is just a tiny old lady.
With one very big robot.
- You little spider-roaches
thought you could creep
your way to Atlas?
Well, let's see how your resolve holds out
against the might of the Atlesian Military.
So be it.
- Dive.
- That was close.
- We need to figure out how to stop
Cordovin and protect
the airship until we do.
- Let's give her more targets to focus on.
- You mean us, don't you?
- Look at that thing.
It's not designed for small enemies.
It's probably meant for giant Grimm
that come in from deeper waters.
We can turn our size into an advantage.
We just have to be smart.
- Maria, can you keep the ship
out of harm's way?
- They can take my driver's license,
but I won't let them take this ship.
- Very reassuring.
- I'll be more useful if I go with her.
From up high, I can
try to spot a weakness.
- Well, he's not the only one
who can grab a bird's eye view.
- You said you needed me on the ground?
- Not exactly.
Check you out
In your big metal shoe
Fighting so many kids
Don't know what to do
You got some heavy metal
But big ain't bad
This little riding hood's
- [Ruby] Let's go.
Just way too rad
Mirror mirror
Who will lose it all
Soundly whip those children
- [Jaune] Hey, over here.
Or your cradle's gonna fall
- [Cordovin] What?
Cuz I'm alive
Like a puppet with a heartbeat
- And you said it wasn't beach season.
I'm on fire
And i'm flying off the dope sheet
You're gonna wind
Up like that robin at your last tweet
You're heading for a fall
And you're nearing the end
Like a house made of straw
No one's putting you together again
- [Cordovin]
Surely you knew Atlas
was the father of hard-light Dust,
or do lesser kingdoms simply
lack proper education?
- Cordo just activated shields.
- [Oscar] I saw that.
We need to find whatever's generating it.
- [Ruby] You know, in video games,
the weak spot's usually on the back
of the giant boss.
- [Weiss] Ruby, this isn't a game.
- [Ruby] I'm just trying to-- look out!
- You are ants.
You are lower than ants.
Ah! What was that?
- Until the shield's down,
we're gonna have to get
up close and personal
with this thing.
-Ah!
- [Ren] That's easier said than done.
- [Ruby] Weiss and I are on it.
- Hold on.
- Wait, that's it.
When she...
Ruby move!
- Go!
- Get off of me!
- Ah!
- What if I hadn't caught you?
- I knew you would.
Uh.
- Got you.
What'd you find?
Well, alright then.
- No, no, no, no.
- You get back here with my man.
- Jump on.
- [Cordovin] I've
had enough of you ingrates.
- No!
- [Cordovin] This is what happens
when you think you know better
than those rightfully in charge.
- We gotta do something.
- Calavera.
- Can you do anything besides run?
I wouldn't have to be doing this
if you just behaved.
But you're selfish.
You're a coward.
- You're delusional.
- People hurt me long before we met.
All sorts of people in all sorts of ways,
but no one hurt me quite like you.
You didn't leave scars,
you just left me alone.
So, tell me, Blake.
How does it feel to be alone?
- I'm not alone.
- You.
- Yang.
- It's okay.
Catch your breath for a second.
I can hold him off.
- She's right, Blake.
It's okay, we have unfinished business.
- His semblance is like yours.
He absorbs energy through his sword,
stores it up and then sends
it back when he's ready.
- He gets to dish out damage
without having to feel it?
That's just cheap.
- Yang!
- [Yang] Leave us alone.
This is your last chance.
- Do you really believe that?
Or are you just trying to scare me away
so you won't have to die
trying to protect her?
- She's not protecting me, Adam.
And I'm not protecting her.
We're protecting each other.
Check you out
In your big metal shoe
Fighting so many kids
Don't know what to do
You got some heavy metal
But big ain't bad
This little riding hood's
Just way too rad
Mirror mirror
Who will lose it all
Soundly whip those children
Or your cradle's gonna fall
Cuz I'm alive
Like a puppet with a heartbeat
I'm on fire
And i'm flying off the dope sheet
You're gonna wind
Up like that robin at your last tweet
You're heading for a fall
And you're nearing the end
Like a house made of straw
No one's putting you together again