Stay close, move fast
The darkness cannot last
No hope, no path
But we’ve got a dream to catch
And we can not wait
Trust the way we’re made
The sparrow’s born to fly
The mountains tower
The river knows to reach the sea
Rain will help the flowers be
We’re the same you and me
The lightning doesn’t take advice from anyone
The willow doesn’t need to learn to stand
As sun seeks day
We'll find our way
And we’ll catch that dream together someday soon
We’re rising like the moon
- [Yang] Salem can't be killed...
- You all heard her too right?
- I--
- There was so much
you hadn't told us!
How could you think that was okay?
- [Ruby] Professor...
What is your plan to defeat Salem?
- I...
don't have one.
(loud smacking)
(wood breaking)
(soft crunching)
- No one wanted me.
I was cursed.
I gave my life to you because you gave me
a place in this world.
I thought I was finally doing some good.
- But, you are.
- Meeting you was the worst luck of my life.
- Maybe you're right.
- What happened?
- He's gone.
- That bastard!
Tell him we're not done yet!
- No.
This is different.
He's gone.
It's like he's locked himself deep inside my head.
Our head?
(grunts) I hate this!
I want it to stop!
- He just left us?
- What are we gonna do now?
(growls)
- Enough!
- We need to get a move on.
It'll be dark before we know it,
and every one of you is spewing negativity!
There's a trail over there.
Trails usually lead somewhere.
- Lady, I don't know who you think you are but--
- No buts!
I understand that you're upset.
Honestly I'm still coming to terms with the fact that
this is humanity's second time around.
But, if we don't move, we die.
And I'll be damned if I've lived this long
just to die out here in the cold!
- She's right.
Come on.
(wind whistling)
- I'm just going to be another one of his lives, aren't I?
Of course not.
You're your own person.
- Don't lie to him, Ruby.
We're better than that.
(wind whistling)
(engine roaring)
(engine idling)
(suspenseful music)
- (laughs) Welcome back, welcome back!
I do hope you missed us as much as we missed you.
- Let's go.
- Speaking of which,
where is our Fall Maiden?
(gasps and giggles)
- Emerald, come on.
- Don't tell me something happened to her? (laughs)
- I will cut off more than just your tail.
- (chuckles) Careful, little girl.
Cinder isn't here to protect you anymore.
- Back off, freak.
- Oh, don't misunderstand,
I am in mourning just as you.
Because it appears you've failed our queen,
and that is a tragedy.
(laughs maniacally)
- I would like you to explain to me
how it is you've failed so spectacularly.
- The Faunus militia split our forces--
- Stop.
Let me rephrase the question.
Who is responsible for your defeat?
- I take full responsibility.
(loud banging)
- But that wouldn't be fair now, would it?
We all know who's truly to blame.
- I don't--
(wet crackling)
(Hazel grunts)
(footsteps tapping)
- Emerald.
I want you to tell me whose fault this was.
(Emerald breathing heavily)
Now.
- Cinder!
We failed because of Cinder.
- That's right.
I want you to understand that failure.
I want you to understand why Cinder
must be left to toil in her isolation
until she redeems herself.
- You mean--
- [Emerald] She's alive?
- You're joking.
How could you know that?
- Are you questioning our divine savior?
- I...
(chuckles nervously)
Of course not, forgive me.
- It's important not to lose sight of what drives us.
Love.
Justice.
Reverence.
But the moment you put your desires before my own...
(Hazel grunts)
they will be lost to you.
(Hazel gasps)
This isn't a threat.
This is simply the truth.
The path to your desires is only found through me.
And so we must press on.
The sword under Vacuo's academy, Shade--
- Ma'am.
I have more to report.
(wet crackling)
Qrow and the children are taking the lamp to Atlas.
- (laughs) Not if I can help it.
- And they're being led,
by Ozpin.
- [Tyrian] So soon?
- He's the only man with a chance
of getting through to Ironwood.
If that happens...
(loud cracking)
- Leave.
- Your Grace, I can...
(suspenseful music)
- Come on.
(Salem screaming)
(glass breaking)
- (sighs) Doesn't look like this is gonna let up.
- Just wanna get this stupid relic to Atlas.
- Let's hope we don't have to walk all the way there.
- I thought trails led somewhere.
- Do you have nothing better to do
than to harass a defenseless old lady?
- Everyone, quiet.
Do you hear that?
(metallic squeaking)
- [Blake] Well, at least one good thing happened today.
- [Weiss] It looks abandoned.
- It's still better than this.
- Come on, I think we could all use some rest.
(wind whooshing)
(metallic clanging)