Stay close, move fast
The darkness cannot last
No hope, no path
But we’ve got a dream to catch
And we can not wait
Trust the way we’re made
The sparrow’s born to fly
The mountains tower
The river knows to reach the sea
Rain will help the flowers be
We’re the same you and me
The lightning doesn’t take advice from anyone
The willow doesn’t need to learn to stand
As sun seeks day
We'll find our way
And we’ll catch that dream together someday soon
We’re rising like the moon
- C'mon! You didn't even hear us out!
- Our orders are clear! The
Mistral-Atlas border is closed!
- Please!
- Have a good day!
- But...
- A good day!
- Hey, if you don't wanna believe
that I'm friends with Ironwood
- General Ironwood!
- Yeah, General Ironwood, then fine.
But look, we have Weiss Schnee with us
and we're trying to get her home safely.
- Approach!
- Very well! You may speak with our
commanding officer.
We will fetch her at once.
- Hup-hup-hup-hup-hup!
-Atlas! Atlas! Atlas!
- They were kind of...
- Super weird?
- Huh, yeah.
- Hmmmm...
- What's wrong?
- Well I, may know this
commanding officer.
- That's good isn't it?
If she's your friend
then maybe she'd be
more willing to help us.
- I wouldn't exactly call us..."friends".
- Acquaintances?
- Not quite.
- Colleagues?
- Warmer.
- Enemies?
- That's the one!
- Wait, what?
- Oh, yes. I come through here about once
every ten years to get my
eyes checked up in Atlas.
You bring outside cashews on one flight,
and suddenly you're
placed on the additional
screening list for life!
- You've gotta be kidding me.
- Now, now. Let's not give up hope yet.
Maybe she's dead.
- Introducing!
- Special operative!
- Caroline Cordovin!
- Witch.
- She-devil.
- Hm, I've seen you've chosen larger
contraband to smuggle this time.
- Oh, Cordo. You know they
say time changes people,
but I see you've still
got that stick right up-
- H-hello! Miss, uh, Cordovin.
My name is Ruby Rose, and I was wondering
if you would hear us out about-
- I've already heard what your
other little friends had to say, Miss Rose.
What are you doing back here??
I thought I told you to leave!
- And I told you we
wouldn't rest until you let us through!
- Nice to see again as well!
- You civilians are clearly incapable
of comprehending the importance
of our mission here in Argus.
So allow me to say this
slowly, with smaller words:
This base, that relay tower,
the very safety of Argus
are all gifts from the
glorious Kingdom of Atlas.
And it is my duty to uphold them, as only
I have the wit and tenacity for such a task.
- Such wit!
- Such tenacity!
- Or maybe Atlas just wanted to get you
as far from the kingdom as possible.
- You're just like the rest
of these Argus ingrates!
This city wouldn't even
be here if it weren't
for our Atlesian ancestors, and
what do we get in return? The entire world
is ready to put a knife to our throats!
- Please, we know your kingdom had nothing
to do with the fall of
Beacon -- we were there.
- No one's happy about the Atlas borders
or embargo, but I know General
Ironwood is just worried.
It's why we need to talk to-
- The General is no
coward! Atlas is strong.
If all the kingdoms plan
to make us their enemy,
then so be it! Atlas will prevail!
- Atlas will prevail!
- Do you guys seriously have to do that?
- If Miss Schnee has
truly come to her senses
and wishes to return to her family,
then of course the Atlas
military will escort her home.
But the Kingdom will not be responsible
for her "friends" of
questionable character.
- What's that supposed to mean?
- It means we're done here.
- Oh yeah? Well you're face looks...
Like a big dumb boot!
- Way to show her, Nora.
- I don't...
- [Ruby] Weiss.
- I told you we wouldn't
leave your side for a second.
We'll find a way to Atlas. Together.
- So, where are we going now?
- Yeah...what's the plan?
- The plan? The plan
just got shut on our face
three times over. I'm going for a drink.
- Uncle Qrow, I really think we should
try and come up with something...
...together.
- What's his problem? It's
not your fault we can't go on.
- If he's gonna be a jerk then we'll just
come up with something without him.
I mean, we've got Ozpin with us.
He usually knows what to do.
What is it?
- Jaune!
- Everything we did was for nothing!
- [Blake] That's not true.
- Really? Cuz it sure does sound like it.
- I, um....
- If Salem can't be killed, then
how are we supposed to win this?
- [Jaune] Wow.
- Great plan everyone.
- Look, none of this is great, we know.
But we're not the bad guys here.
- Are we sure about that?
- What?
- He's in your head, isn't he?
Did you already know about this?
- He didn't know any of it!
- How much longer can we even trust him?
- Jaune!
- How do we even know it's really him?
What if we've been talking
to that liar this whole time?
- Jaune!
- Is he gonna be okay?
- I don't know!
- I think it would be best if
we had some time to ourselves.
- Maybe we could all use some space.
- Come on, please.
Where are you?
- You know, I came out
here to avoid the yelling.
- Sorry.
The others went
to get food for tonight.
- Why not go with them?
- I don't know.
I don't know anything.
What do I tell Jaune and his team
when we don't even have a plan?
Qrow's out drinking,
Ozpin hasn't come back
and even if he did, I don't
know if I could trust him.
And there's always Jinn, but we only have
one more question we can ask her.
I feel like I'm letting everyone down.
- You know, you don't give
yourself enough credit.
- Oh, thanks.
- That wasn't a compliment.
- Uh...what?
- If I have to explain it to you,
it will just defeat the purpose.
But if you're tired of
not knowing anything,
how about we discuss those eyes of yours?
- Oh! Yes ma'am, I would be honored!
- Sit back down, for Pete's sake.
Let's start with what
you do know. Tell me.
- Uh... silver-eyed people are supposed
to be legendary warriors.
Or something.
And at the Fall of Beacon, I turned
a giant Wyvern into stone.
- Oh, boy.
- Look, if I already knew everything
I wouldn't be asking for help.
- Yelling.
It's not your fault.
I had my father to teach me, and even he
didn't have all the
answers. But what he told me
makes sense, given what I've seen.
- Was he a Huntsman too?
- It wasn't really an official
title back in his day.
I only knew him as an old
solider, and an excellent teacher.
I never attended one of those
fancy academies of yours,
but I scored higher on
the license exam than
any other Huntsman or Huntress that day.
- You must've been proud.
- He would've scolded me for showing off.
He'd never been able to find much
information about our abilities.
Just legends of warriors
whose eyes shown like mirrors,
reflecting the light of
the world onto darkness.
He found so little, in fact,
that it made him cautious.
How could such powerful
bloodlines be so rare?
Unless, something was actively
seeking to destroy them.
- Salem.
- I tried to keep my powers a secret.
But as you know, it wasn't enough.
I owe my life to my
training, and my Semblance.
At the end of the day, those are still
your most powerful tools.
- What is your Semblance?
- Preflexes! A silly name I came up with.
Hard to explain, but I can
sense everything better
than most and react to attacks
almost before they happen.
Combine that with my
training and secret ability
to turn Grimm to stone, or blind them,
or vaporize them. (clears throat)
And that's how you become the Grimm Reaper!
- So, how do I laser beam
monsters with my eyeballs?
- First, you stop thinking like that!
I want you to think of all
the times you've triggered
your powers. What did those
moments have in common?
- I was scared, and stressed.
Is it emotional? Like
unlocking a Semblance?
- It's emotional, but
more focused than that.
Think, what is it you wanted?
- I wanted to protect my friends.
- Precisely! It is the
desire to preserve life
which fuels the light inside you.
And to make no mistake, it is light.
Preservation is an extension of creation,
or, at the very least,
an enemy of destruction.
The Creatures of Grimm were
made by the God of Darkness,
but your light comes from his brother.
- How do you know that?
- I always knew how to use the light,
but never why it only worked on the Grimm.
Then, Jinn showed us her vision.
Were you paying attention?
- The God of Light...
His eyes.
Okay, where do we start?
- Well, not here.
The light will only work
in the presence of Grimm.
Meaning the only practice you'll get
will be a trial by fire.
But, what you can do
is focus on creating a state of mind
that you can tap into when you need it.
Don't think about your light as a means
of destroying evil, but as a way
to protect the people of Remnant.
- But that can't be right.
- Hm?
- You said the light only
reacts to Grimm, but...
I used it during our battle at Haven.
It reacted to Cinder.
- Interesting.
Perhaps there was something
that you just weren't seeing?
- Ruby!
- Oh, hey guys.
- What's going on?
- It's Oscar.
He's missing.