Keep dreaming 'bout a better world
You keep wishing for some clarity
Always hoping that a lightning bolt
Is gonna save you from this gravity
Your holding out for some romantic life
Maybe you'll wake up in a world of charm
Oh, but whats here can set you free
You don't have to dream
Your life's a masterpiece
If you just believe
Then all you see is all you need
Right now your hopes are shattered
Just pointless ever after
But in time you'll find
Through love your power just shines
When you don't know where to turn to
And you're sure all hope is gone
When the day you waited for won't come
And dark won't yield to dawn
Trust love
And open up your eyes
The truth is there but sometimes in disguise
The way's uncertain but we're together
Moving toward the light
When we trust in love
And open up our eyes
- [Jaune] Give up,
we've got you outnumbered.
- All right, then.
- [Ren] What?
- [Nora] Where'd she go?
- [Guard] Freeze!
- [Jaune] We gotta move!
- You Atlas Elites are all the same!
You think hoarding power
means you'll have it forever,
but it just makes the rest of us hungrier.
And I refuse to starve.
- I have come too far to be
stopped by some toy. (grunts)
- What are you doing?
My life doesn't matter.
- I disagree.
- Hurry, we gotta lose them!
- Guys?
- [Woman] They went this way!
- No!
- [Jaune] Oscar!
- [Jaune] Stop!
- [Guards] Drop your weapons!
(guns fire)
- Fall back!
- [Guards] This way.
- You had your time in the sun,
but now I'm afraid your time is up.
- Yes, I've been waiting here
for some time I think.
What was I waiting for?
- Me.
Huh?
- No.
I had a job to do.
- Huh?
- What is that?
- That's the power of a
fully realized maiden.
Ahh, it's too cold!
We have to do something.
Penny!
- [Oscar] I'm sorry.
- Don't be.
- We weren't ready to become huntsmen.
- That's not true!
- Then why aren't we holding the relic?
Now Salem has the lamp,
Ironwood has the staff,
and we have nothing!
- Ren, that's enough.
- [Pietro] Hello, anybody
there, can you hear me?
- Our scrolls, Doctor!
- [Maria] Ha ha, finest mind in Atlas!
- [Nora] Maria, what are you doing?
- Grabbing our getaway ship.
We need to hightail it out of here.
Where are you?
- [Nora] The academy training room.
We slipped away from some soldiers,
but it won't be long before...
- [Guards] They're here.
- [Yang] We're on our
way just stick together.
- Oscar, Oscar?
- [Oscar] Sorry, but you all
need to go on without me.
- What are you talking about?
- There's something I have to do alone.
- Are you okay?
- I had a job to do.
I was supposed to protect the power
of the maiden
until I was ready.
I worry I may have lost track of time.
But you can tell James that I'm ready now.
- Ma'am, if you do that--
- I'll be gone.
I know I have a hard time
remembering,
but I remember that.
What's your name?
- It's Penny, ma'am.
- Penny.
Are you the one?
- I...
- Winter, thank you, I know
that must have been difficult.
I-- I'm so sorry.
And whom do I have the
pleasure of speaking with?
- Still just me.
- It was smart of you not
to bring the lamp down here.
I wouldn't trust me either right now.
- Trust is what I'm hoping to fix.
I know we can still figure
this out, all of it, together.
Please.
- Do you intend to fight me?
- No, that's exactly what she wants.
I guess it's because of us
but holding it helps calm
me down when I'm afraid.
- You still think I'm afraid?
- We all are, it's what we
do in our fear that reveals--
- That's easy for you to say!
You can label me whatever you'd like,
but the fact of the matter is I was right!
The minute I softened, let my guard down,
that's when Salem had her open.
- If you abandon Mantle,
you abandon our best chance
of reuniting the world.
You abandon Remnant, leaving
millions to fend for themselves
so a few can survive, what kind of--
- All excellent philosophical points
that won't matter if Salem wins.
- Listen to me!
- No, you listen!
I am done letting others
inability to see the big picture
get in the way of doing what's right.
Robyn, the council,
this kingdom, even you.
- Then you're as dangerous
as she is, James.
- James is what my friends call me.
To you, it's General.
- I...
I...
- She's mine! (screams)
- No.
- [Weiss] Winter!
- Huh?
- [Ozpin] The single
quality that is common
across every living creature
on this planet
is fear.
- [Weiss] Winter.
- What did you do?
A new day
- [Ozpin] It's funny then,
that as common as fear is
Is gone without a trace
we so easily underestimate its power.
All memories are dark and light is fading
We tried so hard
- Are you all right? Penny, what happened?
- She's...
But what are we fighting for?
...gone.
- [Winter] No.
We're losing all our strength
How can we give more?
She's a part of you now.
Time falls away
- [Ozpin] Fear of
growing close to someone,
a subsequent fear of loss.
The pain always finds a way to stay
Fear of failure.
- [Blake] Come on!
The tears that you've shed
May find a tree to water
- Where's Oscar, and the relic?
But only when you're stronger
- [Ozpin] And as more
people depend on you,
those fears can take on greater power.
I promise I'll be here until the end
- [Ozpin] But fear itself
isn't worthy of concern.
It is who we become while in its clutches.
- I suggest you all surrender
(grunting)
and comply with the General's orders.
- We can't do that.
- Then, I suggest you run.
- No, you're hurt, I'm not
going to leave you like this.
- You're not leaving me.
I'm giving you a head start.
This is Special Operative Schnee
in need of immediate medical assistance.
Send reinforcements, over.
- We all have to carve out our own way.
- Guys you're...
- We need to go.
- [Ozpin] Will you
be proud of that person?
Will you forgive them?
Will you understand why they felt the need
to do the things they did?
Will you even recognize them?
Or will the person staring back at you
be the very thing you should
have feared from the start?
- [Ozpin] I suppose we all
find out sooner or later.
- That power, these memories,
you're back aren't you?
You saved me.
- [Ozpin] Actually you saved us.
Oscar, I--
- Stop, all I want to know
is how we save Atlas next.
- [Pilot] We've got multiple
hostiles on radar.
Is anyone else seeing this?
- [Pilot] These readings can't be right.
I'd understand
If you'd rather not
Talk about this
There's always a chance
That we might remain
In ignorant bliss
Most of the time
We coast along
Safe from the storm
We follow our hearts
Trust what feels right
Keep to the norm
We are lucky
If our lives
Can avoid it
But fear changes
All of our choices
Who will you see
There in the darkness?
When no one is watching
Who will you be?
When you're afraid
And everything changes
Will you see a stranger
Feel proud, or betrayed?
All of your life
Guided by truth
Right from the start
Then one twist of fate
In the blink of an eye
And it all falls apart
What happens then
When all that you knew
Just fades away?
When you've lost all control
You've broke from your soul
And fear has its day
Will you make the
Right choice in
That moment?
Will you stand and be brave
Or be broken?
We live in fear
That we might fail
Fear
That we'll succeed
That we may not provide
The things our loved ones need
But our greatest fear
Will be realized
If we fall
And lose ourselves to fear
We've become what we feared
All our lives
Who will you see
There in the darkness?
When no one is watching
Who will you be?
When you're afraid
And everything changes
Will you see a stranger
Feel proud, or betrayed?