Keep dreaming 'bout a better world
You keep wishing for some clarity
Always hoping that a lightning bolt
Is gonna save you from this gravity
Your holding out for some romantic life
Maybe you'll wake up in a world of charm
Oh, but whats here can set you free
You don't have to dream
Your life's a masterpiece
If you just believe
Then all you see is all you need
Right now your hopes are shattered
Just pointless ever after
But in time you'll find
Through love your power just shines
When you don't know where to turn to
And you're sure all hope is gone
When the day you waited for won't come
And dark won't yield to dawn
Trust love
And open up your eyes
The truth is there but sometimes in disguise
The way's uncertain but we're together
Moving toward the light
When we trust in love
And open up our eyes
- [Weiss] Only my father
would turn a hostile takeover
into a fluffy PR move.
- On the news, he said he
just wanted to break bread
and hash things out.
Maybe it won't be so bad.
We do want the General to start opening up
to these people, right?
- Yeah, but on his terms.
Ironwood's going to be locked in a room
at his rival's own dinner party.
I know Jacques says
he's happy to moderate,
but all that really means is he'll
be the one controlling the conversation.
- Not hard to imagine how
that's gonna play out.
- [Weiss] I still can't believe he won.
Robyn was supposed to be
the people's champion,
wasn't she? (sighs)
There's just too many coincidences.
- You really think your
dad might have something
to do with Salem?
- I think my father would
do whatever it takes to win.
- And we should do the same.
- Meaning...?
- Well, no one knows
your dad better than you,
and out of everyone going tonight,
I'd say you're the only
one who could snoop
around the house and not be questioned.
If Jacques Schnee is up to something,
I think we should know what it is.
- Suppose we should smile for the cameras?
- Sir, with all due respect,
you'd have to pay me.
- Good evening, everyone.
- Where's Klein?
- What an interesting way to
say, "Hello, dear brother,
"how have you been?"
I'm afraid you won't find him here.
He was let go.
I can't imagine why.
General, exactly how large do you think
our dining room table is?
- I happen to know it's enormous,
but most of my guests will be on standby
in case the Council requests
additional eye witnesses.
Until then, I'm sure they'll
be happily celebrating
your father's victory.
- For those of you joining
us in the dining room,
please follow me.
- Wish us luck.
- (chuckling) I mean,
they already invited you,
didn't they?
(chuckling)
- Care for a drink, sir?
- Uh, no, no thanks.
I think ill just stick
to patrolling the grounds.
- Words out of my mouth.
- Right, well, don't wander off,
don't break anything, and be ready
in case the General calls on you.
- [Vine] Hors d'oeuvres?
- [Elm] Let's eat them out of house and home.
- Counterpoint, how
about we do wander off,
consider breaking things, and
then all that other stuff.
- I'll be in touch.
- Dear sister, I was hoping
we could use this time
to catch up.
- Oh...
- I have to know,
why did you go through so much trouble
to leave home, only to come crawling back?
- This might be a problem.
- [Jacques] General Ironwood,
please: have a seat.
- Councilman Sleet, Councilwoman Camilla.
- [Robyn] Councilwoman Hill would
have had a nice ring to it.
Though I suppose I should just be grateful
I got invited to the table.
- Miss Hill, that vigor
of yours is precisely
why we're grateful to
have you with us tonight.
- What is she doing here?
- What we're all doing here, James,
addressing the concerns of our kingdom,
which means we have much to discuss.
- [Ironwood] Indeed. I was
hoping we could start by --
- [Jacques] Are we safe
with her here, by the way?
I do recall come confusion regarding
her involvement in that horrific massacre.
- As the official report stated,
that footage was doctored.
Penny is completely under my control.
- [Jacques] Which is concerning, I think.
- Concerning?
- [Jacques] Let's talk about
exactly what it is you control.
- Why won't this kid buzz off?
- We need to do something.
- What was that earlier
about breaking things?
- [Weiss] Well, Whitley, I'm sure the company
is lucky to have you,
but if you'll pardon me--
- And where exactly is
it that you're going?
- [Nora] Careful, messy
food comin' through!
- [Whitley] Of course, once I'm
old enough to drive,
the company has promised
me my own parking space,
- [Butler] Care for a drink?
- Don't mind if I do!
(crashing)
- [Nora] Oh no, look out!
- I'm going to go get some hors d'oeuvres.
- Yeah!
(splashing)
Oops.
- If you'll excuse me.
- The fact of the matter
is, you've operated
with a fair amount of autonomy
for the past few years, James.
But what we need now is for you
to work with us.
- [Ironwood] Sir, I have--
- It's obvious that no kingdom intends
to declare war on Atlas.
We had no involvement in
the incident at Haven,
we have proof our drones weren't
acting on orders at Beacon.
At this point, the
closure of Atlas borders
is only serving to hurt our relations
with the rest of the world.
- I--
- The rest of the world?
It's hurting us.
The people of Atlas are suffering
and they want to know why.
- [Jacques] Quite right, Ms. Hill.
And I'm afraid there's
more than just your choices
that have brought harm to
our citizens as of late.
Have your forces found
any additional evidence
as to who is slaughtering
innocent civilians down in Mantle?
- That is an ongoing investigation,
the details of which are
classified, I'm afraid.
- [Jacques] I'm afraid
of the ever-growing list
of classified information
you seem to be keeping.
I asked our fellow councilmen here
to shed some light on your
Amity Colosseum project
and, as it turns out, they
know about as much as I do.
- Even you don't know?
- [Ironwood] The Amity
project will help with all
of the issues you've
presented, but you have
to understand that discretion
is a top priority
at this time.
- [Jacques] Are you
saying you don't trust us?
- You can't just buy trust
like everything else,
you have to earn it.
- I couldn't have said it better myself.
General, if I may be blunt, you have spent
what little trust this
council had left in you.
The hacker who turned
Atlas drones against us
was never captured,
whoever's been murdering
your critics is still at large.
How are we supposed to give you our trust,
when you've given us nothing as of late?
- That's not what--
- Winter.
That's enough.
- [Winter] Excuse me.
- Miss Schnee, is everything okay?
- I'm fine, thank you!
Keep up the great work.
- [Willow] Hello darling.
- [Penny] Are you okay?
- I'll be fine, I just let my emotions
get the better of me.
- What do you mean?
- You wouldn't understand.
- Oh, right.
- No, no, what I mean is: this place
holds a lot of memories
for me, specifically.
I thought I was in
control, but you heard me.
I sounded like a petulant child.
- I thought you sounded fine.
You were just speaking from your heart.
- And that is precisely the problem.
I should have just stayed in line.
- I guess you're right,
I don't understand.
- I'm sorry I couldn't
come down for your party,
I'm afraid I'm not feeling well.
- Um, it's okay, Mom, it's fine.
- What are you doing in
your father's office?
- Just looking for something I left.
- That's right, you left.
You left.
- I need to use father's computer.
- Why?
- Because I think
he may have done
something. Something wrong.
- I thought we all simply
assumed that at this point.
- Yes, well, some of us are trying
to do something about it.
- He started locking his home computer.
But, he still has blind spots.
- You put a camera in here?
- I put them in every room of this house,
for our safety, in case
I ever needed to...
You haven't come back to stay, have you?
- No.
- Good.
(sniffling) A man came by.
I'm afraid your father may be involved
in something more
dangerous than he realizes.
[Willow] No matter what happens, Weiss,
please don't forget about your brother.
- [Weiss] Whitley wants
nothing to do with me.
- [Willow] Of course not, you
left him alone. With us.
- Who are you?
- Hey mom, it's snowing!