Keep dreaming 'bout a better world
You keep wishing for some clarity
Always hoping that a lightning bolt
Is gonna save you from this gravity
Your holding out for some romantic life
Maybe you'll wake up in a world of charm
Oh, but whats here can set you free
You don't have to dream
Your life's a masterpiece
If you just believe
Then all you see is all you need
Right now your hopes are shattered
Just pointless ever after
But in time you'll find
Through love your power just shines
When you don't know where to turn to
And you're sure all hope is gone
When the day you waited for won't come
And dark won't yield to dawn
Trust love
And open up your eyes
The truth is there but sometimes in disguise
The way's uncertain but we're together
Moving toward the light
When we trust in love
And open up our eyes
- [Newscaster] Although rioting in Mantle
is finally under control,
how does it feel to know that the majority
of those involved were your supporters?
- I don't condone rioting,
especially when our
city is being denied aid
for the hardships we've
already had to go through,
but Jacques Schnee's
latest stunt is holding
the city hostage for
his own political gain.
So I understand their anger,
but ask that they show
it not in the streets
but at the polls today.
- Ah, ah!
(ball banging)
- Ah!
(weapon buzzing)
- Nice, your recovery is getting faster.
- [Oscar] Have you always
been able to do that?
- (panting) I don't know.
I don't normally think
it through that much.
- You guys are evolving
and I still don't even have my Semblance.
- [Ruby] Well, I bet we'll
all be jealous when you do.
- [Ironwood] Clover wasn't kidding.
You're really giving this your all.
- Well, we have to with
the way things are going.
- They're not going well, are they?
- Better Robyn then Jacques Schnee.
- [Ironwood] Oh, I suppose so.
Either way, this election
doesn't bode well
for our stability.
- It could be a chance to work with Robyn
and get Mantle on your side.
- The likelihood of that working --
- [Nora] She's right,
you have to do something
about Mantle.
if you could get Robin to trust you.
- I bet if you opened up
to her she'd understand
that you're being framed.
- (sighs) Perhaps,
but it will only work
if she's open too.
- I take it your here for
new mission assignments.
- You could say that.
The General and I want
you to take the rest
of the day to recuperate.
- You're giving us a night off?
- Ordering it.
After tonight's election,
we'll be waking up
to a very different Atlas tomorrow.
I need you rested and ready
for whatever that may bring.
- [Newscaster] We still
have hours ahead of us,
but as votes come in, it
looks more and more certain
that Robyn Hill will fill
the open council seat.
- There's no way my
father could've thought
layoffs would do anything but hurt him.
So why announce this the
day before the election?
- Just seems like a power
play that backfired to me.
Won't matter in a few hours though.
- Where are you guys going?
- Team FNKI invited us out dancing.
Yang and I thought it would be good
to get our minds off the election.
- I thought you said
Team FNKI was annoying.
- That's the best part about dance clubs.
(whispers) I can't hear you.
- Ruby, come on!
- I still can't believe
you're going to that thing.
- Just because Ironwood dislikes Robyn
doesn't mean we all have to.
From where I'm standing, both
of them seem to be trying
their best to help Atlas.
As to who's doing a better job...
- (sighs) But a victory party?
- [Ruby] Invite's still open if you want in.
Penny's gonna be working security.
- Oh my gosh, no. You
gotta do it like this.
- That's what I'm doing!
- Hey, Oscar and I are hitting the
movies if anyone wants --
- Yup!
- Oh, okay.
- [Ren] I understand Weiss' point though,
a victory party does
seem a bit premature.
- Aw, let them have one sure thing.
- [Ruby] Probably the last sure thing
before Amity Tower goes up
and everyone learns about...
what we're fighting.
- We spent so much time worrying
about how Ironwood will
react to the truth about her,
but have any of us considered
how we're even going to beat her
if we manage to work past that?
- [Nora] Jinn said she can't be beaten.
- [Ruby] She told Oz that he couldn't destroy her.
- But maybe someone else could?
- I don't know.
- We should be training right now.
- We've trained enough!
Take some time to --
- We don't have time!
Party people gonna stay up late
Oh, and celebrate tonight
Oh, tonight
Grab your dancin' shoes
Put away those blues tonight
- Ruby, Nora, Ren!
- Hey, Penny.
- I am so glad you made it.
It's just Marrow and I tonight,
so more friends means more fun.
Where are the others?
- Weiss is out with the boys,
and Blake and Yang are off
doing their own thing,
Again.
- At least they're back to being friends.
- Friends, huh? Just friends?
- What else would they be?
- Two people who've
gone through that much,
I think there's more going on.
- Well maybe one of them feels that way
but the other might be worried.
- [Nora] About what?
- [Ren] It's just, there's a lot of things
going on right now.
- [Nora] Well, how can
they figure things out
if they don't talk about it?
- I believe I may be confused.
Who are we talking about again?
- I'm not really sure.
- [Marrow] Penny, where'd you go?
- Please don't leave me!
- Oh hey, what -- what're you doing here?
- Just hangin' out with a
friend while she's on the job.
- [Marrow] Yeah, real cute.
Look, try not to be too
much of a distraction.
We need to be vigilant in case --
- [May] In case what?
- In case someone tries to start trouble.
- Oh, funny, that's why we're here.
So feel free to take a hike.
- Listen, the General's
trying to help, all right?
Just 'cause you can't understand --
- [Robyn] What's going on here, Wags?
Oh, and the pipsqueak is back.
- (scoffs) We're concerned
about security risks, ma'am.
The General doesn't want
any surprises tonight.
- Fine, but stay out of the way.
If I get elected tonight,
we'll all have to learn how to get along.
- Sure, we won't have any problems,
as long as you stay within the law.
- The law isn't perfect, you know.
It's certainly not equal.
- Trust me, I'm well aware.
- My only goal is that all the citizens
of Mantle and Atlas -- and
Faunus -- have an equal shot
at a good life.
- That sounds great.
And you're planning to do all
that equalizing legally, right?
- Everything I've done is legal.
- Of course, 100%.
- Ha-ha, well, that worked.
- Scram kid, we've got a job to do.
- Can we please just
not do this right now?
- I should've just gone to the movies.
- I want to thank everyone
for going to the polls today.
This is Mantle's moment.
I know that, like me, you're all thrilled
that we chose Robyn as our voice in Atlas.
No one has fought harder
for Mantle than she has.
And... I know Robyn will continue
that fight on the Council.
(giggles) Will you share a few words?
- I've never been much
for public speaking,
probably wasn't my best idea
ever to go into politics.
Thank you so much,
everyone, for choosing me.
You said you believe in me.
But I'm the one who
believes in all of you.
You've proven to me that as
individuals, we are strong.
But together, we're unstoppable.
So no matter what happens
tonight, win or lose,
we will continue to fight for our city,
because it is this city
that brings us together.
- [Newscaster] We're in
the final minutes now,
and it's looking to be a
closer race than anticipated.
Baby let's get real
Tell me what's the deal
- Don't worry, it's in the bag.
I've gotta know what you're thinkin'
Oh
Let your heart reveal
Show me how you feel
Tell me it's love
- (sighs) Ren, what's going on?
Oh
That it's you and me
Why won't you just talk to me?
Let this girl run free
- You know I've never been
really good with talking.
That it's you and me
Let this girl run free
- Then screw talking!
Tell me it's love
- You ready, Tyrian?
- (chuckles) Always.
- [Robyn] The polls are
about to close. 12, 11--
[Crowd] 10, nine, eight,
seven, six, five, four, three--
- [Ruby] Watch out!
- Go.
- Ah, ah!
- [Marrow] Penny, what's
going on over there?
- [Penny] Put down your
weapon and surrender!
- [Marrow] This is Ace Operative Marrow,
requesting immediate assistance!
- Huntresses, to me!
- Come on, we've gotta get you outta here!
Ah!
- Robyn!
- Right on time!
- [Newscaster] And the winner
of the Atlas Council election is...
Jacques Schnee!
- It's Ironwood's robot!
- Penny.
- I-- I didn't.
- [Jacques] O-ho, thank you everyone, thank you.
It's all because of you.
It's a new day in Atlas.
We've won, we did it!
- What happened?
- It was Tyrian, Tyrian's here!
(fingers clicking)
- Stay!
- Get Penny out the back, now!
- I'm okay, I'm okay.
- I'm sorry, is she --
This wasn't us, I swear.
- Fine work, Tyrian. I think
we are done for tonight.
- [Newscaster] A surprise victory
by SDC Mining Corporation's
CEO, Jacques Schnee.
Last minute voter turnout
produced a dark horse victory
for the dust industry leader.
- Penny, you need to get to Atlas.
Backup's on the way.
- [Marrow] Penny?
- Grimm.
- (sighs) We've got a long night ahead.
- [Jacques] And as the
newest member of the Council,
I pledge to serve each and every citizen
of Mantle and Atlas.