- [Radio] Manta 5-1.
Welcome home.
Please continue your approach
to Atlas docking bay, Omega-12.
A security team will meet you there.
Over.
- I don't understand.
What's happening here?
- I don't know.
- But we are here.
We got the lamp to Atlas.
So, I guess we land and get some answers.
- [Weiss] I'm not so sure.
I've never seen our forces
deployed so aggressively before.
If we land in a stolen ship,
there's no way the security team
will let us anywhere near Ironwood.
They might even take me back to my father.
- So...
- Winter!
Put some distance
between us and the fleet.
- You don't have to tell me twice.
- [Braodcast] ...cannot express
our appreciation enough....
Many describe these as uncertain times,
and while that may be the case
for the rest of the world,
I can tell you what is certain.
The Kingdom of Atlas will remain strong,
and it will remain safe.
That is my promise.
- General Ironwood.
He looks...
- Tired.
- James, what have you been doing?
- [Civilian 1] Ugh, not these again.
- [Civilian 2] Why can't
they just leave us be?
- This isn't right.
None of this is right.
- [Radio] Manta 5-1, we've
noticed a detour in your route.
You are to make your way
to docking bay Omega-12
immediately, do you copy?
Over.
- We're kind of running
out of time here, kids.
- We need to ditch the ship.
- Agreed.
Get lost in Mantle and
buy ourselves some time.
- I'm telling you, my sister
can take us to Ironwood.
- Uh, Weiss?
- [Broadcast] A reminder.
- Huh?
- Failure to cooperate with
Atlas military personnel
is a punishable offense.
If your sector
is under lockdown...
- Winter?
- No offense, Weiss.
I'm not sure that's a good idea anymore.
- There's obviously something very wrong.
If we can just talk to her, then we--
- Look, I'm not even sure we
should be talking to Ironwood
until we know exactly
what's going on with Mantle.
- But--
- Everyone, calm down.
(sighs) I know someone
who can help with both.
- [Radio] Manta 5-1, you are to make your-
- Jeez, lady, take a hint.
- [Soldier] It landed
over there, let's go!
- Come on now, hurry!
It shouldn't be much of a walk.
- Is this many soldiers normal?
- No.
At least, I didn't think so.
- Huh?
Ooh.
Maybe we should pick up the pace.
- You have to remember,
the kingdom had just lost the Great War.
The people of Mantle needed
a sign of a brighter future,
and that sign was Atlas.
After all, a home in the clouds
is about as bright as it gets.
- Unless you're the one
having to look up at it.
- This whole city, it just seems awful.
- Yeah?
You don't like it here?
There's plenty of space out in the tundra.
- Sorry, I didn't mean to-
- Atlas is the greatest kingdom
in the world, all right?
- Hey!
- We can't cause a scene.
- The embargo-
the embargo's got us in a rough patch,
but it'll blow over, you'll see.
- We try and help the other kingdoms,
and this is what happens?
I say let 'em rot!
- I apologize.
I didn't mean to insult you.
- Stupid Faunus like you
wouldn't under-
- It was worth it.
- Hey, wait!
You're-
that was-
- We are here for your safety.
Thank you for your cooperation.
- [Man] And no more heavy lifting,
you hear?
- Ah, it's good to see you again,
old friend.
- Ah, yes, yes.
Have we met?
- Well, this is off to a fantastic start.
- Cybernetic optical implants.
You adjust them.
Every 10 years or so?
- Maria!
Yes, with the cybernetic optical implants!
I adjust them every 10 years or so.
(laughing) Oh wow, has it
been that long already?
- Ah, I know.
I age like a fine wine.
Would've been here sooner if I hadn't
run into these jokers.
At the time,
I thought they might need my guidance
while fighting a little old sphinx.
- Oh, did they?
- No, no.
They had much more complicated issues.
- (clearing throat) And this is?
- So impatient.
I didn't think I'd need
to introduce one of
Atlas' finest minds.
- Working in a place like this?
- He likes to keep a low profile.
Something I've come to realize
none of you know anything about.
- You can call me Pietro.
- Finest heart, too.
This pharmacy is just where he volunteers
when he's not building the future of Atlas
alongside Ironwood,
up in the clouds.
- Oh, it's stuffy up there.
Down here I get to help the locals
and have a little fun.
I'm currently working on shoes
that make you dance.
You wanna try 'em on?
- Yes!
- Before we get to that,
we were wondering if you could help us?
We came to Atlas hoping to
talk with General Ironwood,
but, um...
- What exactly has been happening here?
- (coughing) Well, the
fall of Beacon took a toll
on all of us.
James was no different.
I couldn't tell you exactly what it was
he saw there,
but it changed him.
He's...
- He's scared.
- Paranoid would be the
more appropriate term.
You have to understand,
it wasn't just the Grimm.
Someone completely dismantled
Atlas security code.
Made it their play-thing.
And made us look like traitors to some and
buffoons to everyone else.
Whoever managed to do that
is either a genius or
one of our own.
I fear the answer may be both.
And so does the General.
- Maybe Atlas isn't as safe as we thought.
- After we came all this way,
we can't just leave,
can we?
- How does the council
feel about all of this?
Or Winter Schnee?
Do you know anything about her?
- Well, the council's so scared,
they'll agree to whatever he wants.
Though some representatives from Mantle...
Wait,
you're Weiss Schnee!
- Wait, what was it that you were trying
to say about Mantle?
- You painted it.
- What?
- Is everything okay?
- You're Team RWBY.
- You know us?!
- Oh, my girl I do.
I most certainly do.
And I feel like such a
dunce for not recognizing
you sooner.
My daughter's told me so much about you.
- Your... daughter?
- Ah, trouble.
- Wait!
- I guess the city
defenses aren't doing much.
- Somehow that doesn't surprise me.
- Hm?
- Well, we didn't come
this far to fail now!
- Hey!
Hm!
- Penny!
- Darling,
why don't you say hello to your friends?
- Sal-
U-
TATIONS!
It is such a pleasure
to see you all again!
- Penny, I-
I thought you-
- [Pietro] Died?
I guess in a manner of speaking,
she did.
But we were able to recover her core
from Amity Arena once it had made its way
back to Atlas.
It took me some time, but-
- I'm as good as new!
Better even.
And now I'm the official
protector of the city!
- That's my girl.
We're not going to let a little
ripping to shreds stop us,
are we? (laughing)
- No, sir!
- This is...
- Strangely wholesome.
- Sounds like Penny to me.
- We have so many things
to catch up about.
I cannot wait.
It seems we will have to wait.
Let's talk more later.
I can't wait to hear about all
your adventures- (whooshing)
I'm very excited for the whole experience!
- I can't tell if I completely
understand what's going on,
or have like,
a million questions!
- And thankfully,
I have about a thousand answers.
But let's get out of this weather first.
- I have absolutely no
idea who that child was.
Is she important somehow?
- That was unexpected.
- Never a dull moment.
- But I wouldn't say unwelcome.
I was honestly expecting things to
go a lot rougher.
- Good work, team.
- Hey!
What's going on?
- Hey, pal.
I'm a licensed Huntsman.
Just helped save everyone?
- Hm.
Let's get them loaded
into the next transport.
- Please!
We were just trying to help.
- What is the meaning of this?
(coughing) What are the
Ace-Ops even doing down
here in Mantle?
- Ace-Ops?
- Doctor.
Good to see you.
Well, we heard a report
of an unauthorized ship
making an unauthorized landing
followed by an unauthorized use of weapons
by non-licensed Huntsmen.
- If we could just talk this out-
- They'll be able to talk this out
once they get up to Atlas.
Let's move out!
- Now, this...
This is much closer to
what I was expecting.
Keep dreaming 'bout a better world
You keep wishing for some clarity
Always hoping that a lightning bolt
Is gonna save you from this gravity
Your holding out for some romantic life
Maybe you'll wake up in a world of charm
Oh, but whats here can set you free
You don't have to dream
Your life's a masterpiece
If you just believe
Then all you see is all you need
Right now your hopes are shattered
Just pointless ever after
But in time you'll find
Through love your power just shines
When you don't know where to turn to
And you're sure all hope is gone
When the day you waited for won't come
And dark won't yield to dawn
Trust love
And open up your eyes
The truth is there but sometimes in disguise
The way's uncertain but we're together
Moving toward the light
When we trust in love
And open up our eyes