Keep dreaming 'bout a better world
You keep wishing for some clarity
Always hoping that a lightning bolt
Is gonna save you from this gravity
Your holding out for some romantic life
Maybe you'll wake up in a world of charm
Oh, but whats here can set you free
You don't have to dream
Your life's a masterpiece
If you just believe
Then all you see is all you need
Right now your hopes are shattered
Just pointless ever after
But in time you'll find
Through love your power just shines
When you don't know where to turn to
And you're sure all hope is gone
When the day you waited for won't come
And dark won't yield to dawn
Trust love
And open up your eyes
The truth is there but sometimes in disguise
The way's uncertain but we're together
Moving toward the light
When we trust in love
And open up our eyes
- [Nora] Here, kitty kitty!
- Now!
- Head to the nearest shelter!
- Those shelters are gonna fill up soon.
- They're all we've got.
We just have to hold off the Grimm.
- Okay, yes sir, understood, over and out.
- New orders?
- Let's go.
- Take us to Atlas, we
won't survive down here.
- Why isn't Ironwood doing anything?
- Please, everyone. We're doing our best.
We will get you to safety.
Just give us a little more time!
- Atlas, Mantle, I know you're scared.
I'm here with General Ironwood,
and we have a message for you.
What he has to say may sound unbelievable,
but it is all true.
- An ancient and terrible evil lies
outside of our kingdom.
It was responsible for
the destruction of Beacon,
the attack on Haven, and for
the recent attacks on Mantle.
This powerful force goes
by the name of Salem.
- He's doing it!
- [Ironwood] Salem
seeks only to divide us.
- To turn us against each other.
- If she can incite hatred in us,
Then we will lure in the Grimm,
and destroy ourselves.
- [Robyn] Salem herself does
not work alone.
Her minions have invaded our very city.
- [Ironwood] Arthur
Watts and Tyrian Callows.
These men are the ones responsible
for the recent murders in Mantle,
and for sabotaging the heating grid.
But we cannot let ourselves
give in to fear and panic.
That is what she wants!
Instead, we must unite,
and fight back, together.
Every single one of us!
- Alright, single file line!
Place a hand on the shoulder in front of you,
eyes forward, move, move, move!
Show them how it's done, kids!
- Where did you learn to do that?
- Morning school route?
- [Ironwood] This, my
friends, is why I was forced
to divert resources from Mantle.
For the Amity Communication Tower.
Amity Tower is now completed,
and ready to launch.
It will re-establish all
global communications--
- The Colosseum remodeling
was a communications tower?
How did James get this past me?
- [Ironwood] The council and I have decided
to evacuate everyone in Mantle to Atlas.
I am withdrawing all defenses from Amity
in order to assist with
repelling the Grimm in Mantle.
- We must put aside our differences
and band together to defeat this threat.
I fully support General Ironwood's plan.
- The Grimm should have
destroyed our enemies,
not made them friends!
- Wait, our tin soldier's
heart has cost him his mind.
We need to keep their attention on Mantle
for as long as possible.
- You want more chaos
than a Grimm invasion?
- If anyone on Remnant could deliver that,
wouldn't it be you?
- [Robyn] If you've made it to your
local shelter, stay put.
Help is on the way.
And for those of you in Sector 17,
I'll be seeing you personally.
- Come to think of it, I do have an idea.
- [Cinder] I still can't believe
those idiots beat us here.
Vacuo was supposed to be the next target.
The timeline has changed.
You said the farm boy has the lamp?
Find him, take it.
No, we get what I need first!
Then we get what we want, now go.
Ironwood's been hiding the
Winter Maiden for years.
Tonight I'm going to find her.
The general's as
predictable as his androids.
Threaten what he has, and
he'll flock to protect it.
- Get in, get in!
- I've got this!
- Alright, we just need
to get everyone to the closest air pad.
- The closest LZ is...
- There.
- Penny, are you okay?
- Ouch, those tusks sure are dangerous.
- They sure are.
I think I have a plan.
- What is it?
- [Penny] Over here, you big bag of bones!
- [Ruby] Now!
- Yeah, they saved us!
- [Woman In Crowd] The
protector of Mantle!
- [Yang] Just sent the ship up.
Heading to the next LZ.
- [Nora] Ditto.
- [Jaune] Same here!
- Ms. Hill, the southern
outskirts are clear.
It should be safe to
begin evacuations now.
- Great work, Penny. Over and out.
Make sure you get these people to safety.
I'm gonna check for any stragglers.
- Robyn Hill, for such a little bird,
you have quite the impact around here!
Bringing hope and a smile wherever you go!
I find it... upsetting.
- Sorry Callows, I really
wanted to pummel you on my own,
but the general insisted I share.
- Well, you're not the
only one with a grudge.
- You'll both have to get in line.
- Hmm... This will certainly do the trick.
Although I wouldn't
exactly call it finished.
- [Ironwood] Arthur Watts...
Welcome.
- It wasn't finished, it was bait.
- You know, James, this place has
always been a technological marvel.
- Truly, even before you
went and did all this.
The different types of
dust, the biome system,
and of course, everything that
goes into controlling them.
- You always were a pain in the ass.
- At the risk of sounding cliche, James,
I won't be going down without a fight.