Keep dreaming 'bout a better world
You keep wishing for some clarity
Always hoping that a lightning bolt
Is gonna save you from this gravity
Your holding out for some romantic life
Maybe you'll wake up in a world of charm
Oh, but whats here can set you free
You don't have to dream
Your life's a masterpiece
If you just believe
Then all you see is all you need
Right now your hopes are shattered
Just pointless ever after
But in time you'll find
Through love your power just shines
When you don't know where to turn to
And you're sure all hope is gone
When the day you waited for won't come
And dark won't yield to dawn
Trust love
And open up your eyes
The truth is there but sometimes in disguise
The way's uncertain but we're together
Moving toward the light
When we trust in love
And open up our eyes
- Aahhh!
- You guys were incredible.
Oh, the way you took down
that Geist without needing
to plan your tactics out, you
just knew exactly what to do.
- Well, Ace-Ops are hand-picked to
perfectly complement one another.
So we can focus on our assets
and leave our liabilities behind.
- Some of us are all
asset, zero liability.
- Wha-- Yeah? Think I've
got some liabilities, Elm?
- Your brains, for one.
- Ohh.
- You did ask.
- Hi. Do you need a new best friend?
Our pair name can be --
THUNDER THIGHS!
- Perfect complementary
teamwork. Oh, yeah.
I wnt to have my friends'
backs just like that.
- Friends?
- Ha ha, this isn't the schoolyard, kid.
- Thunder thighs...
- But, I mean, when you go through so much
with someone it kind of
changes things, doesn't it?
- We got along well enough, sure.
I count on them to keep me alive.
They do the same. But that's the job.
We don't confuse the two.
- Speaking of the job...
- Yes, sir.
- Duty ever beckons. You
all hang back a second.
- [Clover] Briefing already, sir?
- What do you guys want to
do when we get back to Atlas?
Sightseeing? (gasps) Oh,
what should we visit first?
- (yawns) How about our beds?
- Oh, come on, guys! This is
a great time to go exploring.
We haven't done that in so long.
- Ruby, we just explored
a whole continent on foot
before flying to this one.
- Well, yeah. But it was
only the boring parts.
- We almost died.
- [Qrow] Hey. Heads up.
- Can I get the team leaders over here?
There's something I'd
like to discuss with you.
You too, Qrow.
- [Ironwood] I need you on the
ground, but be subtle.
If people see too many
huntsmen milling around
they'll get nervous.
And Clover? Don't take Marrow.
- New problems in Mantle?
- More of the same, unfortunately.
Someone in Mantle is taking out
public leaders who
speak out against Atlas.
Specifically, people who
speak out against me.
It didn't look like a pattern at first.
But this is the third murder of
its kind in the last week.
- Wait a minute. That's the guy
that rode with us after we were arrested.
- He died?
- Your opposition in Mantle dropping dead
isn't exactly a good look for you, huh?
- Not really worried
about my public image,
but it is causing unrest.
I think someone's trying to frame me
and by extension, Atlas.
And it's working.
- Well, if it wasn't
for the embargo making
everybody so mad, people
probably wouldn't be
so quick to blame you for everything else.
(clears throat) S-sir.
- No. No. You're right.
Things in Mantle have been...
hard to manage lately.
I'm not blind to its issues.
In fact, that's what I
want to talk to you about.
With the launch of this
mobile communications tower
and tensions down in Mantle,
I think there's a lot of good
your teams can do here.
What? Already? Here?
No, it's fine. Let him land.
I'll deal with him myself.
- More Mantle problems?
- No. This one's an Atlas problem.
- So let me get this straight, James.
In addition to this nonsensical embargo
of yours crippling my business,
you've also decided you have the authority
to commandeer private property?
When the Council hears about this,
you will never --
- Actually, I've already informed them.
As this is now the site of a
classified military operation,
it didn't even require a vote.
- Didn't require a vote?
- You might want to brush up on
Council law before you lose this
upcoming election, Jacques.
Now. I've allowed you to land here
once as a courtesy,
the next time, it won't
a friendly reception.
- Lately, you seem to forget
who your friends really are.
I'm going to get that council seat, James,
and maybe then you'll --
You...
You roped my missing daughter
into these schemes of yours, too?
How long has she been back in Atlas?
Did Winter know about this?
- It was my decision to come here.
Just like it was my decision to leave.
Or have you forgotten all about that?
- If you think I'm one
to forget anything, girl,
then you've misjudged
the man your father is.
- Believe me, I know exactly
the kind of man you are.
- How dare you speak to me that way?
I have half a mind to --
- [Ironwood] Half a mind to what, Jacques?
- You know, your mother was
devastated when you left.
Didn't leave her room for days.
You know how she gets when she's upset.
I knew one day you would
overextend your reach.
I didn't come here to beg
for an abandoned mine.
I came here to thank you.
For personally handing
me the noose to hang you.
You'll regret this.
So these are the little friends
you threw everything away for?
- Not friends. Family.
- Hmm...
- [Weiss] Oh, now you show up, Winter.
You just missed Father.
- I wouldn't say I missed hi-
(crash)
[All] Ah!
- Surprise!
(party horn)
Uh, did we not start yet?
- Ugh. Apparently, we haven't.
- Start what?
- It goes without saying
that this arena
holds a significance to all of us.
It's only fitting that we
should be able to reconvene here.
Now. When the world needs to be
brought together more than ever,
the road you traveled
from our first meeting
hasn't been easy.
- You fought for your school
and your friends at Beacon.
You fought for the world
and the innocent
at Haven Academy and beyond.
You faced down terrors
people can't even fathom.
That's not the behavior of students.
It's the behavior...
of huntsmen and huntresses.
- Wait, what is this?
- You are being granted your
huntsmen licenses, today.
- [Ironwood] I know this is
coming a little ahead of schedule,
but Brothers know you deserve it.
I only regret that I couldn't do something
a little more ceremonious
for the occasion.
- I -- we... we're honored, General Ironwood.
But you really don't have to do th--
- Please. With the threat
of Salem still out there
and tensions rising in our kingdom,
I certainly could use more
trustworthy fighters by my side.
I should be so lucky to have all of you.
It's okay. It's a big moment.
And what better way
than to celebrate here?
When this tower is ready
and communications
are back up and running,
we'll tell the world about Salem
and face down whatever comes
at us after that, together.
(sighs) That's just about
all the pomp I have in me.
If you'll excuse me, I have to get back
to running this operation.
Um...
Well then, enjoy the cake.
- Your speech outros are improving, sir.
- After everything we've been through,
I almost forgot this is what I wanted
in the first place.
- When Beacon fell,
I didn't even think this
would even be possible.
It almost feels trivial now.
- [Qrow] Jeez, guys, lighten up a little.
Enjoy yourselves for a change.
You've earned it.
- [Nora] Finally! Someone said it.
Let's kill some cake, huh?
Because I can eat two slices
before Ren even eats one.
Who says I can't?
Who says it, huh?
- Nora, nobody is arguing
with you about this.
- Ooooh! (giggles)
- Chomp.
- [Qrow] Big day for you, huh, kiddo?
- It's... definitely a lot to take in.
- Which part? The finally
getting to Atlas part,
getting your license part,
or the not quite disclosing
everything to Ironwood part?
Or... all of the above?
- (soft laugh) All of the above.
I'm trying to do what I think is best
but I really can't tell if
what's best is what's right.
Or if I'm not different from Oz.
- Ruby, Oz only trusted
himself with the whole truth.
You're trusting others,
but you're making sure they
prove themselves first.
I think that's a pretty big difference.
- I hope so.
This says I'm a huntress now.
But I don't feel like I know much
more than I did at Beacon.
That feeling never goes away.
Your mom, Summer, would be proud of you.
- Her last mission...
was that another Oz secret?
- Hm. There were a lot
of those back in our day.
But this one was a Summer secret.
When she didn't come back,
Ozpin seemed just as in the dark
as myself and your father.
Still, who knows what he may have
hidden from us over the years.
- What do you think she would have done
if she learned the truth about Salem?
That she can't be destroyed?
- Pressed on, I think. Like you.
She was always the best of us.
Bit of a brat though,
but, hey, I like brats.
- Hey Ruby! Come check this out.
- (gasps) Oh my gosh, is
that a mission board?
It's an app now?
Can we ride a Megoliath?
Stop an underground crime ring?
Do I get to go... undercover?
Maaaybeee!
- [Marrow] Hey, you guys smell that?
Smells like fresh meat.
- That's odd.
I don't smell meat.
- Neither do I.
- Ugh. You know what? Nevermind.
- [Elm] Let me get this straight.
You've only been official for an hour now
and you're already
looking for huntsmen work?
- To be fair, we've been
official for a whole 57 minutes.
- [Vine] I'd like to remind you all
that the real mission here is ensuring
the successful launch of
the communications tower.
- True, but we can also keep training
and improving by helping where we can.
- [Elm] (sigh) The enthusiasm of youths.
- Well, it's hard to argue with that.
Okay, let me show you how it works.
Ooh. Here's an important one.
Who wants to volunteer?
- Yes!
- Alright!
- We need someone to escort children to
pre-primary school down in Mantle.
There's not actually any danger,
but the parents fret
and that attracts Grimm.
Perfect, thanks.
- Juan... Jwan... Jim?
- Close enough, I guess.
Wow, my first huntsmen mission.
- Next, a massive Sabyr is
loose in the Mantle sewers.
We need two brave
warriors to flush it out.
- Wha--? But -- Why didn't I
get a choice for that one?
- Father, you, um... have a visitor.
- I told you I didn't
want to be disturbed.
Why did you let them in?
- [Whitley] I didn't. He let himself in.
- A spitting image of you,
this lad, Jacques.
Creepily so, I might add.
He's definitely inherited your... affect.
- Arthur. Whitley, leave us.
And shut the door.
I said shut the door!
I-- You're supposed
to be dead.
- That is what I wanted people to think.
You're right.
However, I've heard things
about you too, Jacques.
Namely, that you have
an Ironwood problem.
- That bastard is costing me more money
every day with this embargo.
I'd lay off every employee in Mantle
if I wasn't trying to get their
damn votes for this Council seat.
- What if I said you
could have your cake,
and eat it too?