Keep dreaming 'bout a better world
You keep wishing for some clarity
Always hoping that a lightning bolt
Is gonna save you from this gravity
Your holding out for some romantic life
Maybe you'll wake up in a world of charm
Oh, but whats here can set you free
You don't have to dream
Your life's a masterpiece
If you just believe
Then all you see is all you need
Right now your hopes are shattered
Just pointless ever after
But in time you'll find
Through love your power just shines
When you don't know where to turn to
And you're sure all hope is gone
When the day you waited for won't come
And dark won't yield to dawn
Trust love
And open up your eyes
The truth is there but sometimes in disguise
The way's uncertain but we're together
Moving toward the light
When we trust in love
And open up our eyes
- [Clover] All right, gather round.
Our mission today is to
secure the launch site
for the Amity Communications Tower.
The designated area is
an abandoned Dust mine.
Since its closure, the
Grimm have moved in.
The good news is all that untouched Dust
is still down there, too.
Science team says they'll need it
for the first phase of their launch.
- [Pietro] Apologies for the mess
and for holding onto
your weapons for so long.
The upgrades you requested were, uh,
well, they were more than
I anticipated (laughs).
- [Clover] Atlas military huntsmen
are already hard at work
clearing out the surrounding tundra.
But recon has identified a powerful Geist
that's managed to evade
destruction and take several lives.
After we increased our numbers,
the Geist were smart enough to
retreat into the mine itself,
meaning it's old, and extremely dangerous.
This is our target.
- [Pietro] Your new weapons and armor
should be as requested,
but I also took the liberty
of reviewing your combat footage
from the Vytal Festival Tournament.
There's some additional
enhancements I'd like to suggest.
Oh, but for now, these
should serve you well enough.
- The mine was a labyrinth back in the day.
There's all sorts of tunnels and chambers
the Geist can move between,
so if we're gonna kill this thing,
we'll have to split up and corner it.
General Ironwood says you've
seen your fair share of combat.
I trust that man with
my life, so tomorrow,
I'll be trusting you all, too.
- Hey, Ruby?
- [Clover] Let's make it happen, people.
- [Weiss] Hm.
(Yang laughs)
- Hmm!
I looked in the mirror
- Oh! (laughs)
And I’ve gotta say
It’s been a long, long time
Since I felt this way
Right now, I’m just a bit surprised
Because I feel just fine
And I might just touch the sky
I might just touch the sky
- This is my favorite part.
- (laughs) Perhaps you kids
won't get yourselves killed after all.
- Hmph!
(Jaune groans)
- She meant that as a compliment.
(device chirps)
- This is Alpha squad.
LZ's clear, proceeding on foot.
You've all got fancy new scrolls,
so don't forget to use 'em.
Keep your eyes and ears open.
I want an update if you
encounter the target.
Alpha out.
- Huh?
- Uh, sorry, just not
used to the new hair yet.
- Is it bad?
- [Yang] No, no, it's good, great even!
- Man, I did not sign
up to be a babysitter.
- Yeah, well, the rest of
us babysit you all the time.
- Hmph!
- Hmm.
- Oh, it's freezing out here!
- Without heating or projected Aura,
the cold of Solitas can kill
you in a matter of hours.
- I suddenly don't feel as bad
about leaving Oscar behind.
- (sighs) Can we talk about that again?
- What about it?
- We're really not gonna tell
Ironwood what happened to Oz?
What we learned about Jinn, about Salem?
- We are, we will,
but you saw how things looked
when we flew into Atlas.
- The General's heart seems
to be in the right place,
but that doesn't mean
we should trust him yet.
- We need to play along for a while
before we make any major decisions.
- Okay, how did Oscar feel about that?
- [Ruby] Er, probably shouldn't
keep running around
with an ancient relic
on a keychain, you know?
- But --
- I know you'll
keep it safe in Atlas.
- Ruby, hiding things from Ironwood,
doesn't that feel like
what Ozpin did to us?
- Gotta say, I'm still
not really used to working
with other huntsmen in the field.
- But you were on a team
before, weren't you?
- (sighs) Long time ago.
I just found working alone
tends to be for the best.
- Well, I think that's a shame.
Oh!
(Clover grunts)
- [Qrow] Hmph.
- Alpha here, gimme an update.
- The connecting ice tunnels seem clear.
We should be approaching the
actual mine any minute now.
- This is so exciting!
It feels like we're an
actual huntsmen team!
I, um, like what you did
with your outfit, Ren.
- We should probably stay
focused on the mission.
- Oh, okay.
- I like your outfit, too.
- Hmph.
- [Harriet] Bravo checking in.
Hit a bit of a snag.
There's been a cave-in
in the main entrance.
Not sure if it's recent
or was caused by the original accident.
Either way, we'll have to
do a little problem solving.
- [Clover] Understood, let us
know if you need anything.
- You okay?
- I just realized where we are.
This mine was closed after an explosion.
- I remember this disaster,
or rather, I remember how
furious it made my father.
(sighs) I wish I could
take back the years of pain
my family has caused the Faunus,
and all of my complacency in it.
- This society is set up for
Faunus to be at the bottom,
and humans are willing participants.
They benefit from doing
nothing to help us.
But there are still those
who actively abuse us.
Anyway, I didn't come
over here looking to solve
systemic societal issues.
Harriet found a gap in the
rubble we think one of you
could fit through, ideally
someone with a knack
for seeing in the dark?
- Oh, of course.
- Mm.
- [Marrow] All right,
Blake, take a look around.
Is there any Dust in the immediate area?
- Mine carts... debris...
no Dust, though.
- [Marrow] Great, then it should be safe
to blast our way through.
- Okay, heading back.
(creature whooshing)
- Damn it, Blake, stand back. (shouts)
- Don't let it get away!
Huh?
Ah!
That's disgusting.
- Hmm.
- Ha!
(creature shrieking)
Yah!
Stay.
- This is Bravo, we found the target,
but it fled deeper into the
mine. Engaging Centinels.
- Let's pick up the pace!
- Contact!
- Yah!
- Whoa, uh!
- A very... head-first approach.
- Yeah, well, that's
just kind of our style.
- One left!
- I got it.
Whoa, your Semblance makes
you super fast, just like me!
- Very cool, though based
on your reaction time,
I'd say I'm a little faster.
- [Clover] This is Alpha,
we've engaged the target.
All squads head towards our position.
- (Clover grunts)
- Wait, stop!
- Darn it, target escaped,
last seen headed east.
Thanks for the call-out.
That could have been bad.
- (sighs) I wouldn't thank me.
My Semblance brings misfortune.
Sometimes I can't keep it under control.
- [Clover] That so?
Well, hey, don't beat
yourself up about it.
My Semblance is good fortune.
Lucky you, huh?
Charlie, Bravo, you should
be able to cut off the target
at the heart of the mine.
Qrow and I won't be far behind.
- Guys!
- [Vine] Everyone use caution.
- This room is highly
active with Dust energy.
Triggering it could ruin the launch site.
- [Marrow] And vaporize us.
How is that always second with you?
- I thought the target was
supposed to be in here.
- It added Dust to its body?
How are we supposed to --
- Elm!
- (grunts) Vine!
- (grunts) Marrow!
- Ha!
(weapon whooshing)
Huh?
(grunts) Harriet!
- Ah!
- Crap!
- (laughs) What would
you guys do without me?
Harriet!
- Ooh.
- Thought you said
your Semblance was like mine.
- It is?
- I've seen other speed Semblances before,
but that was different.
I think there's more
going on than you think.
- Wait until she sees what
she can do with her eyes.
- Lucky catch, huh?
- Hmm, no, I'd chalk
that one up to talent.
Atlas Control, this is
Clover. Mission accomplished.
- Yeah, thanks for the lift!
Huh?
(light buzzes)
Whoa! Who are you?
- [Tyrian] Me? Oh, well,
I'm... someone just like you.
Someone who wants
to mix things up around here (laughs).
- Ah, ah! (screams)