Keep dreaming 'bout a better world
You keep wishing for some clarity
Always hoping that a lightning bolt
Is gonna save you from this gravity
Your holding out for some romantic life
Maybe you'll wake up in a world of charm
Oh, but whats here can set you free
You don't have to dream
Your life's a masterpiece
If you just believe
Then all you see is all you need
Right now your hopes are shattered
Just pointless ever after
But in time you'll find
Through love your power just shines
When you don't know where to turn to
And you're sure all hope is gone
When the day you waited for won't come
And dark won't yield to dawn
Trust love
And open up your eyes
The truth is there but sometimes in disguise
The way's uncertain but we're together
Moving toward the light
When we trust in love
And open up our eyes
- [Ruby] Ironwood's declaring martial law and
abandoning Mantle!
Salem is coming and he's
going to use the Staff
to move Atlas.
If we don't stop him
Mantle's going to be--
- Declaring
martial law?
We cannot let him do this.
- Ms. Hill, I'm sure the General
understands the enormity of his--
- Clover...
- Qrow,
you should know
that I've been asked to bring you in.
A free ride and a show!
- There's also an alert
out for Team RWBY's arrest.
- What?
Has James lost his mind?
- He's trying to stop anybody who might
get in the way of this inhumane plan.
Looks like he underestimated me.
Again.
- Only Qrow is under arrest.
After everything we've
been through tonight
please don't make me arrest you too.
- Cut it out! Both of you.
We're almost back to Atlas.
Let's talk to James personally and--
- It's taking a very long time
for this show to get to the good part.
- Shut up!
- He's right.
Let's get this over with.
- Robyn!
(sigh) Fine.
- I wish it hadn't come to this.
- It doesn't have to!
- You can hug it out once
we've taken him down!
- What are you doing?
- The will of our goddess!
- Weiss.
What did you do?
- The General is leaving Mantle to perish?
- (sigh) He's saving Remnant.
We can't let the Relics fall to Salem.
- But all those people we just protected,
they won't survive.
- We don't have time to--
- That doesn't bother you?
What about your sister? Our friends?
- My personal feelings don't matter.
We have orders. I'm to retrieve
the power of the Winter
Maiden so we can access
the Relic. You're here
to ensure my safety.
Now come on.
We've already lost enough time.
- It should matter.
- Penny.
The General is making hard choices so
we don't have to.
For the good of all, not just a few.
- [Penny] I do not see what is good
about any of this.
- On that we can agree.
- [Weiss] Please, think
about what you're doing.
- [Harriet] You heard the General.
Until this is sorted
out, you're under arrest.
- Really?
- Please. Don't make this difficult.
- Don't make us have to
get out of here by force.
- Whoa, whoa, whoa.
We're not actually going to slug this out,
are we?
- We're not doing anything.
They decide what happens next.
You think you're going
to stop us. (scoffs)
We're the best huntsmen in Atlas.
- You were.
Then you trained us.
- Come on Harriet!
We're playing right into Salem's hands!
You know we need to be working together.
- Oh don't give me that crap!
I had you kids pegged
right from the start.
- Huh?
- If you come peacefully,
we won't hurt you.
- Speak for yourself!
They betrayed us!
- You're betraying the people
you've sworn to protect!
- It's not worth it Blake.
They're just following orders now.
- I know you Schnee's are used to getting
what you want.
But it's time to let this one go!
- [Weiss] This is my home.
- And I'm not giving
it up without a fight.
- [Clover] Robyn needs help.
Surrender and we can take her to Atlas,
get her patched up.
- Never pegged you for
the manipulative type.
But I've learned a lot of things tonight.
- [Clover] I enjoyed working
with you, you know.
Even with that endless cynicism of yours.
- [Qrow] I'm usually proven right.
- We don't have to fight, friend.
- (scoffs) You don't know my friends.
That's how it always goes.
- [Tyrian] Oh don't stop on my account.
- (growls) Wasn't planning on it.
- [Qrow] Me and you have a score to settle.
- Oh I agree.
So what's say we put
the kid to bed and then
finish it.
- Marrow!
Cut the crap will you!
- I'm trying to arrest
her, not kill her, Hare.
You're being excessive!
- It's not excessive if it's necessary.
- [Elm] Time to wrap this up, Vine.
They've had their chance. Don't be soft.
- Are you telling me?
Or yourself?
Never really had a problem with you
All along I thought our friendship was true
Put my trust in you right from the start
I never dreamed
That you would be
My enemy
The knife to take my heart
You screwed me in the perfect way
- Stay!
A friend betrayed
Just another mourner
Content to follow orders
Stay!
Leave behind your conscience
Abandon those who need you most
Convince yourself you're noble
But we both know it's not so
But if you cross my battle line
You'll find you'll be sorry that you tried
If it's war that you want then you got it
If it's pain well I brought what you need
If it's true what you say you're the best
Then let's play
You won't believe it
Until you see it
When I kick your ass and look you in the eye
And with a smile and a cheerful heart
I'll turn to you and wave
Goodbye
- [Ruby] We have to stop Ironwood.
If he can't access the
Relic, he can't move Atlas.
- We just have to get to the Winter Maiden.
- Blake and I will look for the others.
- But our scrolls don't--
- Oh!
- This is the part where
they ask us to help.
- Oscar must be around here.
Oscar!
Oscar?
Oscar! You're here!
- [Oscar] No!
This crazy girl showed up and attacked me.
But she looked like someone else.
- [Nora] Neopolitan.
- You know her?
- We haven't exactly heard good things.
- [Winter] I hope it will be painless for her.
- [Penny] You said your
personal feelings do not matter.
- They won't change my actions.
What I'm committed to.
The power of the Winter Maiden
and the Relic must be kept
from our enemies.
Even if it means she dies.
But yes Penny,
We must still acknowledge
our personal feelings.
Wrestle with them.
It ensures us that
we're on the right path.
It's what makes us human.
- I think...
I think I understand.
- [Winter] What was that?
- [Cinder] Hmm.
Both of Ironwood's puppets.
Lucky me.
- Cinder.
- You were responsible for Beacon.
For what happened to me.
- It was unfortunately temporary.
Now step aside or there won't
be anything left to salvage
this time.
What do you think of that?
- [Penny] I think...
It gives me personal feelings.
- (heavy panting) Why couldn't
you just do the right thing
instead of the thing you were told?
- Sometimes the right decision
is the hardest to make.
- I trust James with my life!
I wanted to trust you.
- Doesn't look like your
friend's going to make it.
- I'll kill you!
- Oh you mean
like you just killed Clover?
- [Tyrian] Ah, here they come.
Right on time.
- Looks like our score will have to wait.
You know my track record with
the authorities! (laughing)
- [Clover] Someone had to take the fall.
- James will take the fall.
I'll make sure of it.
- [Clover] (chuckles) Good luck.
- (screams)