Keep dreaming 'bout a better world
You keep wishing for some clarity
Always hoping that a lightning bolt
Is gonna save you from this gravity
Your holding out for some romantic life
Maybe you'll wake up in a world of charm
Oh, but whats here can set you free
You don't have to dream
Your life's a masterpiece
If you just believe
Then all you see is all you need
Right now your hopes are shattered
Just pointless ever after
But in time you'll find
Through love your power just shines
When you don't know where to turn to
And you're sure all hope is gone
When the day you waited for won't come
And dark won't yield to dawn
Trust love
And open up your eyes
The truth is there but sometimes in disguise
The way's uncertain but we're together
Moving toward the light
When we trust in love
And open up our eyes
- [Ruby] Where do you
think they're taking us?
- I'm gonna go with jail.
- I still can't believe that fishing
pole guy took us out like it was nothing!
- Welcome to Atlas.
Those were Ironwood's Ace Operatives.
- Hmm?
You guys had a run-in with the Ace-Ops?
Ironwood must really have
a bone to pick with you.
- [Weiss] They're not that big of a deal.
- Not that big of a deal?
The Ace-Ops are the
elite-of-elite military huntsmen.
And Ironwood's personal attack dogs.
- So they got you too, huh?
- Pfft!
I wouldn't let myself get caught by them!
I'm here because I've been speaking out
against Atlas' exploitation of Mantle.
And General Ironwood is
trying to silence me!
- [Guard-Driver] You
threw a brick at her ship!
- It's worth it if it gets
people talking about our cause!
- Our cause?
- Yes, the fight for better
conditions in Mantle!
Lead by the charismatic, talented,
lovely, Robyn Hill and
her Happy Huntresses!
They were all top Atlas Academy
graduates, who could've
signed up for the military.
But Robyn and the Huntresses
chose to stay in Mantle.
She's gunning for a seat
on the kingdom's council,
and when she gets it,
she's gonna put an end
to Ironwood's tyranny.
- [Oscar] Happy Huntresses?
- Is that their real name?
- Don't you think tyranny's
a little dramatic?
- Easy to say for a Schnee heiress
living comfortably up in Atlas.
- Not anymore.
- Whoa, it's gorgeous up here!
- Don't let that fool you.
- This isn't the police station.
It's Atlas Academy.
- I guess we will be seeing the General.
For better or worse.
- [Ren] So what do we do?
- [Ruby] I don't know yet.
But we should be careful with what we say.
- We'll follow your lead, Ruby.
- [Ironwood] I swear if
I have to sit through
one more council meeting like that.
- Yay, you're here!
- Winter.
- Anyone wanna give us a hand with these?
- You have 10 seconds to
take those off, before
I start hurting you.
- [Both Guards] Huh?
- Sorry!
- Please let us help you!
- [Guard] Forgive us!
- Please, come in.
It is so good to see all of you.
- Our reception didn't really convey that.
- I sincerely regret how
you were treated by my team.
When a rouge airship
entered our airspace,
it raised some red flags.
We assumed the ship was stolen.
- Stolen?
Okay yeah, it was stolen.
- You stole an Atlas airship?
What were you thinking?
You might've been shot down!
How unbelievably irresponsi--
- I'm sorry I worried you.
But we did what we had to do.
- I...
I suppose I understand.
But I cannot believe that you
allowed this to happen, Qrow!
- You try stoppin' these kids
when they have their mind
set on something.
Speaking of which.
We have some important information
for you that's... confidential.
- Oh, is it about the Relics?
- Or perhaps the Winter Maiden?
- You told them?!
- Hmm.
Did you really think
you were the only one who got to
work on a new plan after Beacon?
With Ozpin gone I needed my own
team of people I could trust.
So yes, I told them.
The Ace-Ops too.
Which is why I'm so glad
you're here with this.
Until now, I believed it was impossible
to truly turn the tide against Salem.
Oz has pushed her back.
Has kept victory out of her claws
but she will keep returning.
Stronger and stronger.
Unless we destroy her.
- But, what about the Atlas Relic?
- You mean the Staff of Creation?
- It's safe inside the Vault!
- [Qrow] And the Winter Maiden?
- She is secure and in stable condition.
- Stable condition, what does tha--
- She's uh, not exactly a spring chicken.
- I know how this all looks.
Recalling my military?
The embargo?
I probably don't seem the
most trustworthy right now.
- Then why continue it?
- The people of Mantle are hurting!
- I needed to ensure
Salem couldn't infiltrate Atlas.
And I wanted my military here.
Protecting my people.
- But it's not protecting them!
It's making everyone hate you.
- It's a price I'm willing to pay.
Just as you all have been
entrusted with the knowledge of
Salem's existence,
I need you all to trust me.
I have a plan.
Ozpin believed the best way to fight Salem
was to do so in secret.
Whether that was the right choice or not
isn't for me to say.
But we find ourselves in
the position of needing,
well, a new approach.
- And what do you suggest?
- That's Amity Colosseum.
- Where the Vytal Festival is held?
- Indeed. When Beacon fell
and everyone on Remnant lost
contact with one another,
I knew our current system was outdated.
Amity was built to bring
the nations together.
And it will serve that purpose once again.
- [Penny] Isn't it great?
We're not going to just
replace Beacon Tower.
Building a new tower on top of
Amity Colosseum will re-establish
global communications!
- By launching the tower
high into the atmosphere,
our scientists believe
we can create a sort-of
satellite -- out of reach of the Grimm,
and capable of maintaining global
communications even if we
were to lose another tower.
- That is great.
- James, you don't need the
entire military for this.
- I will for the next part.
Where I finally tell
the people about Salem.
- Huh, so that's why you
withdrew your troops,
to handle the panic that
will break out in Atlas.
- Yes, panic is inevitable.
And panic brings Grimm.
But I believe we are ready.
Once Atlas has come to
grips with the fight ahead,
I'll use Amity Tower to spread the message
to all of Remnant.
- But everything will fall apart!
Grimm will be everywhere!
- You're right, but Atlas is
willing and prepared to assist.
- Trying to hide the truth from the world
will eventually kill us all.
- Oz spent his whole life, many
lives, keeping this secret.
- I know. But since
Beacon, things have changed.
Without him here to guide us,
all I can do is use my best judgment.
What is it?
- Actually, Oz isn't completely gone.
- Uh, Oscar here is... is the next Ozpin.
- Oz?
I am so glad you're here!
I didn't think you --
- Not quite. He's kind of,
um, gone at the moment.
- That's not normal.
How did he --
- We don't know!
We were in a train crash,
and ever since, well,
suddenly Oz wasn't there anymore.
- That's the worst news yet.
Did you learn anything from
him about the Relics before?
- He told us the lamp can
answer three questions.
But, all the questions
were used up already.
- Right, right.
Ozpin told us that too.
Once upon a time...
At least we have you Oscar.
You're safe here in Atlas.
Maybe together we can figure
out how to bring Ozpin back.
- Thank you, sir... I mean, uh, General...
Uh, Ironwood?
- You're giving it back to me?
- After what happened with the Ace-Ops,
I don't want you to think I'm
keeping anything from you.
Especially something as important as this.
For the time being, I think it's safest
with the people who brought it here.
- Um... thank you.
- We must work together if
we're to fight Salem and win.
Now, if you're all on board...
- Tell us how we can help.
- Good, because getting the
Amity Tower ready to launch
won't be easy.
But first,
I think we need to get
those weapons of yours,
up to our standards.
- Remember, this is Atlas.
While assisting the military,
we will provide you
with the best equipment
our scientists can devise.
- [Everyone] Yeah!
- So that was the second
time I got banned.
Then there was the third time when --
- All right, cut the chatter.
- I'd like to sincerely apologize
for the miscommunication down in Mantle,
we didn't intend to --
- I feel so bad, honestly!
If we had known who you were we'd be
laughing over a hot meal right now and--
- I understand, you were
just following orders!
- I mean you could have asked
us some questions first.
- Questions are for the weak, but we're
all on the same team now!
Not that I'm happy about it.
- We just wanted to say we're sorry.
And that we're looking forward
to working with you on our next mission.
You might be students, but you've
been fighting just as hard as we have.
If not, harder.
- Exactly why I'm
looking forward to seeing
what you kids can do.
- Ugh, not everything's
a competition Hare.
- C'mon, let me show you around campus.
- Qrow.
I meant it when I said it
was good to see you again.
- Uh, yeah, you too.
- So that way's the cafeteria,
and that way is the training rooms, oh,
and over there are the classrooms!
- This all looks great, Penny.
But where are we staying?
- Remember, you're in Atlas now!
As the most well-funded school on Remnant,
every teen at Atlas Academy gets
their own room!
And if that wasn't enough --
- So we're staying in the dorms?
- It'll be just like Beacon again!
- [Intercom] The kingdom
of Atlas will remain strong
and it will remain safe.
That is my promise.
- For the last time, a singular hideout
makes us more susceptible to discovery.
- [Tyrian] But what if we're seen?
What if we're recognized?
- We stay mobile.
- [Tyrian] We're walking
around a city with
a thousand eyes.
- While cyber security has
been stepped up in Atlas,
as usual, none of the code
was updated in Mantle.
- [Tyrian] That certainly sounds useful.
- It should be, I helped
write that code after all.
- Ah, well, I suppose we
all have our talents.