Keep dreaming 'bout a better world
You keep wishing for some clarity
Always hoping that a lightning bolt
Is gonna save you from this gravity
Your holding out for some romantic life
Maybe you'll wake up in a world of charm
Oh, but whats here can set you free
You don't have to dream
Your life's a masterpiece
If you just believe
Then all you see is all you need
Right now your hopes are shattered
Just pointless ever after
But in time you'll find
Through love your power just shines
When you don't know where to turn to
And you're sure all hope is gone
When the day you waited for won't come
And dark won't yield to dawn
Trust love
And open up your eyes
The truth is there but sometimes in disguise
The way's uncertain but we're together
Moving toward the light
When we trust in love
And open up our eyes
- Salutations!
Good morning, team RWBY!
- Ugh, Penny.
What time is it even?
- Time to be huntresses, of course!
- Yahoo!
- Sure, take it.
I been feeling sad
Luck's been bad
- Eyes up, huntsmen.
Living in a painful way
Time to get used to the
new normal in Atlas.
In disarray
- [Clover] Your top priority is Amity Tower.
It's like every day
That means protecting supply
runs from Grimm and bandits.
Was dark and gray
I'm just another washed-up cliche
- Heeyah!
- [Clover] And, protecting the site itself.
It sucked to be that way
- [Clover] Diverting all construction
resources to Amity Tower means
But i've got a plan i'm gonna
there are going to be gaps
Change direction
in Mantle's defenses against Grimm.
Gonna claim this life as mine
They'll need help on the perimeter.
And i'm just moving forward
- [Marrow] Hey, have you two ever thought about
I don't need perfection
branching out a little?
You always pair up, but I don't
know if your styles really-
Gonna try a re-design
Gonna branch out and see what's up
Might bloom like a buttercup
All starts with a new haircut
Yup!
But nothing's wrong today
Really, really good stuff!
Yeah, keep it up!
Everything is looking right ok
- Single file line, you know the drill.
- [Clover] But there's still
plenty to do in Mantle itself.
- Oh, another casserole,
that's too kind.
Taking everything in stride
The sun is shining in the sky
- [Clover] I think you'll find everyone
appreciates having a huntsman around.
The birds are smiling so am I
- It's totally the haircut.
I'm kicking ass in every way
- [Clover] You're of course
free to enjoy your time off
Think this change is here to stay
as you see fit.
Whatever helps you take the edge off.
It's feeling like a brand new day
- [Ironwood] You might not
hear Oz anymore, Oscar
but that doesn't mean we
can't try to jog him loose.
- What did you have in mind?
I been weak and lame
Filled with shame
- [Clover] The huntsmen around you
Trapped inside the place I made
can be an invaluable resource.
If you're willing to pay attention.
A house of pain
Well I finally saw what I became
- [Vine] Have you ever thought
about extending your aura?
Beaten at my own damn game
- [Clover] But make no
mistake, school's over.
In drunk loser hall of fame
You get to choose what type of huntsman,
But now I think there's time
or huntress you are.
For me to make corrections
Turn this ship around
- Again.
Gotta look inside
A little introspection
- [Ruby] Penny, Penny!
So yesterday Weiss and
I were like (grunts)
A better me just might come around
and they were like (screams)-
- So, what's it gonna be?
- [Neon] Never miss a
beat, never miss a beat.
Excuse me! (blows raspberry)
- [Neon] Come on, lightning bolt,
aren't you supposed to be fast?
- [Neon] Wow, your boyfriend's
actually holding his own!
Where's all that energy
when he's around you?
Wee!
- Huh?
- Wow!
That was amazing!
You guys have really improved
since the Vytal Tournament,
And that cute farm boy had
a few surprises for us, too.
- Well, you really had us on our toes.
Thought you had a there for a second, whew!
- Oh c'mon, it was way more than a second!
- You guys busy?
Wanna grab some lunch?
- Do we?
I could eat a sandwich the size of Kobalt!
- Ah, man.
We'd love to, but...
- Duty calls.
Maybe some other time?
- No worries!
The next time you're
free, just let us know.
- Yeah, next time.
- [Neon] Hey Ivori, if you're
gonna go get froyo,
can I have a bite?
- [Flynt] Aw, come on!
- There's still time
for sandwiches, right?
- [Ruby] Not that I'm bored,
but why can't we just use
an airship to take
these supplies to Amity?
- [Penny] The components
for Amity Tower's
construction are far too heavy.
All that weight would
require precious dust
we should be saving for the launch itself.
And the Grimm that will come after.
- [Ruby] It just makes for long,
very long, supply runs.
- At least the tundra is scenic.
- [Ruby] Totally.
- Ruby, I just wanted
to say how excited I am
to be working with you in
a professional capacity!
As friends!
- (laughs) Me too, Penny.
- Relationships are so
interesting, and varied!
- Speaking of friends...
Have you been able to make any new ones?
Since, you know...?
- Now that I'm the official
Protector of Mantle,
I don't really have a team anymore.
General Ironwood says I
don't have time for friends.
- Oh, uh, how do you feel about that?
- I feel like I wish I could do
both the things I need to do,
and the things I want to do.
Is that normal?
- That's about as normal
as it gets, Penny.
- [Qrow] Everything
going alright up there?
- Just fine, Uncle Qrow!
- I win again.
Maybe we should call it quits?
- Shut up and deal.
- Your niece sure is one of a kind, huh?
- They all are.
Been through a lot together.
- It's a good thing they had someone
to look up to and get them through it.
Not everyone is so lucky.
- I don't know about all that.
Thanks, by the way.
For looking out for 'em.
You and your team.
- What good is saving the world without
another generation waiting in the wings?
Hopefully they'll leave Remnant
better than we left it for them.
- Once upon a time,
I'd have drank to that.
- You shouldn't do that, you know.
- Don't worry, I gave that up.
- I meant deflect a compliment.
Those kids wouldn't be
where they are without you.
You've had more of an effect
on them than you realize.
- Uh, Uncle Qrow.
- What's going on?
Grimm?
- No. Worse.
You two with me, Penny, stay
put and keep an eye on our six.
We may need an element of surprise.
- Affirmative.
I will plan for six possible outcomes.
- Alright ladies, time
to show them our teeth.
- Robyn! Well, if it isn't
Mantle's hometown hero.
Is there a reason you're blocking
an official military transport?
- Clover, I'm so glad you're here.
Maybe you can help me
understand why this truck
that's supposed to be taking
construction materials
to fix Mantle's outer wall,
is on its way to the middle of nowhere?
Are you lost?
- [Clover] (laughs) It's pretty
easy to get turned around
out here in the tundra,
everything looks the same.
Thanks for checking up on us though.
We'll be on our way now.
- [Robyn] (sighs) I was hoping
you'd play it straight with me.
What's Ironwood doing with
Amity at the old SDC mine?
- Oh, that.
Just giving her an annual checkup.
- The next Vytal Festival
isn't anytime soon,
only automated drones and a
few select Atlas scientists
are allowed out here.
And Amity's getting invaluable
resources we need in Mantle
to protect against Grimm.
Seems like more than just a check-up.
- You've been scoping it out.
- We can't fix the wall without
the supplies on these trucks.
I think Mantle deserves to know
what they're being used for.
It doesn't have to be difficult.
Just tell me.
- I'm going to have to pass on that.
- How 'bout you, pipsqueak?
Five o' clock shadow?
Either of you want to tell me
why Mantle's being put at risk
for Ironwood's pet project?
- We're trying to help
Mantle, we need -
- That's enough, Robyn.
As a potential Councilwoman,
you should probably focus on the election
instead of harassing huntsmen.
Now, it's time to let us pass.
- I think you've misjudged the situation.
One way or another, these supplies
are going to get where they're
supposed to go: Mantle.
- Then I suggest you do that through
the proper legal channels
as a Councilwoman.
If you get elected.
- Now where's the fun in that?
- Robyn Hill.
I would like to politely ask
that you call off the huntresses
approaching the rear of the truck.
- (laughs) Alright.
Joanna, May.
The Protector of Mantle, huh?
- Let us through, please.
- Robyn.
Good luck at the election.
- [Qrow] That was a close one.
- [Clover] You're telling me.
- What now?
- I want to know why Amity Colosseum
is suddenly so important.
Whatever it takes.
- [Winter] Your technique still has
those maddening sloppy touches.
But you've learned how to
make them work for you.
You've made them your own.
- Wow, that was very
close to a compliment.
- I didn't intend it that way.
- We all make mistakes, I guess.
- (laughs) You've grown
up a bit, haven't you?
You're not the little girl
clinging to the family name anymore.
- Since Beacon, I haven't
really had a choice.
Father's view of the world
no longer matches with mine.
- Whatever the case, I am
glad to see you've moved on.
Distancing myself from the Schnee name
is the most beneficial
thing I've ever done.
We can move forward without him, together.
I know General Ironwood
would have a place for you.
- I would be grateful to him if he did,
but I'm not sure I could accept.
- Really?
- It's just...
Our kingdom isn't
supposed to be like this.
Fearful, and withdrawn.
We should be opening our
borders to help the world,
not closing them down.
- We will, though.
Once we've weathered the storm, we will.
I know the General hasn't
done everything perfectly,
but he's doing what he thinks is right.
- Everybody thinks what
they're doing is right,
but usually, they're just
looking out for themselves,
and their secrets.
- Ironwood isn't keeping secrets.
Not from me.
- Can you be sure?
- [Winter] Come with me.
There's something I want to show you.
- [Winter] Good afternoon,
feeling better today?
- Good morning.
- [Winter] Would you care for some tea?
- I do like hot tea on a cold day.
Reminds me of home.
Is it cold outside?
- [Winter] Yes, dear.
- [Weiss] That's the Winter Maiden.
- [Winter] She could pass any day now.
Until that happens,
I'm the only person
Fria's allowed to see.
- Ironwood's chosen you to be the next...
W- When she dies.
How long have you known?
- [Winter] Since Beacon fell.
- [Weiss] Doesn't it bother you?
He practically groomed
your whole military career.
- It did at first, when the
General first proposed it to me.
But the more I thought about it,
the more I saw it as a privilege,
a chance to do some real good for Atlas.
For Remnant.
- But your destiny was chosen for you,
without your input.
- [Winter] Perhaps, but I'm choosing it now.
I've made it my own.
And I take great pride in it.
That has nothing to do with
Father, or the General...
That belongs to me.
- I guess we've both had
to do a little bit of that.
Carving out our own way.
- I suppose we have.
- Speaking of the family name.
- What is he doing?
- [Jacques] If I'm elected Councilman,
I've made it no secret
I will be opposing
General Ironwood and his senseless embargo
that is crippling all of Atlas.
It is my belief that these
measures are not only reckless,
but criminal.
With no shipments allowed to
enter or leave the kingdom,
I know many are suffering.
And my family has been weathering
the same storm as many of you.
- [Jacques] Effective immediately,
I am forced to shut down
all nonessential SDC operations.
If elected to office, I will
make the changes necessary
to fix what Ironwood has broken.
I hope you ask yourself before the vote,
"Can you trust anyone
else to stop Ironwood?"
Will Robyn Hill be able
to get your jobs back?
- I think... I think Father
may have just provided
the spark that's going to
set this kingdom on fire.