Keep dreaming 'bout a better world
You keep wishing for some clarity
Always hoping that a lightning bolt
Is gonna save you from this gravity
Your holding out for some romantic life
Maybe you'll wake up in a world of charm
Oh, but whats here can set you free
You don't have to dream
Your life's a masterpiece
If you just believe
Then all you see is all you need
Right now your hopes are shattered
Just pointless ever after
But in time you'll find
Through love your power just shines
When you don't know where to turn to
And you're sure all hope is gone
When the day you waited for won't come
And dark won't yield to dawn
Trust love
And open up your eyes
The truth is there but sometimes in disguise
The way's uncertain but we're together
Moving toward the light
When we trust in love
And open up our eyes
- Nineteen.
- Ugh!
- Ah!
I would die
Without regret I'd offer up my life
- 14, 13.
With zero reservations
I would fly
Into the sun if that would keep our dream alive
Deliver you from harm
Shelter in my arms
The fear will surely fade
Know right now the plan I make
- Ten.
Will guide us home
We’ll survive this storm
I will fight
- Seven.
For you no matter how I am despised
Portrayed as cruel and heartless
I am might
I am power
I’m due process
I will smite
Our enemies destroy
- Hmph.
Mettle I'll deploy
Ah!
No chance that I won't take
My oath to you I won’t forsake
Hope’s not gone
Just hold on
Take my hand
I'm here to protect you
Nothing will stop me
Understand
There’s no sacrifice that I won’t make
I’ll risk it all to keep you safe
Trust me to be strong
I’ll be your hero
Just hold on
- [Watts] You never
appreciated my genius, James.
You just stood atop it
and called yourself a giant!
I gave you everything
you could have wanted!
- You chose that rat-imbecile over me!
I suppose in this instance,
my brains and your brawn
are evenly matched.
- You're smart, but you're not
the only one who can count.
- [Watts] Oh, I know.
- [Watts] That was a little
too close for my liking, James.
Rebuilding those rings is
going to be such a pain.
Now, if you'll excuse me.
[Watts] I wouldn't do that if I were you.
I mean, unless you're hoping
to add more metal to that body of yours.
All right now, where did
they put them?
What?!
- I will sacrifice whatever
it takes to stop her.
- Oh, I hope you do, James.
I hope you do.
- Tyrian Callows, you're under arrest.
- Hya!
- Where's that smile now?
- This is Clover.
Requesting prisoner transport.
- [Clover] We have Tyrian
Callows in custody.
- [Winter] All students
are to remain indoors
until further notice.
Faculty and upperclassmen can provide gu-
- [James] Schnee.
- Yes, sir?
- [James] Was anyone caught
trying to enter the school
grounds while I was away?
- ...No.
- [James] Are you sure?
- [Cinder] Still afraid, I see.
Now show me where you've been hiding her.
- Affirmative.
- [Weiss] I don't understand.
Why would the general call us
back without giving a reason?
- Especially with evacuations
still going on in Mantle.
- [Elm] You don't have to
understand orders, kids.
You just have to follow them.
- Civvy Transports won't
be stopping anytime soon.
If the general says he needs
us now, he needs us now.
- You all get to the general
and find out what's happening.
We'll bring Oscar and see you soon.
- General Ironwood.
- [James] We have made a critical error.
The Black Queen was the
symbol Salem showed us
before we lost everything.
Her way of telling us she was inside.
Then it was too late.
We stopped Watts.
We stopped Callows, but someone was here.
They put this in my
office to tell me that --
what if Mantle was just a distraction?
What if it was just to draw us
away from the academy to, to --
- Sir.
It's going to be okay.
We've got Mantle on
our side now, and --
- How do we know that
wasn't part of their plan?
How do we know they didn't want us
to bring people into
Atlas by the thousands?
- In trying to save everyone,
we left ourselves most vulnerable.
- Salem has been one step
ahead of us this entire time!
- It's... glass.
Black glass.
This was Cinder.
- She's alive?
And she's here?!
- If Cinder's here, then, for all we know,
Hazel's here, too!
- Sir, this isn't over yet.
We're with you.
- Are you with me?
- Sir?
- How did Robyn know
about the Global Communications Project?
- We told her.
The night of the ambush.
- You did what?!
- [Yang] We were trying to help.
- [Marrow] By going behind our backs?
- Does that mean you let her escape?
- Robyn is on our side!
She always has been.
- [James] We didn't know that for sure.
- None of this matters right now!
- Loyalty always matters!
Gah!
- [Salem] General Ironwood.
The brave Huntsmen and
Huntresses bested Arthur Watts.
Congratulations.
- We stopped Tyrian, too.
And we'll stop Cinder and anyone
else you try to send here.
- Dear girl, their goal was never victory.
It was merely to set the stage.
- For what?
- For me.
Time isn't on your side, James.
It's always been on mine.
The people of Atlas have suffered enough.
Surrender the staff and the lamp to me,
and they needn't suffer any further.
- That's... not going to happen.
- Simply accept the
futility of your situation...
And this can all be over.
- [Ruby] We've seen
what you're capable of.
The lamp showed us.
It showed us everything.
We've seen that you can't be killed.
But we've also seen you fail.
We don't have to kill you to stop you.
And we will stop you.
- Your mother said those words to me.
- My... mother?
- [Salem] She was wrong, too.
- Ah!
- [Marrow] That's Salem?
That's who we're up against?
- And she's apparently on her way.
- But we'd be alerted if any forces
had approached the kingdom.
We have long-range proximity alarms
all along the coast, and --
- They're offline.
With all of the chaos, we didn't notice.
- Watts must have shut them down!
- [James] Or they've
already been destroyed.
- What?
All of them?
- [Blake] You said in your
speech that Amity Tower
was ready to launch.
Was that true?
- [Yang] No.
You just said that to lure out Watts.
- General Ironwood?
- I sent your sister to claim
the power of the Winter Maiden.
- What?
- When I realized we'd been compromised,
I knew we couldn't wait any longer.
The staff and the lamp
have to be locked away.
- I thought... you said
we could keep it.
- Well, that was before you
lied to me about the lamp.
Before you lied to us about Robyn,
before Salem was right on our doorstep.
Before Mantle was nearly destroyed,
and myself and my army
were left exhausted!
The timeline has changed.
And so we must change accordingly.
- What are our orders, sir?
- We are going to take
our plan for Amity Tower,
and apply it to the city of Atlas.
- What?!
- It was Oz's plan in a former life.
But he didn't take it far enough.
If we harness the power of the staff,
and raise ourselves high
into the atmosphere,
the city's artificial climate will keep
citizens and food supplies unharmed.
Always out of reach of whatever Salem
may try to send our way.
- But we're nowhere near
finished evacuating everyone!
You'd be leaving Mantle to die.
- Yes... I would.
We can't allow Salem
to capture the Relics.
This is our best chance
at getting the staff,
the lamp and the maiden as
far away from her as possible.
- But we have an opportunity
to reunite the world.
If we launch the tower, we
can all work together again.
We could even call for help.
If we can hold out long enough --
- Sometimes, doing the right thing
means making tough decisions.
- You're right.
And I think the right thing to do
would be to stand our ground.
- Me too.
- We ran ourselves ragged
trying to save Mantle tonight.
We try that again against
an even larger force --
- But you're Huntsmen and Huntresses!
You can't just back down from a fight!
- You can't focus on one single fight
while trying to win a war.
- What's the council going to say?
- [James] Nothing.
Once I declare Martial Law.
- No.
- What about Robyn?
- Who exactly are you loyal to?
- We're loyal to the people
counting on us to save them!
- We are saving who we can.
And you're standing in our way.
- [Jaune] It's Jaune!
We have got a serious problem!
- Ironwood's declaring Martial
Law and abandoning Mantle!
Salem is coming, and he's going
to use the staff to move Atlas.
If we don't stop him, then
Mantle's going to be des-
- What? No!
- I'm sorry it's come
to this, but until Atlas
and the Relics are safe,
you are all under arrest.
- We won't just let you take us.
- I know.
- Ruby, are you there?
Ruby!
- [Nora] Did you tell them?
- Oscar, where are you?