Keep dreaming 'bout a better world
You keep wishing for some clarity
Always hoping that a lightning bolt
Is gonna save you from this gravity
Your holding out for some romantic life
Maybe you'll wake up in a world of charm
Oh, but whats here can set you free
You don't have to dream
Your life's a masterpiece
If you just believe
Then all you see is all you need
Right now your hopes are shattered
Just pointless ever after
But in time you'll find
Through love your power just shines
When you don't know where to turn to
And you're sure all hope is gone
When the day you waited for won't come
And dark won't yield to dawn
Trust love
And open up your eyes
The truth is there but sometimes in disguise
The way's uncertain but we're together
Moving toward the light
When we trust in love
And open up our eyes
- [Ironwood on P.A.]
Citizens of Mantle:
Following the most recent Grimm attack,
a temporary prohibition of
assembly is now in effect.
There are to be no public
gatherings of any kind.
Please conduct your business
and return to your homes before curfew.
This is for your own safety.
- [Patrol] Hey, stop right there!
Stop running! Wait!
- [Newscaster] Though military officials
have gone on record to say
the footage was doctored,
many citizens are still insisting that the
Protector of Mantle be deactivated.
- [Driver] Civilian,
you are obstructing an
Atlas military operation.
Please, step aside.
- [Soldier] Everything
all right over here?
Uh, hello?
- [Ironwood] This is
the worst case scenario.
More people are dead, Penny's been framed,
and somehow, Jacques Schnee
is sitting on the council.
- That's the second shipment
for Amity that was hit today.
It seems election night was the last push
Robyn needed to go from hometown hero
to full-on vigilante.
- I'm afraid the problem
is more complicated than that.
- [Ironwood] It seems Robyn has emboldened
our suppliers in Mantle.
They're refusing to sell us provisions
until the city is adequately repaired.
With Robyn redistributing the
goods her team has stolen,
the Amity Project is completely stalled.
- [Ruby] But we're so close.
There has to be some way
we can finish the tower.
- There is: declaring martial law.
- [Nora] You're not actually
considering that, are you?
- [Ironwood] What's more important?
Establishing communications,
unite the world?
Or appeasing a few city blocks?
- [Nora] Don't make is sound trivial
when you know it isn't.
You keep talking about how we
just need a little more time,
but you're not the one having to struggle.
- [Ironwood] We have all
had to make sacrifices
for the greater good.
Mantle has had to bear a lot
of the burden, yes, but--
- They're bearing all of it!
The longer this waiting game goes on,
the harder each day gets
for people down there
and now you wanna send in more soldiers?
You can't force people to fall in line.
If you do that, you'll just be trading
all of these problems for the Grimm.
- Please, General Ironwood.
Squeezing Mantle this way...
That kind of division plays
right into Salem's hands.
That's why Tyrian is here framing you.
- [Clover] Right, the reason we called
you here in the first place.
You're sure this was the man you saw?
- [Winter] Tyrian Callows was accused
of murders all across Anima.
A homicidal maniac who escaped justice
when his prison transport
was attacked by Grimm.
After that, he was never seen again.
- Well, he works for Salem and he's here.
- If we ever had any
doubts Atlas was Salem's
next target, I think those
are officially out the window.
- [Ruby] But now we have a suspect.
We can tell the people.
- That a long-lost serial
killer is loose in Mantle
and the military has no idea where he is --
might make things worse
before they get better.
- [Nora] I am so sick of secrets!
If we just told everyone
about Amity, about Salem --
- We can't!
If we talk about Amity now,
we risk Salem's forces,
who we know are here,
working to sabotage it.
If we tell them about
Salem now, we risk falling
to the Grimm before we
can reunite Remnant.
We have to finish the tower.
I want Robyn Hill in custody.
We can offer her a deal if
she gets Mantle to cooperate.
- We'll figure it out.
- Anyone not assisting with Robyn
needs to focus on Tyrian.
I want to know who he's working with,
where he's hiding, what he's planning,
and how exactly that video of
Penny got all over my kingdom.
Do I make myself clear?
- [Everyone] Yes, sir.
- [Ren] Yes, sir.
- [Yang] Looks like
we're approaching 51st.
- [Clover] Thanks for the
assist on this, you two.
Now, we may all be split
between different trucks,
but we need to be ready to act as one
in case Robyn's team takes the bait.
If your truck is hit, pursue immediately.
Everyone else will move
in as fast as possible.
Going radio silent. Over.
- Do you...
Do you think we should've
told Ironwood about Salem,
before he put so much
on the line for Amity?
- Sounds like you do.
- I trust Ruby, but I
think he deserves to know
what he's stepping into.
We all did.
You don't agree.
- Look around.
The embargo, the military presence,
the restrictions on assembly.
He's a bit prone to overreacting.
- Yeah, hard to argue with that.
Still, he didn't have
a lot of good options.
- I'm not sure there are
many good options left
for any of us anymore.
Keeping secrets, taking lives?
It makes you wonder how
far we're gonna have to go
to keep doing the right thing.
- Blake.
We did what we had to do.
- I know.
But, next time, I wanna
make sure we don't have to,
and I can tell you, ambushing
a huntress who's just
trying to help isn't an option
I'm thrilled about choosing.
- Then, maybe we shouldn't.
- [Ruby] How is she doing?
- [Pietro] She's confused, scared.
We'll have her recorded
visual data shortly.
That should prove her innocence,
but the damage has already been done.
The things people are saying about her...
If Penny hadn't been
there, Robyn would be--
- I don't think Robyn was their target.
Salem's goal has always been to divide us.
I think Penny was exactly
where they wanted her,
just like at the Vytal Festival.
- And just like back then,
someone is using our own
technology against us.
This doctored footage of Penny
came from her work all around Mantle,
stolen straight from our
surveillance network.
- Ugh, hacking, technology...
Why can't people just do what they used to
and fight to the death?
A lot simpler, if you ask me.
- Well, if we're dealing with
the same enemy from Beacon,
hacking into Mantle's
system would be simple.
Fortunately, the rest of Atlas
is running on an upgraded network.
- [Weiss] And how would someone
get access to that network?
- Well, only a few people have clearance.
Ironwood, the council, our cybersecurity
and surveillance leads and
maybe a select few who oversee
critical systems like
sewage or the heating grid.
- The heating grid run in partnership
with the Schnee Dust Company.
- What are you thinking?
- I don't know yet, but
something isn't right.
- [Maria] Understatement of the century.
- And how are you doing?
- If Maria hadn't offered
to help me these past weeks,
I'd have likely collapsed by now.
Getting a communications
tower into the sky
seems impossible on its own,
but now, to think of what
people wanna do to my girl...
- Even if the worst does happen,
you can always reactivate her again,
so maybe try not to worry so much.
- There's a reason why Penny
is the only one of her kind.
When the General first challenged us
to find the next breakthrough
in defense technology,
most of my colleagues
pursued more obvious choices.
I was one of the few who believed
in looking inward for inspiration.
- You wanted a protector with a soul.
- I did. And when General
Ironwood saw her, he did too.
Much to my surprise, the Penny Project
was chosen over all the other proposals.
- Why would you be surprised?
You created an artificial aura.
- Well, not quite.
- You gave her part of yours?
- Yes, and each time I rebuild Penny,
it takes a little more.
If the people get their
wish and she's destroyed,
I won't be able to...
- [Ruby] We'll find whoever's responsible.
I promise.
- [Yang] Robyn--
- [Robyn] Scramble!
- [Blake] No, wait!
- [Robyn] Split up, and
regroup at the hideout.
- [Blake] Please stop, we just want to--
- If Ironwood wants me,
he'll have to send more
than a couple of kids.
- [Yang] He is.
Stopping the trucks alerted the Ace Ops.
We don't have long before they arrive,
so please listen to us.
You need to know the truth.
- You're stalling.
- Amity Colosseum, all these
supplies, they're for...
They're for a new communications tower.
- That doesn't make any sense.
- A new tower means the
kingdoms can finally--
- I know what the tower means, Fisticuffs.
One of you take my hand.
- What?
- You said time is short.
Either take it, or I'm gone.
Tell me again, what is Ironwood
building out in the tundra?
- A new communications tower.
He's trying to help everyone.
- You're telling the truth.
- Handy semblance.
- Why keep that a secret?
- Because he doesn't
know who he can trust.
Atlas isn't out to get anybody.
The people murdering civilians in Mantle
are just trying to make it look that way.
And if those same people
learn about Amity,
they'd do everything in
their power to destroy it.
- So, who are they?
Who's actually behind this?
- [Harriet] Yang, Blake,
where are you?
- We can't tell you that part yet.
- Ugh, bullsh--
- Look, we are trusting
you, so trust us when we say
that Amity Tower needs to
stay a secret until it's done.
We just need a little more time.
- [Soldiers] This way, come on, over here.
We saw them over this way.
- Run, we'll throw them off.
- I won't stop until I
know the whole truth.
- [Ironwood] It's right behind that door.
- [Oscar] The Staff of Creation.
- [Ironwood] I hoped
bringing you down here
might jog some memories.
After all, it was your
idea to use the staff
to lift Atlas off the ground.
- I thought gravity
dust kept Atlas afloat?
- [Ironwood] Eh, that's the public story.
But with the staff, we have a constant,
seemingly limitless energy source.
Oz once speculated it could
take us as high as we wanted.
To tell you the truth, that served as
the inspiration for the Amity Project.
Get a communication tower up in the sky,
higher than the Grimm can survive
so we never lose contact
with each other again.
- [Oscar] But, you're not
using the staff to raise Amity.
- The staff can only be used
for one purpose at a time.
We're going to have to do Amity
the old-fashioned way, dust and all.
- [Oscar] It feels strange,
knowing that part of me
helped come up with all this.
- [Ironwood] You'll get
used to it, I'm sure.
Eventually, you won't even
know who's who anymore.
- Right.
- We didn't always see eye to eye,
but I wish I could ask Ozpin
what he thought of all of this.
- Well, I can tell you what I think.
The path you're heading down
where you're the only one
with the answers, where you do the thing
you think is right no matter the cost,
it's not going to take you anywhere good.
- We have to stop Salem,
nothing matters more.
- Some things matter more, I think.
Keeping our humanity. It's what
makes us different from her.
- Sometimes I worry that's
her greatest advantage.
Without humanity, does
she still feel fear?
Does she ever hesitate?
When Salem hit Beacon,
even with all my ships,
all of my soldiers, I
was no match for her.
I've never felt so helpless,
the way she told me she was there.
- [Oscar] It's okay to be afraid.
You just can't let that fear control you.
- [Ironwood] I am not going
to end up like Lionheart.
Do you believe in me?
- I do believe in you,
but not only you.
I think the best thing
you could do is sit down
and talk with the people
you're most afraid to.
- Now you are starting to sound like him.
- [Ironwood] Winter, what is it?
- What's going on?
- It looks like you're getting your wish.
- My father's first act.
We've all been invited to
dinner where the General
will be defending his seat on the Council.