Keep dreaming 'bout a better world
You keep wishing for some clarity
Always hoping that a lightning bolt
Is gonna save you from this gravity
Your holding out for some romantic life
Maybe you'll wake up in a world of charm
Oh, but whats here can set you free
You don't have to dream
Your life's a masterpiece
If you just believe
Then all you see is all you need
Right now your hopes are shattered
Just pointless ever after
But in time you'll find
Through love your power just shines
When you don't know where to turn to
And you're sure all hope is gone
When the day you waited for won't come
And dark won't yield to dawn
Trust love
And open up your eyes
The truth is there but sometimes in disguise
The way's uncertain but we're together
Moving toward the light
When we trust in love
And open up our eyes
- [Woman] What's going on?
Is the heat off in Atlas too?
- [Man] They wouldn't just
turn the heat off...
...would they?
- General, since the day you
were appointed Headmaster,
there have been Atlesians
who are skeptical
of one man holding two Council seats.
- Yes, which is exactly why
we have checks and balances.
- We're supposed to, but lately
you've been running
roughshod all over them,
making unilateral decisions without us.
- Councilman, I never intended--
- What people intend and what they do
aren't always the same, General.
- What?
For how long?
My authorization?
Check it again!
- Councilman Schnee?
- Yes, I agree with everything,
everything that was just said.
No, uh, no further questions.
- I'm not quite done yet.
You're afraid of something,
General. Aren't you?
- I think that's pretty
obvious, Miss Hill.
I'm trying to prevent Atlas
from becoming another Beacon,
another Haven.
- Yet, you don't trust your
own Council to help you?
Operating in secret?
These are the actions of
somebody who's hiding something.
- I'm not hiding anything.
- Let's put it to the test then.
You're all aware of my Semblance.
Let's settle it here and
now, General Ironwood.
Here and now.
- [Weiss] Wait!
You've got the wrong man on trial.
I know who's been framing Ironwood,
who rigged the election.
And my father does, too.
He's been working with him.
- Is that Arthur Watts?
- That's impossible!
Dr. Watts died in the
Paladin Incident years ago.
- [Jacques] What is this?
- Play it.
- [Jacques] That bastard is
costing me more money every day
with this embargo.
I'd lay off every employee in Mantle
if I wasn't trying to get their damn votes
for this Council seat!
- [Watts] What if I said
you could have your cake
and eat it, too?
- [Jacques] What did you have in mind?
- [Watts] James Ironwood
never recognized my genius.
After everything I gave
him, he still disgraced me.
I simply wish to return the favor.
- [Jacques] What's in it for me?
- [Watts ] A seat on the council.
All I need is your login
credentials to the Atlas network.
You promise to make Ironwood's
life a waking nightmare,
and I will guarantee
you victory at the polls
by giving the voters down in Mantle
a little... 'digital push', if you will.
- [Jacques] I always knew you
were a good scientist, Arthur,
but I never knew you were
such a good salesman.
- [Ironwood] Enough.
- [Jacques] That, that is -- I can explain that.
That... isn't real.
- Jacques, take your seat.
- Weiss...
- Jacques Schnee, you're under arrest.
[Weiss] Can I do that?
- [Woman] Atlas killed the heat on purpose
- [Man] They'll do anything to control us.
- [Soldier] The situation here is
getting out of control.
Please advise.
- I knew you'd stoop low to
get what you wanted, Jacques.
But this?
- This is all a great leap, James.
- No, it's quite simple really --
now that I know Arthur Watts is alive.
Working with a madman like Tyrian Callows,
it would be easy for someone like him
to coordinate an unthinkably heinous act
like the one in that warehouse.
Watts designed Mantle's
entire security network.
He used that access to hack
the surveillance system
and frame someone else for the job.
All while stealing an election.
And once you became a Councilman,
your newly granted clearance
gave him a backdoor
into Atlas' secure network.
But you probably hadn't even
considered that, had you?
- The people that died that night,
their blood is on your hands.
- Jacques Schnee must be tried,
not only for treason, but
as an accessory to murder.
- These are outrageous accusations.
I only intended to win the election.
I had nothing to do--
- Only?!
- What else will he be able to do
with the access Jacques' given him?
- With enough time... whatever he wants.
- Wait... wait, what?
What do you mean the heat has gone off?
- You have to believe me,
I didn't know he was planning this.
- You are going to shut your mouth
and get the heating grid
up and running again.
- I... I've been informed
that we can't get into the system.
It's... it's been blocked off.
[Sleet] Without heat down there...
people are going to die.
- [Ruby] General Ironwood?
How bad is it?
- He's using Jacques' credentials.
We can follow that
activity on the network.
If he's found his way
into the Amity system...
No, the secret is safe. For now.
But if he learns about Amity,
she learns about Amity.
- Can you block his access?
- It's too late.
He's already starting to lock us out.
- Can we trace him somehow?
Find out where he's hiding?
- [Ironwood] He's going to be mobile.
We need his access point.
We need to get him out in the open.
- [Robyn] Okay, so let me get this straight.
Yep, still here everyone.
How do a disgraced scientist
and disappeared serial killer
find each other, General?
Why would they target you?
And why are you working so hard
to hide the Amity
Communications Tower from them?
- You know?
- [AK-200] Citizens, please disperse.
For your own safety, please disperse.
For your own safety, please --
- [Pilot] Atlas, Manta Team Delta --
beginning first run.
- I used to think you
were hiding something
to protect yourself.
But I can tell there's something
much bigger going on here.
Now I think it's to
protect something else.
Us... Atlas, maybe even all of Remnant.
And you're afraid of what might happen
if you tell the truth.
- General, the Grimm are all over Mantle.
The air fleet's doing everything they can,
but they can't easily
target Grimm in the city
without risking casualties.
- This -- this is what I
was afraid would happen.
- Sir, we need ground support now.
- What we need is to
start evacuating Mantle.
If it's completely overrun,
it's not going to be safe anywhere.
Use the fleet to get --
- If I move the fleet,
then Atlas is vulnerable.
I... I tried to keep the kingdom safe.
And now we're losing everything.
- General?
Earlier, you asked for my advice.
- I wanted Ozpin's advice.
- And his advice probably would've been
to keep your secrets.
When we first got here, you already knew
that wasn't the right course.
You had a new plan.
- It's time to give up on that plan.
It's all falling apart.
- The panic you were worried about?
It's already happening.
The secrets you're keeping?
They're about to be in the open anyway.
It's time.
Tell the truth.
- [Ruby] You're not alone.
We can do this together.
- Thank you.
Oscar, I think it's time
you get back to the academy.
- I think you're right.
- Miss Hill, Councilman
Sleet, Councilwoman Camilla,
there are some things
you need to know about.
Let's figure out how we
can help Mantle... together.
- I've called a transport.
- What about Watts and Tyrian?
- You leave them to me.
Right now, you're needed down below.
- Alright everybody,
it's time to do our jobs.
All of us.
- What she said.
Let's make it happen, huntsmen.
- [Ruby] Oscar?
- I--
- Oh, you first.
- Sorry.
I didn't mean to interrupt --
- You didn't, actually.
- I just wanted to say --
- I had the thought that maybe--
- [Both] We should tell Ironwood.
- I guess we're on the same page, huh?
- Guess so.
He's finally choosing the truth over fear.
We should do the same.
- I'll tell him.
I'm the one who chose to keep it from him
in the first place.
- [Marrow] Ruby!
Transport's leaving.
- I think you're needed elsewhere.
- You're sure?
- Yeah, I've got it.
- [Both] Good luck in there.
- Ugh, kids.
- All right, everyone.
I need to stress to our new
huntsmen and huntresses,
we are prioritizing citizen
safety over killing Grimm.
Got it?
- [Sleet] Is this really true?
- [Camilla] Ironwood wouldn't lie
about something like this.
- [Sleet] What do we do now?
- She... can't be killed.
Jinn told you this?
- She showed us when we
asked what Oz was hiding.
- Why?
Why would Oz keep this from us?
From the people who trusted him?
- He was worried you would lose hope.
We're sorry we kept it from you, too.
We didn't know who to trust.
I figured you should know
before you make any... sacrifices.
Sir?
What are you gonna do?
- I...
All we can do for the moment
is what we can to save Mantle.
That's what's in front of us.
- He'd be proud of you.
You're bringing the hope that
Atlas was meant to inspire.
A city in the sky is held
to a higher standard.
- You say that like you were there --
Our transports are here.
We should move.
Oscar.
No more surprises, all right?
I'm not sure I could take it.
- You and me both.
- [Marrow] Hang on!
- I can't shake it!
- I don't think we're staying airborne.
- It's time to go.
- You have your team assignments.
Let's go.
- Harriet, don't stay too long.
- Yeah, thanks for the tip.
- Try to keep up, kid.
- Show off!
- [Jacques] How dare you?
This is highly unnecessary.
I will not stand for this.
Don't touch me like that.
I'll be reporting this rough treatment.
- [Cinder] Huh.
You're back early.
Tell me you found what
we've been looking for.