Back to the fairytale, back to the show
Back to the wall and there's nowhere to go
Hopeless and desperate, all paths adverse
Things looking bleak, and they're bound to get worse
Helpless and doomed, and there's no way to win
Goals unachievable, faith running thin
Lost and forlorn, impossible odds
That's when you'll learn you've been messing with gods!
Send in your grimm, tear off my limb
Strike me with bolts of lightning
I won't die
The battle seems unwinnable, but all we need's a miracle
We're going up we'll never be denied!
Can't wish away the dismal days
Can't bring back what is gone
Won't waste more tears on yesteryears
Instead we'll carry on
We'll win, we're sure we will endure
And though our goal is far
We'll be the ones to touch the sun
The Triumph will be ours!
- I totally freaked out and without even
thinking about it.
- Oh, it looks so good.
Do you have any duck sauce,
any duck sauce over there?
Thank you.
- How do you lose your
map at a time like that?
- Believe me, I've asked myself
the same thing ever since.
- Hey, but you made up
for it, Mister Muscles.
You shoulda seen this guy
take a giant Grimm head on!
- I couldn't have done it
without Ruby wearing it down.
- Uh, me?
Did you see Ren during that fight?
He was out of control!
- I'm sorry, I may have
lost my temper momentarily.
- No, no.
Out of control as in awesome.
- Oh.
Thank you.
- [Ruby] You did not!
- [Weiss] Yeah, right in
the middle of the party.
- Please tell me you
let that lady have it.
- Of course not.
Even if I did really want to.
- No way, I don't believe it.
- It's not a replacement
for the real thing,
but I'll make sure to make good use of it.
- That's amazing.
- Incredible.
- And it's just as strong?
- Sure is.
- Wanna bet?
- Nora, please, now's not the time.
- Don't let her beat you!
- Come on,
You can do this
- You can do it.
Show 'em what Team JNPR's made of!
- C'mon, sis!
Aw, you can't lose to a girl
in a skirt.
- You've got this, Nora.
- You wear a skirt, Ruby.
- Don't give up, you can do it
- Weiss, you're not cheering loud enough.
- It definitely feels like the
original, I'll give you that.
- Yep.
But, it does have some new features.
- Oh yeah?
- Did she win?
- Yeah, we ate it all.
Oh, I think I'm gonna be sick.
- Easy there, Vomit Boy, I believe in you.
- Oh, we're doing nickname throwbacks now.
Wonderful.
- I mean, the Ice Queen seems to like it.
- I so did not miss you people.
- Oh my gosh, she really does like it.
What went and warmed your
heart while you were gone?
- Hey, you make it sound
like I used to be terrible.
- Nah, just a lot to deal with at once.
- It's been a long time.
We've all grown in our own ways.
- You really think so?
- Well, think back to when
we were all at Beacon,
would you say you ever did
anything foolish or embarrassing?
Or do you think you were perfect?
- Oh gosh.
- I may have been a little
too gung-ho from time to time.
- You?
I tried to 1v1 a Nevermore
on the second day of school.
- Yeah, well, don't even get me started.
- Well that embarrassment,
that desire to go back
and tell yourself not to be so stupid,
that just proves you're not
the same person you used to be.
You're smarter, or kinder, or stronger,
and you're not done growing yet.
None of us are.
- Yeah, turns out Ren gets real
deep when he feels like talking.
- Well, hold on, I thought I
was pretty great in school.
- Even at the dance when you spilled punch
all over yourself in front of--
- Yes, especially at the dance!
Thank you, Yang!
- [Qrow] How can six kids possibly make
so much noise eating dinner?
- So, the Maidens, Magic, Salem.
It's all true?
- Uh huh.
- Miss Xiao Long, is this more or less
what your mother told you?
- For the most part.
- You forgot something.
You forgot to tell everyone what you did
to Qrow and my mother.
- What is she talking about?
- Oh, great.
- That's not a secret I thought
she would give up so easily.
Your mother must trust you a great deal.
My ability to reincarnate, though a curse,
isn't without a few key benefits.
Much like the Maidens, I, too,
possess a certain magical power.
Using this power, I was able
to gift the Branwen twins
the ability to see more, to move freely,
and be unburdened by their natural bodies.
I, well, gave them the
ability to turn into birds.
Rather ridiculous sounding
out loud, isn't it?
- [Oscar Voiceover] Wait, what?
- Uncle?
- You turned them into birds?
- All right, now you're
just messing with us.
- What else is new?
- He's telling the truth.
We saw it.
Yang's mom changed right in front of us.
- Why would you do something like that?
I mean, what is wrong with you?
- Yang, that's enough.
We made a choice.
We wanted this.
- May I?
Granting this power to
them was no trivial task,
and I can assure you it
was not done frivolously.
I required assistance in gathering
information on Salem's
plans, as well as searching
for Maidens when their
hosts became unclear.
- Okay, so, have you
done this with others?
Like General Ironwood
or Professor Goodwitch?
- As helpful as that might be,
unfortunately it is not that simple.
My power is finite, and if
I'm being honest, dwindling.
The amount that I gifted
to Qrow and Raven was,
all things considered, rather minuscule.
You see, centuries ago, I
sacrificed a great deal of magic
to four young women, who I hoped
would use my gift for good.
They were the first Maidens.
Miss Xiao Long, it was never
my intention to lie to you.
To any of you.
There are just some matters that
I prefer to play close to the chest.
I believe that's how you phrased it?
- Yeah.
- Everyone has a choice.
The Branwens chose to accept their powers
and the responsibilities
that came with them.
And later, one of them
chose to abandon her duties
in favor of her own self-interest.
Now, all of you have a choice.
If anyone wishes to
leave, now is the time.
There's no shame or disgrace
in abstaining, only in retreat.
Very well, then.
- Yang?
- If Ruby sticks around, then I will too.
If there's one thing I know about her,
it's that she somehow always
knows the right thing to do.
But, if we're going to
help, if we're going
to keep risking our lives, no more lies.
No more half-truths.
- Understood.
- So what now?
I mean, what can we do?
- That is a difficult question.
One that I believe is
best answered tomorrow.
- What do you mean?
- The road ahead is undoubtedly filled
with hardships and peril.
However, it's been far too long since
you have all been together.
Please, take tonight, enjoy this moment.
- Oh.
Raven?
Qrow?
They're birds!
Cracked it.
- [Mercury] Hey, ugly.
- Is Raven Branwen home?
- Ya know, I've had a real bad week
so I think I'm gonna take it out on you--
- Doesn't look like he
wants to cooperate, boss.
- Then make him.
- I was hoping you'd say that.