Back to the fairytale, back to the show
Back to the wall and there's nowhere to go
Hopeless and desperate, all paths adverse
Things looking bleak, and they're bound to get worse
Helpless and doomed, and there's no way to win
Goals unachievable, faith running thin
Lost and forlorn, impossible odds
That's when you'll learn you've been messing with gods!
Send in your grimm, tear off my limb
Strike me with bolts of lightning
I won't die
The battle seems unwinnable, but all we need's a miracle
We're going up we'll never be denied!
Can't wish away the dismal days
Can't bring back what is gone
Won't waste more tears on yesteryears
Instead we'll carry on
We'll win, we're sure we will endure
And though our goal is far
We'll be the ones to touch the sun
The Triumph will be ours!
- Are you ready?
- Yes.
It won't be easy for the people to hear,
but the truth often isn't.
I know they'll do the right thing.
- You got this.
- Coming to us live
and now speaking to us.
- In the estate where
former White Fang leader.
- I've seen it and she's
always looked out for me.
- Thank you all for assembling here.
I wanted to take time to
address some of the rumors
that have been circulating
around our island.
I believe that it is important
for the people of this
territory to understand the truth.
No matter how you feel
about the human race,
I think we can all agree
that the event now known as
the Fall of Beacon was a tragedy.
A tragedy that will set both
man and Faunus-kind back.
While the main aggressor is still unknown,
we do have official
confirmation that Adam Taurus,
the leader of a powerful
splinter group working inside the
White Fang, was partially
responsible for these attacks.
His actions not only
tarnished the reputation of an
organization originally
created to bring peace
and equality to all,
but to our entire race.
With each day that this
man remains unpunished,
it becomes increasingly
difficult to condemn
those that look down upon us.
Recently, a spy from
the same splinter group
set their sights on this very home.
My own daughter, Blake,
and her friend did their
very best to apprehend this individual.
While they were unsuccessful
after being physically
assaulted and seriously injured,
they were successful in
obtaining the assailant's Scroll.
With this, we have been able
to ascertain that Adam Taurus
has plans to overthrow the
current leader of the White Fang,
Sienna Khan, and take
over the reins himself.
His radical plans do not stop
there, the documents on this
scroll proclaim his next target to
be Haven Academy and
its attached CCT Tower.
Their plan is to strike on
the last full moon before the
beginning of the Fall semester,
roughly two months from today.
I have sent my swiftest
messenger to the government of
Mistral, but I believe we
have a greater responsibility.
My relationship with the White Fang
has been an interesting one.
Years ago, I led the
organization to help try
and create a world where I,
and every Faunus who wished,
could walk alongside the human race.
And while I believe we made
great strides toward this goal,
it was made clear to me
that the people both in
and out of the White Fang
wanted faster results.
So I stepped down,
and Sienna Khan was
appointed as my successor.
It's true that I do not fully
condone many of her methods.
What I do condone is
what Sienna fights for:
the idea that the Faunus and humans are,
and should be, equal.
Adam Taurus does not seem
to have that goal in mind.
What he has done benefits
no one but himself.
I think it's time that the Faunus
showed the world that we are equals!
Time that we snuff out
this splinter group,
and restore the White
Fang to what it once was!
To do this, I think the answer is clear,
we must go to Haven and
protect it at all costs!
Before we proceed any further,
I'd like to invite my daughter
to come and share her story.
Not only as a former
member of the White Fang,
but also as a survivor
of the Fall of Beacon.
You can do this.
- [Ilia] Traitors!
- Ilia.
- Cowards.
After everything the
humans have done to us,
everything they've put us through,
you're asking us to help them?
- I know we haven't been treated fairly.
- Where was their help when the Dust
companies treated our people like slaves?
Where was their help when Kingdoms
hunted Faunus just for being who they are?
Where was my help when my parents
were killed in a Dust mine?
Where?
- Young lady, progress takes
patience and cooperation!
- The Belladonnas are
the worse kind of Faunus!
They want us to work with the same people
that are trying to hold us down!
If you truly, truly want
to help your people now
is the time to support
Adam, not the Belladonnas!
He will bring about the
future that you deserve.
And if you are unwilling to fight,
know that the White
Fang will do it for you!
- [Sun] Shut up!
- After her!
- [Nora] Did he age backwards?
- [Jaune] He's possessed!
- [Ren] Or reincarnated!
- [Ruby] Oh, isn't it weird?
- It is very weird, yes.
- Okay, okay.
Let's all just take a second and remember
that this is very
overwhelming for everyone.
- Thanks.
Ah, sorry!
It's just I've never really met
Huntsmen and Huntresses before.
- Well, uh, we've never met
a person with two souls!
So, first times all around.
- Not to break up the whole
getting-to-know-you game,
but we need to have a talk.
Mind showing us your
little parlor trick, kid?
- Yeah, okay.
Just so you know, I'll still be here.
- It is so very good to
see you again, students.
- Wait, what just happened?
- Professor Ozpin?
- Correct.
And though I may be the one speaking,
Oscar is still present mentally.
He's merely handed over
the control, so to speak.
- [Oscar Voiceover] Just don't make us
do anything embarrassing.
- I'm afraid this all
must be very perplexing.
- And alarming, and bizarre,
and just really kind of
hard to believe overall.
- It's good to see you children
still have your sense of humor.
I know you've all been through
tremendous hardship already.
I'm sorry.
- I mean, it's not your fault.
- It's all my fault.
I told you once that I made
more mistakes than any man,
woman, and child on this planet,
and I wasn't exaggerating.
I'm cursed.
For thousands of years, I've
walked the surface of Remnant,
living, dying, and reincarnating
in the body of a like-minded soul.
The Professor Ozpin you all
met was not my first form,
and clearly wasn't my last.
It's an extraordinarily strenuous
process on everyone involved.
- So who, what, are you?
- I am the combination of
countless men who've spent their
lives trying to protect
the people of Remnant.
With every rebirth, my soul
is eventually merged with
another and I am changed,
but my memories stay with me.
This curse was bestowed
upon me by the gods
because I failed to
stop Salem in the past.
But we must stop her now.
- And how do we do that?
- We start by ensuring the
safety of the Relic of Knowledge.
- Well, well, well, look who's awake.
- What's going on?
Where am I?
- You know, I never thought
I'd see a Schnee in this camp.
- Vernal?
- What do you want?
- Straight to the point.
I like it.
We don't normally deal
in trafficking people,
not really worth our time.
But, once we realized we
had a Schnee, that changed.
- You're going to ransom me
back to my father, is that it?
- It's a shame you're a Schnee.
You'd probably do quite well around here.
- [Weiss] I would never
sink to your level.
- Just keep quiet and cooperate
and you'll be back in your
mansion before you know it.
Don't make this complicated.
- What's going to make this
complicated is when my sister
finds out I didn't make it to Mistral.
You know my sister, don't you?
Winter Schnee?
Special Operative of the Atlas Military?
She's in Mistral now, and
when she hears I'm missing,
it won't take her long
to find me, and you.
What's so funny?
- Oh, I don't know if
it's more funny or sad,
but you're clearly out of the loop.
Your sister isn't in Mistral anymore.
No Atlas personnel are in Mistral anymore.
General Ironwood closed the
borders and recalled all of his
little troops and tin cans.
No one is coming to rescue you.
- This is perfect!
We were stuck at a dead end, but now,
we can just take little cute boy Ozpin
to Lionheart and have
him set things straight!
- Please don't call me that.
- We're not sure that's the best idea.
- But I thought the headmasters
all took their orders from you.
- That was the intention.
Four lieutenants I can trust,
especially during times of reincarnation.
But Qrow told me about
your meeting with Leonardo.
He isn't just behaving irrationally,
he's disobeying specific
instructions I had left him.
Something's wrong.
I don't want to jump to conclusions,
but I don't want to rule out
any possibilities, either.
No one outside of this
room knows that I've paired
with Oscar, and I think it may
be best to keep it that way.
- Play things close to the chest
until we get a better hand.
- Precisely.
Now, we have two steps ahead of us.
The first is enlisting
the aid of more Huntsmen.
- But the Mistral council--
- Doesn't own every
Huntsman in the Kingdom,
and I've been here enough times
to know where we can find some more.
- [Ozpin] So long as they're trustworthy.
- You can trust them
to put up a good fight.
I'll throw together a list tonight.
- [Nora] Good luck with that.
- After that, we can move on to step two.
- What's step two?
- Getting you four into fighting shape.
- But, uh, we already know how to fight.
- You can only fight so long
as you have Crescent Rose,
but you're still lacking
in hand-to-hand combat.
- Well, uh, yeah.
- Mr. Arc, I'm glad to
hear you've improved,
but sorry to say, you've yet
to unlock your Semblance.
All of you still have a-ways
to go before you're ready
to pose any real threat
against Salem and her forces.
And though Oscar can give
me temporary control,
he'll need to strengthen
his body and his Aura.
- [Oscar Voiceover] Wait, what?
- He'll inherit my muscle memory in time,
but practice will expedite the process.
- But if Qrow's out looking for Huntsmen,
then who's going to teach us?
- Well, I believe I was the
headmaster of Beacon Academy.
We have approximately one month
before classes resume at Haven.
If Salem were to plan an attack,
it would make sense that it occur
prior to students' return.
It's not much time, but
it's better than nothing.
Just don't expect me to go easy on you.
- You've gotta be kidding me.