Back to the fairytale, back to the show
Back to the wall and there's nowhere to go
Hopeless and desperate, all paths adverse
Things looking bleak, and they're bound to get worse
Helpless and doomed, and there's no way to win
Goals unachievable, faith running thin
Lost and forlorn, impossible odds
That's when you'll learn you've been messing with gods!
Send in your grimm, tear off my limb
Strike me with bolts of lightning
I won't die
The battle seems unwinnable, but all we need's a miracle
We're going up we'll never be denied!
Can't wish away the dismal days
Can't bring back what is gone
Won't waste more tears on yesteryears
Instead we'll carry on
We'll win, we're sure we will endure
And though our goal is far
We'll be the ones to touch the sun
The Triumph will be ours!
- Uh-oh. What're ya gonna do now?
- Whatever it takes to shut you up.
- You guys doin' okay?
- I think so. She's coming to.
I just wish this would go faster.
- How about you don't complain and just be
thankful you unlocked your
semblence when you did.
- My semblence?
- How else do you think
you're healing her, dummy?
- No, I don't think I'm
healing her. Our aura
heals our bodies. It
feels...it feels more like
I'm using my aura to amplify hers.
- Wait. Aren't you
worried about running out?
- Vera once told me I've got a lot of it.
I still believe her.
- Jaune?
- Ren!
- Go! I've got her.
- Jaune, what's happening?
- You took a heavy hit.
You need to stay with me
while the others fight.
- That's...
annoying.
- Good to have ya back Wes.
- Hiding behind the face of
a child? A monster like you
must be stopped.
- How many more children must die for you?
- His semblance, he can block
out pain. It's how he's able
to handle injecting so
much dust into his body.
- I don't need him to hurt.
- I just need him to go down
- What's going on in there?
- None of your concern
- Stay focused. Our friends
are almost done here.
- Adam!
- Blake?
- Who is that?
- Stand down
- Wait.
- To think that I went to
so much trouble to find you
only to have you deliver yourself to me.
- This isn't what's right
for the furnace. Stop
what you're doing and we
can end this peacefully.
- You're wrong, Blake.
And you can't stop us.
- No, I can't.
Not by myself
- That's why she didn't come alone.
- What? Who's there?
- Your brothers and sisters.
- Mata?
- Please.
Stop this.
- Make no mistake brothers.
These are our enemies.
And we will not let them ruin...
- Adam Taurus, this is
the Mistral police force.
Lower your weapons and
surrender peacefully.
- Huh?
- What's happening?
- I'm not sure. How are you feeling?
- Better.
Much better.
Keep it up.
- How? How did you do this?
- Adam, it's over.
- Then it's over for all of us.
- Hey, wait!
- Huh?
- What are you doing?
Trying to get us all killed?
- I am making humanity
pay for what they've done.
- We sent someone over to
confirm your explosives.
And, once we did, she disarmed them.
- What do we do?
- This is your business, not mine.
Fix it.
- I told you, Adam.
It's over.
- Kill them!
- Yang?
- Yang, go
- No
- Renal was a decoy the whole
time. The last spring maiden
must've trusted you a
great deal before she died.
I bet that was a mistake.
- Aura can't protect your arm. It's Grimm.
You turned yourself into
a monster just for power.
- Look who's talking
This is the end
Here’s where you’ll die
Legends should scatter
So just say goodbye
No one will miss you
When you’re finally gone
At your conclusion
Sing your swan song
Murder, unkindness, conspiracy
Embers extinguished in effigy
Black out the sky
All things must die
- Hot enough yet?
- Shut up
- If you were stronger or
more clever, then maybe
you'd remember to watch your back
- Thank you Vernal