Back to the fairytale, back to the show
Back to the wall and there's nowhere to go
Hopeless and desperate, all paths adverse
Things looking bleak, and they're bound to get worse
Helpless and doomed, and there's no way to win
Goals unachievable, faith running thin
Lost and forlorn, impossible odds
That's when you'll learn you've been messing with gods!
Send in your grimm, tear off my limb
Strike me with bolts of lightning
I won't die
The battle seems unwinnable, but all we need's a miracle
We're going up we'll never be denied!
Can't wish away the dismal days
Can't bring back what is gone
Won't waste more tears on yesteryears
Instead we'll carry on
We'll win, we're sure we will endure
And though our goal is far
We'll be the ones to touch the sun
The Triumph will be ours!
- [Vernal] Raven, we have a problem.
- What is it?
- Salem's found us.
- Salem.
Okay.
- [Vernal] Four of her
followers are waiting
to speak with you.
- Right, we planned for this.
Bring me my helmet.
I don't recall inviting so
many guests into our home.
Either I'm losing my memory,
or you've all lost your spines.
- Don't be too upset with them, Raven.
Your men simply recognize the power
of a maiden when they see it.
Which is why we'd like
to have a word with you.
- [Raven] Leave us, pack your things
then break down camp, we're moving.
- A little late to run and hide.
You've been on our master's
list for some time,
so you must understand that we cannot
allow you to slip away.
- [Raven] I know all about your master.
But I don't believe we've met.
- We're the guys you should be afraid of.
- [Raven] I doubt anyone
should be afraid of you.
- Oh yeah, tell that to--
Quiet.
- [Raven] That's what I thought.
- I'm Cinder Fall.
This is my associate, Arthur Watts.
And my disciples, Emerald and Mercury.
- [Raven] Two children you've
tricked into following you.
A disgraced Atlesion scientist
and a fall maiden with a
surname so appropriate,
she probably picked it herself.
Something tells me you've got more
than a slight case of ego-mania.
Is that about right?
- (clears throat) Technically,
I was also a doctor,
but I must say the rest was spot-on.
- Aren't you perceptive?
- [Raven] It's what's kept me alive.
- I'm afraid the only
reason you're still alive
is because you have
something our master wants.
Of course, if I'm wrong.
- [Raven] Vernal.
- So, this is the long lost spring maiden.
Prove it.
- [Raven] Vernal has done
well under my guidance.
I'd take that into consideration
before you try anything.
- Raven, I won't underestimate you,
so please don't insult my intelligence.
There is a slim chance you and your maiden
could escape here today.
But if you know our master
as well as you claim to,
then you know you could
never truly escape her.
But we come bearing an olive branch.
- The maidens are merely
a means to an end.
Salem's true desires are the relics
locked within the Huntsman Academies.
Come with us, allow Vernal here
to unlock the relic of knowledge
and all previous acts of
defiance against Salem
will be forgiven.
It's the best deal either
of you are going to get.
- [Raven] You talk as if walking
straight into Haven will be easy.
- That's because it will be.
Headmaster Lionheart
is loyal to Salem now.
All we need is the key to the vault.
You're not the only one to
turn your back on Oz, Raven.
- [Raven] I'm not helping Salem.
I'm not helping Oz.
I don't want a part in any of this.
- That ship sailed when you
chose to harbor a maiden.
But if you come with us to Haven,
we'll leave you, your tribe,
and your little secret to live out
the rest of your days
squabbling in the wilderness.
We just need the relic.
- [Raven] I need time to think this over.
- You don't have time.
In two days, Haven
Academy will be destroyed
by the White Fang.
You're going to choose now.
- [Raven] Backed me into a corner, huh.
- So, are you with us
or against us?
- Agreements like these
are built on trust.
And forgive me for
saying, but I don't trust
a single one of you.
You're going to need to give me more.
- You are in a poor position to negotiate.
- I want my brother dead.
- Qrow?
- That's right.
He knows I have Spring.
And if I help you get your relic,
he's going to become a problem.
I have enough problems to deal with.
Qrow doesn't trust me,
but he does trust Ozpin's
other lieutenants.
If Leo really is loyal to you,
then you can order him to invite Qrow
right into an ambush.
He arrives at Haven, we take him down,
you get your relic.
And we all leave happy.
- Now this is a proposition
I can get behind.
- All right ladies,
let's pause for a moment.
We have one objective.
Retrieving the Relic of Naulch.
Now Qrow Branwen maybe on
our list of individuals
we would very much like dead,
but he's not going to
go down without a fight
and he's not going to fight quietly.
Our advantage here is just as you said.
We walk straight into
Haven, no resistance,
no one the wiser.
The battle with your brother
throws that all out the window.
- He's good, but not that good.
All of us against him,
it'll be over in a heartbeat.
- But it's not just him.
He has the students with him.
He has Ruby.
- He certainly does.
- If we leave that school a bloody mess
it will draw the attention
of the authorities.
The kingdom will be on high alert
and the White Fang's
attack will be ruined.
- Then we wait.
We wait until the full moon.
Leo invites Qrow and his
little fighters to Haven
the same night Hazel and Adam
arrive with the White Fang.
As soon as the battle is won,
the White Fang demolishes Haven
and any evidence we may have left behind
is lost along with the school.
- Then Salem leaves my people alone.
For good.
- You have yourself a deal.
- Wait.
Don't think I don't see what you're after.
If this falls to pieces over
your grudge with a child,
I will not be taking the blame.
- Then what are you worried about?
Fly back home and tinker
with your machines.
And tell Salem she'll get what she wants
and more.
- [Man] Brother.
- Hurry.
- Dad, where's mom?
- I'm not sure.
I got ambushed right away.
- Once we take down Corsac and Fennec.
- No, go now.
- But.
- You keep assuring me your friend
isn't a complete waste of space.
Let's see him prove it.
- We got this Blake.
I've wanted to sock these creeps
since the day we met.
- You'll have to get in line.
Blake, go.
- I won't let you down, sir.
- Shut up.
- You got it.
- Yes, Vernal.
- I followed them as you asked.
- Did they spot you?
- Of course not.
They have a ship two clicks west of here.
Looks like they're staying
there for the night.
- Thank you, Vernal.
Anything else?
- Do you actually believe
they'll let us go once
they have the relic?
- Of course not.
They'll never leave us alone.
Once our purpose has come and gone,
we'll be discarded.
Salem only uses people until
they are no longer useful.
If we want to have any chance
of defending ourselves against her,
then we need this relic.
If Qrow and those brats wanna
follow Ozpin then let them.
When the chaos reaches its peak,
we'll grab the relic
and make our escape.
- And the fact that your daughter
will be a part of all that?
- Doesn't matter.
I warned her.
She made her choice.
This path won't be easy for us either,
but we must do what's right for the tribe.
- I know.
I'll do whatever it takes.
- Good.
- Hey Qrow.
Oz needs to talk to you.