- [Qrow] The city of Mistral.
- [Nora] Ugh, it's about time.
Whose idea was it to walk again?
- [Ren] Well, we did face many obstacles.
Broken airships, destroyed settlements.
- Oh, and, you know, all those people
and monsters that tried to murder us.
- We were fine.
Only one of us almost died.
- Hey.
- So, how much farther to Haven Academy?
- Almost there, but I figured I'd take
you kids on the scenic route.
- Wow!
This is awesome.
- [Qrow] It's certainly something.
- -[Ruby] Oh my gosh,
look at all the weapons.
- [Qrow] Vendors here'll
sell you just about anything
whether they should or not.
- [Jaune] They really made the
most out of these mountains.
- [Qrow] Every inch.
And stay away from the lower levels.
But the higher up you
go, the nicer it gets.
- And we are going up.
- [Weiss] So, how much farther?
- We're in the home stretch now.
No more stops from here to Mistral.
Sorry for the long trip.
Keeping us off the radar's
been harder than I thought.
Lots of air traffic around northern Anima.
- It's fine, I just hope
I haven't been a burden.
- You and your money are more
than welcome on this ship, kid.
What the?
- [Weiss] Is everything okay?
- I don't know.
We're still over Lake Matsu.
Shouldn't be picking up
broadcasts this far from Mistral.
Someone must be close.
- [Pilot On Radio] Mayday, mayday.
We are a small passenger flight,
and our Huntress is down.
We aren't equipped to deal with this!
- [Pilot] Oh man.
- [Pilot On Radio] The Grimm
hit us 400 klicks north
of the southern shoreline.
Get them off us.
If anyone can here this.
(booming)
Ah!
- [Weiss] We're going to help them, right?
- What?
No, I'm trying to avoid them.
- But they'll die.
- Look, if we picked
up their transmission,
I'm sure someone else did, too.
Besides, this is a cargo ship.
She's not much good in a fight.
I just wanna finish this job and get home.
Sorry, kid.
My ship, my rules
- We made it.
Hello?
- Maybe try louder?
- There doesn't seem to be anyone here.
- Well, I guess school isn't
really in session right now.
Maybe that's it.
- No, this isn't right.
Come on.
- Wait for us!
- Get ready, there could be trouble.
- Uh, Professor Lionheart?
- Qrow!
For crying out loud, you
nearly scared me half to death.
- Me?
Why weren't you waiting
for us at the entrance?
- Huh?
Oh, right.
Apologies.
I guess time slipped away from me.
- You're joking.
- Where is everybody?
- Ah, you must be the
students Qrow mentioned.
- Yes, sir.
Ruby Rose.
- Jaune Arc.
- Nora Valkrie.
- Lie Ren.
- A pleasure to meet you all.
Leonardo Lionheart, at your service.
I'm afraid most of my staff is currently
away until classes resume, but--
- What?
Leo, you can't be serious.
Who's guarding the relic?
- Qrow, the children.
- Already know.
I filled them in.
What do you mean your staff is away?
- You filled them in?
- So, is this not going at all
like anyone thought it would?
- Unbelievable!
- Total garbage!
- [Both] We can't let
them get away with this!
- Well, at least you two can
finally agree on something.
- Guys,
everything's gonna be okay.
- [Guard] Good evening, miss.
Can I get you anything?
- Just a little time to
myself, if that's all right.
- Sure thing.
Just call if you need me.
- You need better security.
Please.
I just need to talk.
- [Blake] How could you take
the fall for them, Ilia?
- [Ilia] Blake.
- Corsac and Fennec blamed you.
We confronted them tonight
and they deny knowing anything
and everything we found on your Scroll.
They talked about how
disappointed they were
to hear that you'd sided with Adam.
But you and I both know they're guilty.
- You can't prove anything.
- That Scroll might not have
been enough to lock them up,
but it's enough to sway the Faunus here.
When we go public
tomorrow, they're not going
to stand for any of it
and neither should you.
- Your plan isn't gonna work, Blake.
Please just leave Menagerie
before it's too late.
- You're going to have to make me.
- I know.
- [Leo] I have to say,
Qrow, this all seems
very reckless, even for you.
- No, reckless is leaving one of
the Relics completely unguarded,
it's not checking in with Oz for ages.
- There was nothing to check
in about before the fall
of Beacon, but since that day,
Mistral has been in chaos!
Vale wasn't the only kingdom
to suffer that night.
Everyone was watching.
Every house in every Kingdom
saw that poor girl ripped
to pieces, saw monsters
crawling over the city,
Atlesian Knights attacking
citizens and then nothing.
You could feel the dread in the air.
With all that negativity,
you can imagine what it was
like when the Grimm came for us.
Mistral's controlled territory is
the widest reaching in the world,
you know, and that makes it
infinitely harder to protect.
We lost so many great Huntsmen,
teachers from this very institution.
And it's only gotten worse.
- What do you mean?
- We may have dealt with the Grimm,
but the Mistral council's still at odds
with representatives from Atlas.
First, it was the Dust embargo,
now it's the closing of borders.
I'm not sure what happened to
James in Vale, but it seems to
have only worsened some of his
more unfortunate tendencies.
And, on top of everything, we still don't
know where the Spring Maiden is.
- All the more reason we need
the Huntsmen and Huntresses here.
- Okay, okay!
Things are bad, they're bad.
But we can figure this out.
Why is the Spring Maiden so important?
- I thought you filled them in.
- Mostly filled in.
Look, there's a lot to cover, okay?
I quit teaching for a reason.
- The four Maidens each have
the power to perform feats
of magic, and they are the only ones
capable of reaching the Relics.
- What?
- The Relics are each locked
inside a chamber that can
only be opened by a specific Maiden.
Winter for the gift of Creation,
Summer for Destruction,
Fall for Choice and Spring for Knowledge.
Spring is the problem.
- What happened to her?
- She was determined, at first,
when she inherited her
powers, but the weight
of responsibility proved to
be too much for the child.
She ran,
abandoned her training, everyone.
That was over a decade ago.
There's no telling where she could be now.
- I know.
At least, I have a pretty good idea.
- Are you serious?
- It's not exactly good news.
- What are you talking about?
This is incredible news!
After all these years.
Where?
- I did some digging around.
Looks like after Spring
ran away, she was picked
up by bandits, specifically
the Branwen tribe.
- Raven.
- Yang's mom?
- That's right.
That's about where they've
set up their main camp.
It's where they fall back to after
raids and scouting missions.
Raven's managed to gain
a lot of followers since
she returned to the
tribe, and I'm sure when
the Spring Maiden showed up,
it only made things easier.
- Well, Qrow, I've got to hand it to you.
With these coordinates, we
can mount a retrieval force
and head out in a few weeks.
- A few weeks?
- [Leo] That's right.
- Leo, maybe you didn't hear me.
My sister has the Spring
Maiden and I know where she is.
We need to go, as soon as possible!
- And perhaps you didn't hear me.
This kingdom is in shambles.
As soon as possible
does not mean tomorrow,
it means as soon as I can
convince the rest of the council
that I need Huntsmen more than they do.
Unfortunately, bandit tribes
aren't very high on their list
of priorities when the threat
of war is just on the horizon.
- Then damn the council.
We'll do it ourselves.
You and I are trained Huntsmen
and these kids aren't exactly pushovers.
- Yeah!
- Perhaps there's a more
peaceful way to approach this?
- We need to get Spring as far
away from here as possible.
And Raven isn't going to give up her
most prized possession without a fight.
- Unfortunately, you and your
sister are evenly matched
and I'm not the fighter I used to be.
No offense, but these
students and I can't take on
an entire bandit tribe and
a Maiden that's no doubt
had years to hone her skills.
We need to be positive
we can apprehend Spring
because if we fail Raven and her tribe
will scatter and we'll be lost.
We get one shot at this
and it needs to be perfect.
- You know Oz wouldn't be happy with any
of this if he were here.
- Perhaps you're right.
But he's not.
I'm doing the very best I can.
- There has to be something we can do.
- What about Cinder?
She came with Emerald
and Mercury from Haven.
Do you have anything on them?
- We pulled their files
after the fall of Beacon.
Nothing but lies and forgeries.
- Well, I can't say this has
been a warm reunion, Leo.
- I'm sorry.
I know you've all traveled a long way,
but I will do everything I can to help.
- Sure.
We'll stay in the city for the time being.
Local comms are still up.
Keep in touch.
Come on, kids.
- It was nice meeting you, Professor.
- Likewise.
- [Watts] Oh, Leo.
We have got to work on your
improvisational skills.
- So, what do we do now?
- You four head back to the house.
I need a drink.
- [Oscar] Excuse me.
- You know, I don't think they allow
kids in here, pipsqueak.
- Shut up, I'm getting there.
Um, I'm supposed to tell
you, I'd like my cane back.
- It's good to see you again, Oz.
- Aren't you a little
young to be drinking?
- A water.
It's hot out.
- Oh, sure.
- Are you telling me
you're too young to drink?
You look like a regular Huntress.
And a beauty at that.
- [Yang] I'm good.
Thanks, pal.
- Seriously.
Not too bulky, not too lean.
You're--
- Just right.
Yup, like I said, I'm good.
- And your hair--
Huh?
- This one's on the house.
He's been driving me crazy.
So, what brings you around these parts?
- Thanks.
And I'm, uh, looking for someone.
- Not many people come out here.
Too far from the Kingdoms.
Only person worth notin'
around here is, well, Ra--
- Raven Branwen.
Thanks again.
- Now, missy, you don't wanna
go messin' with bandits!
They're a world of trouble.
- So I hear.
- [Man] Hey, girlie.
- Seriously?
This isn't over?
- I heard you're looking for someone.
- Can I help you?
- Um yeah.
Is there a Ruby Rose here?
- Why?
- Well.
- I found him!
- I think her uncle could use some help.
- [Qrow] I found him.
- What is going on out there?
Can't a girl read her comics in peace?
Qrow, did you get drunk again?
- [Qrow] Maybe.
- Oh.
You have silver eyes.
- Who are you?
- Uh, well,
my name is Oscar Pine.
- [Qrow] Wait for it.
- But you probably know
me as Professor Ozpin.
- I did it!
Back to the fairytale, back to the show
Back to the wall and there's nowhere to go
Hopeless and desperate, all path adverse
Things looking bleak, and they're bound to get worse
Helpless and doomed, and there's no way to win
Goals unachievable, faith running thin
Lost and forlorn, impossible odds
That's when you'll learn you've been messing with gods
Send in your grimm, tear off my limb
Strike me with bolts of lightning
I won't die
The battle seems unwinnable, but all we need's a miracle
We're going up we'll never be denied
Can't wish away the dismal days
Can't bring back what is gone
Won't waste more tears on yesteryears
Instead we'll carry on
We'll win, we're sure we will endure
And though our goal is far
We'll be the ones to touch the sun
The Triumph will be ours!