Back to the fairytale, back to the show
Back to the wall and there's nowhere to go
Hopeless and desperate, all paths adverse
Things looking bleak, and they're bound to get worse
Helpless and doomed, and there's no way to win
Goals unachievable, faith running thin
Lost and forlorn, impossible odds
That's when you'll learn you've been messing with gods!
Send in your grimm, tear off my limb
Strike me with bolts of lightning
I won't die
The battle seems unwinnable, but all we need's a miracle
We're going up we'll never be denied!
Can't wish away the dismal days
Can't bring back what is gone
Won't waste more tears on yesteryears
Instead we'll carry on
We'll win, we're sure we will endure
And though our goal is far
We'll be the ones to touch the sun
The Triumph will be ours!
- [Arthur] Are we ready?
After you.
- Your Grace, are you there?
- Hello, Leonardo.
Do you have something to report?
- Of course, ma'am.
I would not waste your time, if not.
- I'm still just so
fascinated by this creature.
Cinder, dear, are, are we coming through?
Can you see us clearly?
Well, as clearly as you can.
- Shut up.
- Oh goody, you've recovered.
- [Salem] Your report.
What is it?
- I've, I've found the Spring Maiden.
- Is that so?
Well done.
Arthur, had I known how useful you'd be in
expediting this process,
I would've sent you
long, long ago.
- As much as I'd love
to take credit, ma'am,
I can't say that either of us are to thank
for this development.
I guess you could say a
little birdie told us.
- [Salem] Explain.
- You see, ma'am, Qrow Branwen arrived at
Haven Academy earlier today.
He believes Spring has
taken residence with
his sister's tribe.
- Is the girl with him?
- [Leonardo] Yes, Miss
Rose was in attendance.
- And you know of the tribe's location?
- Yes, ma'am!
But you have to hurry!
Qrow is already at odds with my--
- Leonardo, do you remember
the first time we met?
I remember.
I remember your fear.
But, since that day, you've
been extraordinarily brave.
I won't forget all that
you've done for me.
Do not forget everything I can do to you.
Cinder, you and your team will meet with
Doctor Watts and together
convince Raven Branwen
that the survival of her people depends
on her cooperation.
Once you have Spring under control,
escort her to the Relic and contact Hazel.
The White Fang was promised
the destruction of Haven
and they'll have it once
we have what we need.
- [Arthur] Understood.
- [Salem] Not you, Arthur.
Tyrian's in need of a new tail.
- What happened to his old one?
- [Salem] Guess.
- The silver-eyed girl?
It will be done.
- Good.
- Seems Qrow was right, Lionheart.
The students aren't pushovers.
- You're free to speak your mind.
- I don't understand.
Working with bandits?
Keeping Ruby alive?
What's the point?
We're strong enough to
take what we want by force!
- Never underestimate
the usefulness of others.
Take Leonardo.
He was one of Ozpin's
most trusted and yet now.
Hmm.
You will have the power I promised you
when the time is right.
But remember that it comes with a cost.
If Ruby Rose has learned
to harness her gift
then you must take care to protect yours.
There's only so much I can do to aid you.
And Cinder, before you go, inform Tyrian
that I wish to have a word with him.
- Where are we?
- Nowhere good.
Passing by some of Lake
Matsu's floating islands.
The gravity Dust that
forms in these things
is giving us a little turbulence.
Nothing I can't handle,
but the islands sometimes
hide some nasty Grimm.
I'm just betting on
our friends in distress
keeping them preoccupied.
- Look out!
- Huh?
You've got to be kidding me!
- [Mistral] By the gods, we've lost Percy!
Help!
We're hooked!
Everyone, abandon ship!
- Lancers, freakin' Lancers!
All right, buckle up.
Huh?
What are you doing?
- What we should've
done in the first place!
You're carrying Dust, right?
- Officially, no.
Actually, yes.
- [Weiss] Then when I tell
you, open the rear door!
- Better make it quick!
Kid, we're cutting it close!
- Ready!
- Ha-ha!
Hold on!
- What was that?
- We're hooked!
I got an idea!
Hold on!
Literally!
Ha-ha!
- Can you find a pair of
islands we can fit between?
- Kid, you are reading my mind!
Yeah!
Great going, kid!
We are in the clear!
- It's a Queen Lancer!
- What?
Do something!
- I can see the shoreline!
Gods, we're not gonna make it!
Shame that it took so long to rescue me
From the guilt you used to tie me to your family tree
I guess your training failed you're not in charge, I'm free
Your patriarchal prison won't hold me
Now this conversation's finally over, mirror mirror now we're done
- Pull up, now!
I've pulled myself together now, my mind and heart are one
Finally one!
I'm not your pet
Not another thing you own
I was not born guilty of your crimes
Your riches and your influence can't hold me anymore
I won't be possessed burdened by your royal test
I will not surrender, this life is mine!
- [Sienna] Adam.
I'm not going to repeat myself so I want
you to listen when I tell you that the
White Fang will not attack Haven Academy.
- High Leader Khan, I am begging you--
- You should beg for
forgiveness and nothing else!
The assault you led on
Beacon was not the great
victory you clearly think
it was and you should
be grateful your punishment
wasn't more severe.
You are a symbol for
many in our organization,
but that doesn't make you infallible.
- I was merely trying to follow
your example, High Leader.
- And what example might that be?
- Strength.
Strength and unwavering conviction.
The humans have seen that strength now.
- I was one of the first
to suggest violence
where violence was necessary.
Peace bred complacency
and acceptance of our
place in the world.
I will not allow humanity to push us down
without pushing them back.
But the destruction of
the Huntsman Academies
crosses a line!
The loss of the CCT has brought global
communication to a crawl!
And the White Fang is more of a target
now than ever before!
You have justified humanity's
campaign against us
and for what?
Empty promises from a group of humans?
Humans we still know nothing about
and come and go as they please!
These are not examples of strength, Adam.
They are examples of your talents being
diminished by shortsightedness!
- If you want to know
more about the humans
then why not talk to one of them yourself?
Hazel!
- Took you long enough.
- What is this?
- Apologies.
I don't aim to cause any trouble.
- You've brought a human to this location?
- [Adam] You should
hear what he has to say.
- This is grounds for execution!
- Ma'am, please.
Nobody needs to die today.
I'm just asking for a moment of your time.
- [Sienna] The longer you stay
here, the less of a chance
you have of leaving alive.
- I'll take those chances,
if you don't mind.
You don't like me.
You have no reason to like me.
But you don't have to like me
to get the results you want.
- I'm starting to doubt either of you
fully comprehend what it is that I want.
I want humanity to fear the Faunus,
to know that we demand respect!
I do not want to start
a war with the humans
that we cannot win!
- That's where you're wrong.
We can win a war against the humans.
Not only because we have the
support of Hazel's master,
but because the Faunus
are the dominant species
of this planet.
We're better than humans.
We have everything humans have and more.
Humans shouldn't just fear the Faunus,
they should serve the Faunus.
I've had enough of this
conversation for tonight.
Guards, take them away.
I said, take them away!
- I will admit, Sienna, you
were right about my popularity.
My followers in Vale already
see me as the true High Leader.
And many here in Mistral feel the same.
- [Hazel] What are you doing?
- What's right for the Faunus.
From this day forward,
I will be the one to
lead the White Fang.
- If you think I'll just step aside
and follow beneath you, you're wrong--
- I know.
Thank you, Sienna.
You were there when our people needed you,
but they need me, now.
I'm sorry you couldn't see
this through to the end.
Give our former leader a proper burial.
All who were here tonight
will claim that Sienna
was murdered by a human Huntsman.
Sienna Khan will become
a martyr for our cause,
her final act as High Leader.
- When were you planning
on telling me about that?
- This was my business, not yours.
- [Hazel] It's our business
now and I don't appreciate you
withholding things like that.
- Your master was concerned with Sienna's
willingness to cooperate.
Now she doesn't have to be.
- [Hazel] Nobody needed to die today.
- I disagree.
- Help please.
- What do you think?
- I think we just hit the jackpot.
Shame that it took so long to rescue me
From the guilt you used to tie me to your family tree
I guess your training failed you're not in charge, I'm free
Your patriarchal prison won't hold me
Now this conversation's finally over, mirror mirror now we're done
I've pulled myself together now, my mind and heart are one
Finally one!