Back to the fairytale, back to the show
Back to the wall and there's nowhere to go
Hopeless and desperate, all paths adverse
Things looking bleak, and they're bound to get worse
Helpless and doomed, and there's no way to win
Goals unachievable, faith running thin
Lost and forlorn, impossible odds
That's when you'll learn you've been messing with gods!
Send in your grimm, tear off my limb
Strike me with bolts of lightning
I won't die
The battle seems unwinnable, but all we need's a miracle
We're going up we'll never be denied!
Can't wish away the dismal days
Can't bring back what is gone
Won't waste more tears on yesteryears
Instead we'll carry on
We'll win, we're sure we will endure
And though our goal is far
We'll be the ones to touch the sun
The Triumph will be ours!
- Regular, or the special?
- I'm actually looking for someone.
Goes by the name Shiro Wan.
You ever heard of 'em?
I heard he's a regular around here.
- Who's askin'?
- Hey, I'm not some cop
if that's what you mean.
I need Shiro for a gig.
We go way back.
- Way back, huh?
So, he's a friend of yours?
- Hmm, yeah I'd say so.
He's a pretty alright guy.
- Well, in that case
you tell that jerk that he
better not show his ugly face
in here until he pays
me the lien he owes me!
- Did I say friend? (laughs)
I meant acquaintance.
Really, we're just colleagues.
Anyways, thanks for your time buddy.
I'll just be takin' off now.
Great start.
Heather Shields.
Oh, uh hey there.
I'm looking for Heather?
Look, pal, I've had a rough day.
Do you know where she is or not?
- Daddy?
Does he know where mommy is?
- I, uh, (sighs)
I'm sorry to bother you.
- You got a lotta nerve
showin' up back here,
unless you brought that idiot with you.
- How much did Shiro owe you?
- Well, I'd say about 16,000 lian.
Wait, what?
Man, you must be in some serious trouble
with him if you're payin' off.
- His name is clear.
- Yeah.
That idiot.
Yeah.
- April, wait outside.
Thank you.
- So, what's the truth?
- You know, it's better when it's hot.
- You know, you're really obnoxious.
- The truth is that
truth is hard to come by.
A story of victory for one person
is a story of defeat for someone else.
By now your uncle has surely told
Ruby and her friends plenty of stories.
- Well he's never given me a
reason to doubt him before.
- That doesn't mean those
reasons don't exist.
You know, you and your
teammates might as well
be the poster children for
the Huntsman Academies.
Your motives vary, but you all enrolled
to try and make the world a better place.
It's adorable.
- It's what huntsmen and huntresses do.
- Not all of them.
Some people are just in it
for the money and the fame,
but there's even more that are just
looking to grow stronger.
Your uncle Qrow and I didn't attend Beacon
to become huntsmen.
We did it to learn how to kill huntsmen.
Daddy and uncle left that part out, hmm?
Aside from the Grimm,
huntsmen were the only ones
capable of ruining our
raids and hunting us down.
Our tribe needed a counterforce.
And Qrow and I were the perfect age.
The entrance exams were child's play
compared to what we'd
already been through.
We were good.
So good that we caught the attention of
Beacon's very own
headmaster, Professor Ozpin.
Even after we were put on a team,
I could tell he was keeping his eye on us.
Back then I thought it
was because he knew,
but it was team Stark
he was interested in.
- What do you mean by that?
- Constant attention,
extra training missions,
turning a blind eye whenever
we happened to break the rules
and get in to more
trouble than we should've.
Sound familiar?
- What's your point?
How much do you know
about Professor Ozpin?
About his past?
- He was a prodigy, one of
the youngest headmasters
to be appointed to a school.
- Because that's how he planned it.
Because the man you know as
Ozpin designed those schools
and has followers inside every
academy on Remnant that are
loyal to him and no one else.
- That doesn't make any sense.
How could he have... no.
Why would someone even do that?
- Because old man Oz has a
great and terrible secret.
- [Raven] One that could
spread fear across the world.
One that he eventually
entrusted to our team,
and once I knew, there was no going back.
I needed to know more,
but with every new discovery I made,
the more horrifying the world became.
- Okay, then tell us.
What's the big secret?
What's so crazy that the
rest of us don't know.
The creatures of Grimm
have a master named Salem.
She can't be stopped, she
can't be reasoned with,
and she will not rest until
humanity crumbles at her feet.
- What?
- You know you two haven't
even touched your tea.
- Why should we believe any of this?
- Now you're catching on.
So far you've done nothing but
accept what others tell you.
But you need to question everything.
Otherwise you'll end up
just as blind as Qrow.
And your fool of a father.
- Don't you dare talk
about my family like that.
- You need to calm down.
- Yang, please.
- Listen to your friend, Yang.
Your teammate's never let you down before.
- You don't know the first
thing about my teammates.
About me!
You were never there, you left us!
Why?
- I know more than you realize.
Not just about you, and not
just what I've been told,
but the things I've seen with my own eyes.
I know the Grimm have a leader.
I know people who can
come back from the dead.
I know that magic is real,
and I can prove it.
You said Ty told you
all about my semblance.
Well I doubt he ever told you
what Oz did to my brother and me.
- Go see for yourself.
- Mom?
- Yang, are you okay?
- I'll be fine once we can
get her to take us to Ruby.
- It's okay if you're not okay.
- You didn't believe what she said, right?
- I ... of course not.
Well, not all of it.
It was crazy, we have the dust semblances,
but I mean there's no such thing as magic.
- A raven?
- I've seen that bird before.
- Maybe it belongs to your mom?
- How did you do that?
Well, I could explain it to you,
or you could ask your uncle.
- You're letting us go?
- I'm giving you a choice.
Stay here with me,
and I'll answer all of
your questions and more.
We can have a fresh start.
Or, you can go back to Qrow
and join Ozpen's impossible
war against Salem,
and meet the same fate as so many others.
But can you really go
back to trusting someone
that's kept so much from you?
- All I care about is making
sure my sister is safe.
- Ugh.
Yang.
If you side with your
uncle, I may not be as kind
the next time we meet.
- You weren't kind this time, either.
- I know.
- This isn't right.
I get one or two of 'em, but all of them?
Raven.
Oh.
- Alright, the first
batch is just about done.
- Awesome!
Now we just need Qrow
and we'll be all set.
- Do you really think he's
going to bring that many people?
This is a lot of food.
- Uh, I don't know.
But it sounds like we can
use all the help we can get.
- [Qrow] I'm back.
- Be right there!
- You're going to overcook that.
- No I'm not, shut up!
- [Qrow] Hey, uh, Ruby?
- I'm coming. (gasps)
Fine, you take over.
So we didn't know how
many people were coming
so we just cooked all of it.
- Yang, I... I'm so sorry.
I should have stayed, and I
should have talked to you more.
I just... I wasn't sure if
you wanted me around and...
- I love you.
- I love you, too.
- Uh...
- Weiss?