Back to the fairytale, back to the show
Back to the wall and there's nowhere to go
Hopeless and desperate, all paths adverse
Things looking bleak, and they're bound to get worse
Helpless and doomed, and there's no way to win
Goals unachievable, faith running thin
Lost and forlorn, impossible odds
That's when you'll learn you've been messing with gods!
Send in your grimm, tear off my limb
Strike me with bolts of lightning
I won't die
The battle seems unwinnable, but all we need's a miracle
We're going up we'll never be denied!
Can't wish away the dismal days
Can't bring back what is gone
Won't waste more tears on yesteryears
Instead we'll carry on
We'll win, we're sure we will endure
And though our goal is far
We'll be the ones to touch the sun
The Triumph will be ours!
- How much further, pal?
- This should just about do it.
You wait here.
I'll go up ahead and make
sure the coast is clear.
I can't believe you were dumb enough
to let me lead you here.
- Is this everyone?
- Yes, little lady.
This is it.
Well, unless you count the whole
rest of the camp back that way.
- That way?
- Yes, that way.
- Good to know, thanks.
- Now to pay me back for this tooth,
we're going to take your bike.
And you're going to take your lumps.
You got the jump on me
last time, sweetheart.
But you really ought to think
twice about fighting all--
All right, get her!
(coughing) Who are you?
It doesn't even matter.
When Raven finds out what
you did, you're dead!
- Possibly.
But I doubt it.
I am her daughter, after all.
- I'm dead.
- Man, Oz wasn't kidding.
Oscar's picking up on this stuff fast.
- Oh my gosh, I'm so sorry!
Ha, yes!
I did it!
Oscar?
- [Ozpin Voiceover] You forgot
to engage your Aura, again.
- Why didn't you tell me?
- [Ozpin Voiceover]
Because this method makes
you less likely to forget.
Mind if I give it a shot?
Not bad, Miss Rose.
But Oscar doesn't have the
years of training that you do.
Or I do.
- Oh, ha, well, maybe we
should uh, take a break.
- Ouch.
- The next time you want
to throw a left cross,
remember to push off with
the appropriate foot.
And as always, do be
aware of any openings.
- Got it.
Oh hey, are you okay?
- How is this so exhausting?
- Your body isn't used
to this kind of training,
not to mention generating a
defensive Aura on your own.
It takes intense concentration at first,
but in time it will become second nature,
allowing you to deflect attacks
and gradually heal your wounds.
After that, you can begin
focusing on your Semblance,
whatever that may be.
- Semblance?
- You know!
Like your very own superpower!
Everybody's got one.
It's just a matter of
finding it and mastering it.
Ruby moves super fast,
Electricity makes me stronger,
Ren can mask emotions,
and Jaune can, uh, um.
Hmm.
- I can't do anything--
- Jaune's like you!
He hasn't found his Semblance
yet, but we all know he will.
And you will, too.
We all just have to try and
help each other get stronger.
- Cool.
- A common philosophy is that a warrior's
Semblance is a part of who they are.
Some say your personality
and character can define your
Semblance while some claim that
it is the other way around.
Of course, there are still many who
don't see a connection at all.
- It's hard to know
when you know sometimes.
Ren's Semblance was unlocked
from intense stress.
- And mine kicked in
during training one day.
- What about you?
- Oh, struck by lightning.
Didn't die.
Crazy Thursday.
- I just don't understand
what's wrong with me.
I train.
I meditate.
- Don't worry, Mr. Arc.
Your journey is far from over.
And the same might be said for all of you.
Unlocking your Semblance isn't the end.
It can still grow and evolve.
Providing you're willing
to put in the work,
who knows what could happen.
- Then let's get back to it.
- Huh?
- Mom.
- Yang.
So, after all this time you
finally decided to visit me.
- You know that I searched for you.
I spent years looking for you.
- And you've found me.
You were patient, determined,
and strong enough to make
your dream a reality.
Well done, Yang.
But did you have to be
so rough with my men?
- I didn't want a fight.
They started it.
- Well, you certainly finished it.
Right.
I'm sure this is all very overwhelming.
But I must admit that
you've proven yourself.
So any questions you have
I'll be happy to answer.
You can stay with us tonight.
I'll even have the cooks
whip up something for you.
- [Yang] That's not why I am here.
- What was that?
- I'm not here for you.
Ruby is somewhere in Mistral.
She's with Qrow, and she's
going to need my help.
I just need you to take me to her.
- And why would I do that?
- Because we're family.
- Family.
Only coming around when
they need something.
I have to say, I'm disappointed.
After all, you found me, didn't you?
Why not take that drive and
use it to find your little
sister if she really
means that much to you?
- Because you're going to save me time.
Ruby was heading to Mistral,
but there's no guarantee
she's made it there.
Looking for her in Anima could take ages.
But, Dad told me how your Semblance works.
- Tai.
- You can bond to certain people.
And when you do, you could create a portal
that takes you straight to them.
You've got one for Dad.
One for me.
And you've got one for Qrow.
He promised me he'd watch
out for Ruby before he left.
And I trust him.
So, make a portal to my uncle and sister,
and I'll be on my way.
- You know, it takes real
strength to march in here
and demand such a favor of me.
I've got to say, I'm impressed.
It's very noble to want
to help out your sister.
But if she's with Qrow, then
she's already a lost cause.
- [Yang] What does that mean?
- You don't want to get mixed
up in all of that, Yang.
Ozpin is not the man you think he is.
And Qrow is a fool for trusting him.
I would know, I trusted him once, too.
- I don't care what you think.
- Your choice is your own.
All I'm suggesting is that
instead of getting wrapped
up in something too big
for you, for any of us,
that maybe you take a moment to wonder
if you're already where you belong.
- Save your breath.
You could spout off whatever you want,
but nothing is going to
keep me from my sister.
- Well, aren't you stubborn.
- I get it from my mom.
- Well, if that's how you feel,
then it sounds like we're done here.
Take her away.
- Did you not hear me?
I said send me to Qrow, damn it!
- That's enough!
You watch your mouth
in front of our leader!
- Make me.
- Yang?
- Weiss?
- All right, well, subtlety is out.
- What is that?
- Don't worry about it.
What are you doing here?
- Well, that's my mom and
she can take us to Ruby.
- Ugh.
- Your mom kidnapped me?
- You kidnapped her?
- [Vernal] Enough!
- Thank you.
If you people don't keep it together
this place will be crawling with Grimm.
Give the girl her weapon back.
You two.
In my tent, now.
- Why?
- If you're really
going after your sister,
then you need to know the truth.
- Sorry about--
- I missed you so much.
- I've missed you, too.