Back to the fairytale, back to the show
Back to the wall and there's nowhere to go
Hopeless and desperate, all paths adverse
Things looking bleak, and they're bound to get worse
Helpless and doomed, and there's no way to win
Goals unachievable, faith running thin
Lost and forlorn, impossible odds
That's when you'll learn you've been messing with gods!
Send in your grimm, tear off my limb
Strike me with bolts of lightning
I won't die
The battle seems unwinnable, but all we need's a miracle
We're going up we'll never be denied!
Can't wish away the dismal days
Can't bring back what is gone
Won't waste more tears on yesteryears
Instead we'll carry on
We'll win, we're sure we will endure
And though our goal is far
We'll be the ones to touch the sun
The Triumph will be ours!
- Why hello.
Thank you for coming.
There seems to more of you than last time.
- Eh, you know what they say.
The more the merrier.
So what's going on with the council?
- Why did you bring your weapons?
- What?
Leo, we're huntsman.
Are you okay?
- [Leonardo] Of course.
Of course, sorry.
Just haven't had my evening coffee.
- [Qrow] Look it's nice to see you
but we've got work to do.
Are we getting support
from the council or not?
- Mom?
- Raven.
- They really are magic.
- If you're going to shoot me, shoot me.
That was insulting.
- What are you doing here?
- I could ask you the same thing.
You've been scheming little brother.
Planning to attack your own sister.
- Leo, what have you done?
- Leo did what any sane person
would in his position.
He looked at all the information
he had in front of him,
assessed the situation, and made a choice.
And it seems you all have too.
- You have the spring maiden.
- I do.
- Then hand her over
and lets work together.
We can beat Salem.
- All the time spent spying for Ozpin
and you still have no idea
what you're dealing with.
There is no beating Salem.
- You're wrong.
We've done things most
people would call impossible.
And I know the only reason
we were able to do it
is because we didn't do it alone.
We had people to teach us.
People to help us.
We had each other.
Work with us.
At least I know we'll have a better chance
if we try together.
Please.
- You sound just like your mother.
- Ruby!
- Hello boys and girls.
- Cinder.
- C'mon guys.
Is that anyway to greet your old friends?
- Everybody stay calm.
- Oh no.
- The white fang is prepping demolition
and securing the school grounds.
No one's getting in, but
no one's getting out.
- Once the charges are set,
move back to perimeter watch.
Tonight, Haven falls.
- This was all just a trap?
- It appears so.
- Raven, tell me, how long
have you been with them?
- Aw, don't take it
personally little bird.
Your sister was a recent addition.
The lion on the other hand...
Entrance into the Vytal
Festival was a real treat.
But Leonardo's been sending
Salem all sorts of information
for a very, very long time.
Isn't that right, Professor?
- Stop it.
- It was you.
You sit on the Mistral Council.
You had information on every huntsman
and huntress in the kingdom.
And you gave it all to her.
I couldn't find any of them
because you let her kill them.
- Aw now, don't beat yourself
up over it Lionheart.
I'm sure Tyrian and Hazel would have found
them on their own eventually.
- What is wrong with you?
How can you be so broken inside?
To take so many lives, and then come here
and rub in in our faces like
it's something to be proud of.
- Jaune...
- All with that damn smile on your face!
- Everybody stay calm.
- I'm gonna make you pay for what you did.
Do you hear me?
- Kid.
- [Jaune] Well, say something!
- Who are you again?
- Jaune!
- You're not getting near her.
- Hey there blondie,
I'm thinking you owe me
an apology for my leg.
Don't you think?
- Take out the Aeris.
Don't bother wasting your power,
she's not worth it.
- Running away was one thing.
But this, you've crossed a line.
- Sorry brother, sometimes
family disappoints you like that.
- We're not family anymore.
- Were we ever?
- I thought so, but I guess I was wrong.
- Lets see what the
Schnee name really means.
- I'm more than a name.
- Hmm, prove it.
- I don't wish to fight either of you.
- Nor I you.
- But we will if you're with her.
- Very well then.
- Young man, I don't know who you are
or what you think you're doing.
But for your sake, I
suggest you leave, now.
I'm warning you!
That's enough.
Ozpin?
- Not quite!
- This can't be, I knew you'd be back
but you made it here, you found Qrow.
How?
- [Ozpin's Voiceover]
Leo, what happened to you?
- Wait, you can't of
had this form for long.
You're not really Ozpin right now.
A boy, a child.
If I deliver you to Salem, he'll
have to be pleased with me.
And I can finally get out of all this.
I can finally be free.
- What do I do?
[Ozpin's Voiceover] Fight?
- Don't think I'm going to
let you take the easy way out.
- I'm starting to remember you.
You're the dense one that can't tell
when he's out of his league.
- Why are you doing this?
Salem...
- I don't care about Salem,
but I owe Cinder everything.
You want to fight her that bad?
Be my guest.
- Are you gonna let her die too?
- Stop messing with me!
- If that's what you want.
- No!
- Did you think you actually
had a chance against me?
You?
You're just a failure with a death wish.
- If I die buying them
time, then it's worth it.
They're the ones that matter.
- You think so?
- No.
No!