Back to the fairytale, back to the show
Back to the wall and there's nowhere to go
Hopeless and desperate, all paths adverse
Things looking bleak, and they're bound to get worse
Helpless and doomed, and there's no way to win
Goals unachievable, faith running thin
Lost and forlorn, impossible odds
That's when you'll learn you've been messing with gods!
Send in your grimm, tear off my limb
Strike me with bolts of lightning
I won't die
The battle seems unwinnable, but all we need's a miracle
We're going up we'll never be denied!
Can't wish away the dismal days
Can't bring back what is gone
Won't waste more tears on yesteryears
Instead we'll carry on
We'll win, we're sure we will endure
And though our goal is far
We'll be the ones to touch the sun
The Triumph will be ours!
- [Blake] Okay.
Are you ready?
- I beat up on giant monsters
and robots more than once,
I think I can handle
getting a few signatures.
- Your chieftain needs you!
Your people need you!
Please, join the fight and
help us save Haven Academy!
- Are you kidding me?
We'd love to have someone
with your skills on our side!
- Mata!
Get back inside.
- [Mata] Mom!
- [Mother] You're not going anywhere!
- Huh?
Huh?
I don't get it!
How can they just sit
around and do nothing
with the White Fang
getting ready to attack?
- Because not everyone is like you and me.
The Faunus here in
Menagerie, the ones that
weren't born on the
island, moved here because
they were tired of fighting, of having to
struggle constantly.
Menagerie is filled with
people that just want
to be left alone and
here we are, asking them
to put the rest of the
world before themselves.
- I guess I never really
thought about it like that.
- The problem is,
whatever happens at Haven
is going to affect them
whether they like it or not.
If Adam gets his way and
Haven falls, it's only going
to make things worse for the Faunus.
Everywhere.
- Adam.
He's the guy you used to work with?
- Yes.
- Sorry, forget I brought it up.
- No, it's okay.
Have you ever met someone
and thought to yourself,
They are the personification of this word.
- Uh.
- Okay, well, I remember
getting to know Ruby
and thinking, This girl is
the embodiment of purity.
After a while, I saw Weiss was defiance.
And Yang was strength.
- What am I?
- Jury's still out on that one,
but I'm leaning towards earnest.
- Ah!
- At first I thought Adam was justice
then I thought he was passion.
But over time, I realized I was wrong.
He wasn't any of those things.
He was spite.
Not hatred, not rage, spite.
He won't accept equality, only suffering
for what he feels the world did to him,
and his way of thinking
is dangerously contagious.
That's what worries me about Ilia.
She's not like Adam, not yet at least,
but I don't know how long that will last.
- She was your friend, huh?
- She was.
Her chameleon traits meant
she could pass as human.
She could've lived a
normal life if she wanted,
but she didn't.
I always admired that.
She lost her family in
a mining accident when
she was young and she
joined the White Fang.
Like me, she was more
or less trained on the
road alongside other Faunus.
She learned to survive, to defend herself,
but as people like Sienna and Adam started
to gain a following, she
became more dangerous.
I guess I did too.
My parents tried to get
me to leave with them,
but I refused.
I had Adam and Ilia, after all.
- You know we're going to
have to face her eventually.
- I know.
- [Sun] So what are you going to do?
- I'm going to try and help
her the way you helped me.
- [Sun] Hm?
- You showed me that
sometimes you need to be there
for a friend, even when
they don't want you to be.
I was drowning in guilt and fear.
I tried to push you away,
but you didn't give up on me.
And I can't give up on Ilia.
It's about time I saved
my friends for once.
- [Ruby] You're really
getting better, huh?
Are you hungry?
It's almost dinnertime.
- [Oscar] Uh, yeah.
That sounds good.
I was about to call it a night anyway.
- So, you've never fought before?
- Just the occasional small Grimm.
Nothing like this, though.
- Wow.
You look like a natural.
- It's strange, I've
only had this cane for a
few weeks, but I feel like
I've had it for a lifetime.
Longer, even.
I sound like a crazy person.
- I mean, uh, yeah, just a little.
But at this pace, you'll
be combat ready in no time!
- Uh.
- [Ruby] Well, uh, I'll see you upstairs.
- [Oscar] How do you handle all of this?
- What do you mean?
- I'm scared.
I'm more scared than I've
ever been in my life,
than I ever thought was possible.
I always knew that I wanted
to be more than a farmhand,
but this?
Who would ask for this?
- We all went to Beacon because
we wanted to help people.
But, you're right.
None of us asked for this either.
We just have to press on and--
- How can you be so confident?
People have tried to kill you!
The world's about to go
to war all over again!
How are you okay with any of this?
- When Beacon fell, I
lost two of my friends.
Penny Polendina and Pyrrha Nikos.
I didn't know them for very
long, but that doesn't change
the fact that they were two of
the most kind-hearted people
I have ever met.
But that didn't save them.
Pyrrha thought that if
there was even the smallest
chance of helping someone then
it was a chance worth taking.
And because of that she
died fighting a battle
she knew she couldn't win.
And Penny was killed
just to make a statement.
- I'm sorry.
- I am scared, but not just for me.
What happened at Beacon
shows that Salem doesn't care
if you're standing against her or not.
She'll kill anybody and
that scares me most of all.
Pyrrha, Penny.
I'd be lying if I said
that it didn't hurt.
That I didn't think about them
every day since I lost them.
That I didn't wish I had
spent more time with them.
If it had been me instead,
I know they would have
kept fighting too, no
matter how dangerous it was.
So that's what I choose to do.
To keep moving forward.
C'mon, if we don't hurry,
Nora's gonna eat everything.
It wouldn't be the first time.
Hey, Oscar?
This isn't gonna be easy,
but the fact that you're
even trying says a lot about you.
You're braver than you think.
- [Ozpin] She really is
remarkable, isn't she?
- Yeah.
She must've been one of the
best Huntresses at Beacon, huh?
- [Ozpin] (chuckles) In some ways, yes.
But in many others no.
She has her quirks, her faults,
just like everyone else.
But she also possesses something
unquantifiable, a spark
that can inspire others even
in the darkest of times.
- This must be really hard on her too.
- [Ozpin] It most assuredly is.
- [Fennec] Your thoughts?
- [Corsac] Are of no significance.
If this is how High Leader
Taurus wishes to proceed
then we shall make it so.
- [Fennec] Of course, brother.
Still.
- Come in.
- Sister Ilia, thank
you for meeting with us.
- [Ilia] How may I be of assistance?
- Please, stand.
We have wonderful news.
- [Ilia] What is it?
- We finally received a
message from the Mistral
brotherhood.
The operation was a success.
Adam Taurus has claimed his place as the
High Leader of the White Fang.
- Good.
And Sienna?
- Buried with honor.
The other branches of
the Fang have been given
the story that was agreed upon.
- A necessary sacrifice.
We won't forget everything she did for us.
- [Fennec] Indeed.
- [Corsac] Your maturity
and understanding in
regards to this matter is appreciated
and it is why we've summoned
you here this evening.
- The White Fang is experiencing
a transitional period.
- Growth requires change.
- And change can be painful.
- If it's for the betterment of the Faunus
then it's a pain we can endure.
What's our next mission?
- [Corsac] Containment.
With the CCT towers still inoperable,
we have the luxury of control
over the flow of information.
- [Fennec] News of Adam's
ascension has yet to reach
Menagerie, but when it does,
the citizens of Kuo Kuana
will undoubtedly react
poorly now that the chieftain
has spoken out against us.
- It's my fault the Belladonnas
had any ground to stand on.
- Do not concern yourself
with past failures, Ilia.
Focus on the future.
We have an opportunity for redemption.
- What do you need me to do?
- The Belladonnas are the
only remaining threat to
Adam's assault on Haven Academy.
- And so they must be silenced.
- Silenced?
- [Corsac] Like Sienna.
They stand in the way of
true progress for our people.
- [Fennec] We would never put
such a burden on you alone
of course.
Your brothers and sisters
will be at your side,
but your relationship
with their daughter makes
you an integral part of this operation.
- Blake?
- We know how close you
were with young Blake.
Rest assured, High Leader
Taurus has requested
she be taken alive, but
we cannot risk having her
present to defend her family.
- But, the people of Menagerie--
- Will come to understand
what happens to those
who speak out against the White Fang.
- And will be left
without a leader until our
victory is complete.
- A necessary sacrifice, Sister Ilia.
- She's right to worry about the citizens.
It's possible they may come
to see Ghira as a martyr.
- It is a risk we must
take for our High Leader.
- I will not allow them to ruin this!
The Belladonna name has
brought me nothing, but grief!
You've done well in finding the deserter.
Bring her to me, alive.
But not before you've
slaughtered her family.
I have a promise to keep.
- He seems unwell.
- He carries with him a tremendous burden.
- Are we sure he is the one to lead us?
- For now.
We must do what is best for the Faunus.
- Yes?
Brother Yuma.
Did you see to Ghira's messenger?
- He rests beneath the waves
along with his warning.
- Then all is well.