Back to the fairytale, back to the show
Back to the wall and there's nowhere to go
Hopeless and desperate, all paths adverse
Things looking bleak, and they're bound to get worse
Helpless and doomed, and there's no way to win
Goals unachievable, faith running thin
Lost and forlorn, impossible odds
That's when you'll learn you've been messing with gods!
Send in your grimm, tear off my limb
Strike me with bolts of lightning
I won't die
The battle seems unwinnable, but all we need's a miracle
We're going up we'll never be denied!
Can't wish away the dismal days
Can't bring back what is gone
Won't waste more tears on yesteryears
Instead we'll carry on
We'll win, we're sure we will endure
And though our goal is far
We'll be the ones to touch the sun
The Triumph will be ours!
Weiss!
Ruby, get up!
Get up! We need you!
You’re lettin’ that boy make a fool of you.
That’s not just a boy!
It’s Ozpin.
He’s already reincarnated!
Ozpin?
Ruby! You-
OZPIN!
Oh no…
You thought you could hide from me?!
You’ll pay for what you did,
you’ll die over and over again!
Do- do we fight?
No, run!
Ozpin is here?!
Is that a problem?
I’m not sure,
but right now we got the upper hand.
Let’s not waste it.
Leo! Open the path to the vault!
Stop them! We’ve got your team covered!
You wanna get to them?
You’re going to have to get through all of us.
Ren, talk to me!
This is bad.
No, no, no, no, not again!
Weiss, c’mon, please!
Make sure they leave Ruby alive.
This won’t take long.
Oscar.
No!
Oscar!
I told you, no!
Please, let me take over! I can handle him!
You told me I needed to fight for myself!
So I will.
This is not your fight!
What does that mean?
Why is he so upset with us?
He didn’t tell you my tale, did he, boy?
I thought you looked familiar,
to think that evil was inside you when our paths first crossed.
Your blood won’t be on my hands,
it’ll be on his.
What was he talking about?
Tell him, Ozpin! Tell him how you killed her!
Her?
Gretchen Rainart was Hazel’s sister.
Despite her brother’s wishes, she enrolled at Beacon Academy to become a Huntress...
...and tragically lost her life on a training mission.
Hazel… holds me responsible.
Please, let me fight.
I know Hazel. He’s wounded in a way that cannot be healed.
You know now!
You can forgive me for what I’m about to do.
Did she know?
Did she know the risk of being a Huntress?
She was only a child!
She wasn’t ready!
She made a choice!
A choice to put others before herself!
So do I.
Then you’ve chosen death!
I’m sorry.
What?
OZPII-I-I-IIN!
She’s hardly breathing.
I...
I don’t know what we can do…
No, it wasn’t supposed to be like this!
Please!
I can’t lose anyone else…
Are you nervous, girl?
The first Maiden in...
- why, I’m not sure anyone knows how many years -
...is about to open a vault.
I would say it’s quite an exciting time.
Don’t you feel honored?
No,
I’m not concerned with any of this.
All I care about is my tribe - my family.
This is a burden, not an honor.
You’ve conditioned her quite well, Raven.
Hm, it’s certainly grander than Beacon’s.
I wonder what the extra effort was for.
Can we please not linger?
After you.
Huh?
Wha- what’s happening?
Weiss!
What happened?!
What’s going on?!
I think she’s going to be okay! She seems to be stabilizing.
Whatever you’re doing, don’t stop!
I won’t.
Good.
Oscar needs help.
I’m on it.
Jaune and Weiss still need cover!
No one’s gonna touch ‘em.
Okay.
Make it happen, RNJR!
Thanks, sis.
You okay?
No.
I’m angry.
Having fun?
Vernal, stay focused.
Oh, come now, Raven,
let her enjoy this.
It’s a once-in-a-lifetime experience.
How does this work?
Once the Spring Maiden places her hand on the door,
...it will open.
For you...
...and only you.
Then I will walk into the vault, and retrieve the Relic.
No one else.
Is that clear?
Yes.
It doesn’t matter to us.
Let’s get this over with.
Alright then.
Vernal,
when you’re ready.
You know,
I’ve heard so many stories about you, Raven.
They say you’re a cunning leader,
that you’re strong,
that you’re clever.
It’s a shame that they’re wrong…
Vernal!
It’s nothing personal, dear.
You’re just not worthy of such power.
But I am.
So I will take…
what is mine.
Wha- what is this?
Where’s the power?!
You won’t find it,
because Vernal isn’t the Spring Maiden…
I am!