- There.
- My queen.
- [Salem] Cinder.
When I chose you as my
vessel for the maidens,
I put my trust in you.
(footsteps approaching)
So, I trust
that you wouldn't possibly
return to me empty-handed.
- [Cinder] The Relic of Knowledge.
I took it right from
under Ironwood's nose.
- [Tyrian] Outsmarting the general
speaks less to your intellect
and more to his.
(mechanical whizzing of tail)
After all, you were outsmarted
by those children first.
- And, according to radio chatter,
that same general and his
forces outsmarted you.
A shame Watts never made it back.
- I'm afraid the doctor
was a necessary sacrifice.
I do hope this little one
doesn't become another.
- Who is she?
- Neopolitan has some
very useful abilities
and has proven to be a valuable asset.
- [Salem] Hm, you certainly
do enjoy collecting assets.
- Cinder.
(rushed footsteps)
You're here! I knew you'd co-
[Cinder] - Quiet!
- [Tyrian] So devoted to
someone so incompetent.
While the good doctor and I
were advancing the will of our goddess;
dismembering the very body
of this kingdom...
you were merely atoning for past failures.
- Polendina's creation
interfered with the transfer
of the Winter Maiden power...
but now I know she has it.
And once I return to Atlas,
it won't take long to
finish what I started.
That power will be mine.
- I've given no such command.
- Ma'am, now is the time to-
- [Salem] This game is
not yours to win, Cinder,
it's mine.
Just because you're more
valuable to me than a pawn,
does not make you a player.
Everything is already in motion.
All you need concern yourself with
is your ability to act when I tell you to.
- Of course.
Without you I am nothing.
- Huh?
(gasps)
Thank you.
- [Man] Heads up.
(spaceship whizzing loudly)
- Need a lift?
- [Oscar] I was stupid to think
the General would listen.
Every choice I've made was the wrong one,
and now...
- We all did what we thought was best.
I'm just glad you're alright.
- Yeah, yeah, I see you.
- [Joanna] Inside! Hurry!
- [May] I know, Sector 3
is going to need to most help.
I'm sending backup your way right now.
Fiona, do you copy?
We need transport from
Sector 3 to the crater.
- [Fiona] Copy!
- When we heard you went off after
Ironwood on your own, we...
- How did you end up down in the slums?
- It's a... (sighs) long story.
I get the feeling there's
been a few of those tonight.
- [Ozpin] You're not going to tell them?
- [Oscar] You and I
aren't done talking yet.
Where's Qrow?
- We don't know.
The last we heard he
was with Robyn, but...
- Alright, your friend is back now.
You ready to work?
The largest Grimm hoard ever
seen is hovering over the tundra
and out there is a city
full of people with no heat,
and from what you told us,
no more military protection.
And while we're happy
to give guys a place
to lie low for a while...
It's time to get those people some help.
- How? Ironwood is stopping
all evacuations to Atlas.
And we can't get them out of the city
with Salem's forces surrounding us.
- The crater. Beneath Atlas.
It's not safe but it's warm,
and with everyone in one place
we can do a better job protecting them.
May can send you where you're needed most.
We've got to get everyone
down into that crater
before nightfall.
In the slums, we might have a chance.
- We're never going to sleep again,
I just know it.
- Either you're helping...
or you're baggage.
- We need to get out there
and do what we can for Mantle.
- [Ruby] We need to do
what we can for everyone.
What about Amity? And telling
the world about Salem?
We can't do this alone.
We need help!
- [Blake] Ruby's right.
The Happy Huntresses are
handling the evacuation
better than we could.
And there's a bigger picture.
- But Amity isn't even finished.
It was still under construction.
- Doctor? What would you
need to launch Amity now?
- Uh
- We've made decent
progress on construction
and fuel collection,
all potentially manageable, but...
Amity was designed so that
it couldn't launch itself
without first being granted clearance
from General Ironwood's terminal.
- Ruby, there is no way Ironwood
will cooperate with us.
- But he doesn't have to.
We just need the green light
from his terminal, right?
- You want to go back to the Academy?
- [Pietro] Actually...there
is more than one terminal.
The one in his office and...
one in the main Atlesian
Military Compound...
at the base of the city.
You'd have to get into the compound somehow,
then get inside the operations room
and then... hoo boy...
I might need to think
about this some more.
- And just to clarify,
this is the easy option?
- What you're saying is it can't be done.
It's pointless.
And even if you got the message out,
there's no guarantee help would come.
- It's not pointless!
Atlas is only Salem's current target.
She's not hiding anymore
and once she's done here
she'll move on to the rest of Remnant.
We need to warn them!
- [Yang] Ruby... when we came here,
we said we'd follow your lead...
but things haven't exactly worked out.
I just...
- There are people here
who need us right now.
That's something we can actually do.
- [Nora] But this isn't about just Atlas.
Ruby's right.
It's about all of Remnant.
They need to know in Vacuo,
in Mistral, in Vale, what's coming...
So they can prepare.
- Okay. Okay...
Then let's go for both.
Get Amity up and running,
and evacuate Mantle.
- But that's how Salem got
this far- by dividing us.
We have to stick together!
- No. What Salem wants is to
turn us against each other.
Just like this.
Jaune has a point.
We can work separately
and still be united.
- [Penny] Or... let me
take the relic to Salem...
and maybe she will call off
her attack on the Kingdom.
- I don't think we can trust
Salem to actually do that.
And the moment she uses the
staff to create anything else...
Atlas falls onto Mantle.
- Nobody's turning you over to anybody.
I think that's the one
thing we could all agree on.
- Okay. Then I guess
we're going to Atlas.
Can you help us get to that terminal?
- I... suppose someone needs
to help you bypass security.
- [Penny] I'll go.
- [Pietro] Penny, we can't risk-
- I'll go.
- Do what you've got to do.
I'm going out there to
see what I could do.
- [Pietro] Yang.
(keys chiming)
Go by the pharmacy.
I was developing some new
tool for you all before...
this happened.
You're going to need them.
- [Ren] Nora?
- [Nora] I'm going with Ruby.
- [Ren] But what about Mantle?
- [Nora] Oh, I'm saving Mantle!
Because I actually believe we can do this.
- Hey, we're still united.
- I hope so.
- [Maria] (over ear-piece) I can get Pietro
out to Amity to prepare,
but that doesn't answer
how we're getting all of you up to Atlas.
- I might actually have an idea for...
- [Ironwood] Hello, Penny.
I'm worried for your safety.
Tell me where you are
and I'll have you picked up right away.
Atlas needs you, Penny.
Salem is here.
- She's not going anywhere
until you change your mind about Mantle.
There's still a chance for Remnant to be-
- [Ironwood] Mantle... You're
still worried about Mantle?!
Remnant is doomed, Ruby!
Unless we leave, Salem will destroy Atlas
and with it, any hope humanity has left.
We need to think about the future.
If she makes it through our defenses,
everything that follows
will be on your hands.
- [Crewmate] Sir, the
prisoners have arrived.
They're being processed in Stockade B.
- [Winter] Qrow and Robyn?
- Could you give us the room, please?
- I'll be fine.
- Thank you, Winter.
I don't know what I would do without you.
I've never-
no one has ever seen a Grimm
force this large before.
The city's hard light shields will hold,
but not forever.
- What will you do... sir?
- [Atlas Technician] Wait, you can't be in here!
- [Sleet] This is absurd! Let us through!
- I'm going to do everything
I can to defend this Kingdom.
- What in God's name do you
think you're doing James?!
- No matter the cost.
- [Sleet] And what's this about martial law?
have you lost your damn mind?!
Are you (inaudible)
- I have questions for you.
But first I need the one
who could show me how.
Bring him to me.
We said goodbye
To all the things we loved
Gave up our lives
Just to find that it was not enough
We leapt in faith
Left our solitude, our carefree peace
What we thought would change the world
Was just a childish dream
We fail to stop our own demise
The tragic end's before our eyes
Hope has no place here
Maybe the path that leads our way home will finally clear
Maybe the end we tried to avoid is already here
Some roses will never bloom
Some dreams will rot on the vine
Some lives will end much too soon
Some evil will never ever die
Some wars will not end in peace
Some heroes choose the wrong side
Sometimes it's worth it all to risk the fall
And fight for every life