We said goodbye
To all the things we loved
Gave up our lives
Just to find that it was not enough
We leapt in faith
Left our solitude, our carefree peace
What we thought would change the world
Was just a childish dream
We fail to stop our own demise
The tragic end's before our eyes
Hope has no place here
Maybe the path that leads our way home will finally clear
Maybe the end we tried to avoid is already here
Some roses will never bloom
Some dreams will rot on the vine
Some lives will end much too soon
Some evil will never ever die
Some wars will not end in peace
Some heroes choose the wrong side
Sometimes it's worth it all to risk the fall
And fight for every life
- I'll take her.
Come now.
You're to make sure the laundry is folded,
the dishes are spotless
and the floors are clean
enough to eat off of.
- Food?
Now hurry and get to your chores.
The floor looks filthy.
Clean the linens, sweep the floors
Shut your mouth and do your chores
Scrub the dishes in the sink
No one said that you should think
Shine the silver, wash the clothes
And when you finished, darn the socks
Draw my bath, fetch my slippers
Fill my glass and rub my feet
Hurry up, you're so slow
You're no good I hope you know
That your life is of no use
And the truth is that no one's ever loved you
- Wow.
- [Step Sister] You missed a spot.
- Now that wasn't very ladylike, was it?
I suggest you remember your place.
Say it.
- Without you, I am nothing.
- [Rhodes] Alright what gives?
Someone took my damn sword.
- [Step Sister] I apologize
for the inconvenience.
- [Step Sister] We'll help you look for it.
- [Rhodes] Now that's not yours, is it?
I'm not here to hurt you.
I've seen you around and
I think it's safe to say
you're not getting the
most fair treatment.
Yeah?
I can't really blame you
for what you're thinking.
- You don't know what I'm-
- But hurting them isn't going
to make your life any better.
You can run,
but you're gonna be running
for the rest of your life
or you could find
another way to handle it.
- [Cinder] Like you?
You can do whatever you want,
go wherever you want.
- Ah, how old are you?
- 10.
- And you want to be like us?
You want to be a Huntress?
Then we've got about seven years.
- For what?
- To train you for the Huntsman exam.
Just a few more years
and you won't need your
guardian's permission.
You'll be free.
- Mom, come quick, we found something.
It's Cinder, she has a weapon.
- Hello?
Anyone?
- You're right.
Without you I am nothing.
But because of you, I am everything.
- [Rhodes] Cinder.
- I won't have to run now.
- That's all you'll ever do.
Silence fuels the deadly cries
Ripped apart by knives in lovers' lies
Curse my innocence goodbye
Take my hand then take my life
- You're awake.
I was so worried.
How are you feeling?
- You, you brought me back here.
We failed.
- Cinder, you were hurt.
I was just trying to help.
- [Mercury] I think she's had enough help.
Besides, she went against our queen.
I'd be careful who you back.
- Cinder's hunch was right.
If we'd had support
then maybe we would've-
- Would you stop trying
to protect her already?
She doesn't care about you.
- [Cinder] Both of you, get out.
I'll let you know when you're needed next.
- Yeah about that,
Salem's got other plans for me.
I'm not gonna be taking
orders from you anymore.
She wants everyone on the bridge.
Something big is about to happen.
- [Oz] I'd like to express again
that this is my burden to bear, not yours.
His grudge is with me.
- [Oscar] No, it'll be even worse.
He's holding back with me.
I can tell.
- [Oz] I understand, I do,
but you've done so much already.
The least I can do is give you a break
and try to get us out of here.
- We can't leave yet.
This is our chance.
- Hmm, maybe you've
taken one too many hits.
- Salem, she knows she can't take on
the whole world at once.
So she doesn't.
She has her followers work their way in
sabotaging us from the inside out.
Maybe we should do the same.
- [Oz] We certainly
are similar, you and I.
Maybe we have been presented
with an opportunity.
- Great.
- [Oz] Oscar, please.
- You don't need to fight this war, kid.
Tell me what I need and we can be done.
- Hello Hazel.
- Coward.
All this time, it could have been you,
but you let him suffer.
Now tell us how this damned lamp works.
The boy has suffered enough.
- Why do you follow her?
I know.
I know how you see me.
But her, look at what she does.
How is she the answer?
Why not stop her?
- Salem can't be stopped.
She's a force of nature.
I've seen it first hand.
But you, you send children to their deaths
for a cause that you know
has no victory, no end.
- Someone has to try.
Salem isn't a force of nature
because Salem can be fought
unless she brings the relics
together if that happens.
- [Salem] Ozma
You have wonderful timing
The show is about to begin.
We have good news.
Tyrian has heard from
our dear colleague Watts.
Although he remains in captivity,
it seems that he has worked with Ironwood
to gain some control
over the puppet masquerading
as the Winter Maiden.
I suppose he remains useful after all.
Speaking of which, Cinder,
you choose to disobey
my specific instructions
just to fail again.
And I've realized,
it's all my fault.
You've fought your whole life
unwaveringly for what you want
and here I am holding you back
instead of lifting you up.
You deserve so much more
than I've given you.
Go to Atlas, recover Watts.
He can lead you to the girl.
Whether you or my Hound get to her first,
you will finally have
the Winter Maiden's power
and I will have my staff.
- You'll only be helping
her bring about the end
for all of you.
- You're too late.
- [Elm] Did the hack just not work?
How do we even know we can trust Watts?
- [Vine] We have confirmed
visual of her leaving Amity.
She appeared to be malfunctioning.
- [Elm] This is why I
don't trust technology.
Now we're wasting our time
searching for broken junk.
- Enough!
You're Atlas elite, act like it.
- [Marrow] Um ma'am, we're picking
up an open comms broadcast.
- Play it.
- [Jaune] It's headed straight for Mantle.
I repeat, a large mass of Grimm
is headed straight for Mantle.
Please anyone.
- Great, you guys.
- Did you hear our message?
It's right there.
We need to hurry.
Where's Penny?
Are you serious right now?
There are people in danger.
There are people in danger because you kids are acting selfish and-
- It's time.
Silence fuels the deadly cries
Ripped apart by knives in lovers' lies
Curse my innocence goodbye
Take my hand then take my life