We said goodbye
To all the things we loved
Gave up our lives
Just to find that it was not enough
We leapt in faith
Left our solitude, our carefree peace
What we thought would change the world
Was just a childish dream
We fail to stop our own demise
The tragic end's before our eyes
Hope has no place here
Maybe the path that leads our way home will finally clear
Maybe the end we tried to avoid is already here
Some roses will never bloom
Some dreams will rot on the vine
Some lives will end much too soon
Some evil will never ever die
Some wars will not end in peace
Some heroes choose the wrong side
Sometimes it's worth it all to risk the fall
And fight for every life
- [Penny] Dad?
- Penny?
- This does not seem
like a very good idea.
- There is a difference
between a good idea
and our best idea.
Sadly, we don't have time for much else.
We have enough systems up
and running to broadcast our message
and keep Amity in atmospheric orbit.
But our thrusters just aren't capable
of reaching our target
altitude on their own.
- Ha, fortunately, we're sitting
on a couple hundred tons of thrust.
- Once we passed into broadcasting range,
we'll activate stabilizers,
re-establish global communications,
and boost the message we've recorded out
into the rest of the world.
After that, (chuckles) we
just have to pilot Amity
away from all this mess.
- But what if no one is
able to come and help Atlas?
If I stay behind, I could maybe...
- [Pietro] Penny, we are not
having this conversation again.
I'm your father and I'm telling you
that you belong on Amity.
- Yes, sir.
- Don't you think Penny
has had enough people
telling her what to do?
- Prepare for launch, please.
I'm moving us into position.
All systems are ready.
Penny?
Amity is requesting launch access-
now.
Oh yes, it worked.
(laughs)
Oh, I didn't have time
to install seat belts,
so I'd advise you to hang on.
- And where do you think you're going?
- Penny, no!
- It's time.
- I was hoping your friends would be here.
But it looks like they left
you to do all the work.
(laughs) You're just a tool to be used!
- You do not know what
you are talking about.
- Get away from her, you-
Stupid, clunky, machine.
Hmm.
Huh?
- [Emerald] Let's go.
- And what do you want?
- Please, please, please!
Yes!
We're drifting.
- Huh?
- Hmph.
- [Penny] No!
Why are you doing this?
Why serve someone like Salem?
- I don't serve anyone.
And you wouldn't either,
if you weren't built that way.
- That is not...
I choose to fight for
people who care about me.
- Cinder!
Ahhhh.
No no no!
No!
I know I can't beat you,
But I can fill that thing full of holes
before you take me down.
Get us out of here.
Hurry.
- Dad!
Are you okay?
- The stabilizer was damaged.
We've missed our window.
At this rate,
We're likely to drift into,
touching down just north-
- I can fix this.
- What?
- Our message is only a few minutes long.
I can try and hold Amity in place until-
- [Pietro] Absolutely not!
You're in no condition
to do something like this.
Even just the temperature out there-
- It is our only option.
- She is right Pietro.
We have to remember the big picture-
- I don't care about the big picture!
I care about my daughter.
I lost you before.
Are you asking me to
go through that again?
No.
I want the chance to
watch you live your life.
- But Dad,
I am trying to.
- Right.
- Come on, Penny.
- Yes! Atta girl!
- Okay, go ahead.
- Um, uh.
Hi.
My name is Ruby Rose.
I'm a Huntress.
And if we've done everything right,
then I'm talking to all
of Remnant right now.
Dr. Polendina can explain more later,
But right now you all need to know
that the kingdom of Atlas is under attack.
Things are dire and we need help.
But please, try not to panic.
This isn't some new enemy
or invading kingdom.
This is a force we've faced before.
For centuries...
Salem.
[Neptune] Dude.
The White Fang , Atlesian Drones
Even the Grimm themselves
have all been controlled and
manipulated by her,
in order to tear down
the Huntsmen Academies.
I know the idea of
the maidens and relics seems...
well...
crazy,
but I promise Professor Goodwitch of Beacon
and Headmaster Theodore of Shade
can verify all of this.
They might even be able to
help organize a way to fight back,
but,
sadly,
General Ironwood can no longer be trusted.
- It seems Polendina's proxy trick worked,
and that's good news for us.
Penny's blades operate
on the same principle
as Amity in the launch terminal.
In order for her to control them all,
they need to communicate with one another.
- [Ruby Rose] We didn't have time
to prepare for Salem.
But now you do!
Just because she can't be destroyed,
doesn't mean she can't be beaten.
If she really was unstoppable,
she wouldn't have acted
with such caution until now.
She knows we're a threat!
So even if we-
even if Atlas falls,
you can't give up!
- [Pietro] Penny! What's
going on out there?
- I, (grunts) I do not know.
- I hope Amity town will help
bring us all together.
Because, in the end,
That's how we'll win.
- No! No, come back!
- Penny, you've done enough, sweetheart.
Get back inside!
We can ride out on Amity together.
- No!
I - I have to go!
The vault.
No!
Dad!
- [Pietro] Penny! What is happening?
Please, baby, say something.
- [Penny] I love you.
- Penny! (cries)
Penny.
- Global comms just went back down.
- And Penny isn't responding.
What did you do?
- Exactly what she asked.
It's possible Penny's systems
may have been rebooting.
As for the tower,
well, perhaps Pietro isn't the genius
you thought-
- We're not waiting.
You're going to find her.
Winter.
- Sir?
- Until Penny either responds
or is standing in front of that vault,
we can not assume her status.
Take the Ace Ops. I want constant updates.
Get him back to his cell.
- With pleasure.
- That was the broadcast.
Why did we lose signal?
- There's another one.
I think it's just up ahead.
What - is this?
- It's Grimm.
A river of Grimm-
heading straight for the kingdom.