We said goodbye
To all the things we loved
Gave up our lives
Just to find that it was not enough
We leapt in faith
Left our solitude, our carefree peace
What we thought would change the world
Was just a childish dream
We fail to stop our own demise
The tragic end's before our eyes
Hope has no place here
Maybe the path that leads our way home will finally clear
Maybe the end we tried to avoid is already here
Some roses will never bloom
Some dreams will rot on the vine
Some lives will end much too soon
Some evil will never ever die
Some wars will not end in peace
Some heroes choose the wrong side
Sometimes it's worth it all to risk the fall
And fight for every life
- [Ironwood] Be ready for anything.
We don't know what state Penny is in.
- If any of those brats have
the nerve to come with her,
we put them down immediately.
The General gave his terms.
No more games.
Is there a problem?
- Just, retracing the
steps that led us here.
- What is it, Sir?
- Qrow and Robyn, they're
in the academy hanger.
- Trying to stop the payload?
- Or just looking for a way out.
- Not going to happen.
I've been waiting to take
my shot at those two.
Let's go, Ace Ops.
- But someone needs to
stay here with the General.
- I'll stay.
We lose the payload,
we lose our leverage.
- She's right.
Contain it.
Now.
- Sir, this course of action--
- I hope you're not going
to try to talk me out of it.
- No, Sir.
I don't think that's possible.
- I didn't think you'd
actually come alone.
I expected at least some
resistance from your friends.
- I don't want anyone else to die.
I must open the Vault.
- You've done the right thing.
- I have.
Feels weird.
It's OK
In time you will grow
But that doesn't mean
You're not already whole
Mistakes that you've made
Will stay in the past
Redemption is yours
If you follow that path
- [Marrow] Stay!
Oh, just hold on, stay tough
Be strong and hit stuff
- [Qrow] Sorry guys, but we don't wanna fight.
- We didn't wanna drop Atlas either,
but we've all had to make
some tough calls, huh?
Go!
Move to phase two.
- [Nora] She has to go to the Vault.
- [Ruby] That's actually a risk
we haven't considered.
- We've been so worried about
keeping the Vault closed
that we never considered
using what's inside.
- The Staff of Creation.
- Maybe we could use it to save Penny
and get everyone in Atlas
and Mantle back to safety.
- Well, you'll never guess
who I just heard from.
- So, you're not arresting me?
- No.
Ironwood's got to be stopped.
- Then, why did you hit me?
- Because you were about to get killed
if I didn't do something.
- What are you doing?
(sighs)
- What I should've done ages ago,
getting in touch with my sister.
We're going to need help.
- Huh?
- Speaking of help.
- [Weiss] So, we've got people
trapped in Atlas and Mantle
that we can't evacuate
unless we use the Staff,
which is located inside the Vault.
If we open the Vault, Penny terminates.
If Ironwood gets wind of any of this,
he blows up Mantle.
- There's something else to consider.
Once the Staff creates anything else,
the city drops.
Atlas has enough natural Gravity Dust
to keep it from plummeting immediately,
but, well, nobody's going
to want to be around
when it touches down.
- Okay, then let's use the Staff
to teleport everyone to safety.
Maybe even to another kingdom.
- We can't just wave it like a magic wand
and make our problems go away.
And we haven't even told you about him.
- Who?
- The spirit in the Staff.
Like Jinn but, well, he's a character.
He can build you anything,
but only if you can explain to him how.
Like any craftsman, he'll need blueprints.
Some sort of reference.
It'll help if we have real
world examples to show him.
- I've already gone
through the city layouts
for the SDC evacuation.
Maybe I can help?
- There's still James
and his bomb to consider.
- Oh, I've got a plan for that.
- [Weiss] So, that takes care of phase one.
- [Ruby] Meanwhile, the real Penny
goes to the Vault with help.
- [Oscar] I blasted a hole through
the bottom of Atlas
and I highly doubt they've
had time for repairs.
That should take you straight to it.
All of that,
is the easy part.
- [Ruby] As soon as Penny opens the door,
we go through, grab the Staff,
and stop her termination.
- Just hang in there, Penny.
Okay?
- It seems someone has come
to engage my creative wiles!
All I'll say is, it had better be worth it
after my last project.
A floating city?
(scoffs) How pedestrian.
- Hi, um, Mr. Ambrosius?
Sir, listen, it's about our friend.
She's- she's dying.
- I'm going to go ahead
and assume that you know
it's against the rules for me
to bring people back from dead so -
- That's not what we want.
She's not your typical girl.
- So, she isn't!
I'd love to meet whoever did this.
Ah, I see.
There's something eating away at her.
I'm guessing you think you have
some clever plan to save her.
Just know, I will give you
exactly what you ask for
and I don't want any complaining
when it's not what you wanted.
- We brought her schematics.
We want you to make a new version of her
using her exact same robot parts.
- That was curiously worded, girl.
- An exact copy of her
would include the virus.
An exact copy of her without the virus
would cease to exist the
second you make something else,
and we kinda wanna keep her
around longer than that.
- (chuckling) You've done your homework.
- We want you to create
a new version of her,
using her existing robotic parts
taking the virus with them.
- Hmm.
Okay, but if I take the
robot parts out of her,
that would leave,
- Penny.
The girl who's always
been there underneath it.
- Hmm.
- You can't destroy,
it's against the rules.
But you wouldn't be destroying her.
Her soul is who she is.
- The mechanical parts are just extra.
- But a soul without a complete body,
what would be left?
- I don't know.
I guess you just have to get creative.
- (laughing) I suppose
I could do a little,
oh, add a touch of,
but if I do that,
how much of the old Penny would be my work
and how much would be her?
Just coming up to the surface.
This is all very exciting,
and very dangerous.
I don't know what the
results are going to be.
- We don't have any other options.
We believe in her.
- Then, ready yourselves
to witness my artistry!
It's done.
- I guess that's the signal then.
Seems like things are
moving forward in the Vault.
- Hopefully Penny is going to be okay.
- If Atlas is moving,
we need to get word out
before people panic.
- Meaning hurry!
- I know! I know!
Okay, this should be, um,
that did, uh, something?
- You're live.
- Everyone can see you.
- Oh!
Citizens of Atlas,
Mantle,
what we have to tell
you is very important.
Atlas is falling but--
Wait, what happened?
- It's dead.
The entire CCT, it just went down.
- And so did kingdom wide communications.
How?
- The bigger question
is, what do we do now?
- That boy said Atlas is falling.
Is that true?
- Yes. We're using the Staff
to get everyone to safety.
Salem can have the rubble.
We'll all be long gone.
- Are you, (buzzing)
are you going to leave me here?
- No.
When we're finished, we'll
move both of you to safety.
- Oh Winter, thank you.
I--
- Don't thank me.
It was Weiss's decision.
- Penny?
Are you okay?
- Do hugs always make you
feel this warm inside?
- Yes.
- Wow!
More!
- We should probably make
sure our theory works.
And start the evacuation.
- Ah!
Free to create and, oh,
it's you guys again.
- We're not done with you yet.
- Ugh, fine!
- Let's try the quick version.
Can you make a bunch of doorways in Atlas
that open at a single stop in Vacuo?
- Sure!
I'll just need coordinates
and specs for each door,
an explanation for bending space and time
to account for the much
greater traffic on one side,
and the single point of exit on the other.
- Okay, that's about what we expected.
So, we need to funnel everybody
through a central location first.
- You're going to have to tell me more
about this central location.
For starters, uh, where is it?
- Here. A place like these Vaults.
Wherever they are, they're
not part of Remnant.
Only accessible if you
know the right way in.
Seems like a safe enough place
for thousands of refugees.
- You kids are either smart
or much more foolish than you realize.
I'm going to need a reference?
- Oh, we've got one.
- [Weiss] People enter from Atlas
and Mantle on one side,
and leave on the other side,
with a one-way ticket to Vacuo.
- Well, everything appears to be in order.
You were quite thorough,
disappointingly so.
- So, it's done?
- Yeah.
- Oh, and one last point of clarification
about this central location of yours,
do not fall.
Okay, and with that dire warning.
- We did it!
- What now?
- We go to Vacuo,
all of us,
and hope that we've thought of everything.