We said goodbye
To all the things we loved
Gave up our lives
Just to find that it was not enough
We leapt in faith
Left our solitude, our carefree peace
What we thought would change the world
Was just a childish dream
We fail to stop our own demise
The tragic end's before our eyes
Hope has no place here
Maybe the path that leads our way home will finally clear
Maybe the end we tried to avoid is already here
Some roses will never bloom
Some dreams will rot on the vine
Some lives will end much too soon
Some evil will never ever die
Some wars will not end in peace
Some heroes choose the wrong side
Sometimes it's worth it all to risk the fall
And fight for every life
- Well, that was harrowing.
- We're not in the clear yet.
We still have to search this whole thing
and find Oscar before the
Ace Ops blow us to pieces.
- How are we supposed to find Oscar?
It's going to be like finding
a needle in a giant whale.
Why did we think this was a good idea?
- I, I might be able to help.
I can sense spikes of
people's emotions, I think.
It happened on Winter's ship.
If I focus my Aura, I can keep it up.
- Okay. That's new.
Maybe one of them is Oscar.
- I can sort of tell where
they are, but not who.
They're more or less in
the same area though.
Further in. I can lead.
- Hey, you don't have to drain yourself.
I can help too.
- Yeah, good thinking. Thanks.
- Well, lead the way.
- [Oscar] She brushed off
her bumps and bruises,
for nothing hurt worse than the
loneliness in her chest.
- [Ozpin] I recognize that,
The Girl Who Fell Through The World?
- I shouldn't be surprised
you're so familiar with fairytales.
- [Ozpin] I've lived
through my share of them.
How are you holding up?
- I thought the idea of
falling through Remnant
into a new world was exciting.
I never understood why she was so sad
when she finally made it back home.
But now it makes more sense.
- [Ozpin] She wasn't
the same girl anymore.
- Yeah.
- [Ozpin] I
think this plan to divide
might have run its course.
It's time we start
thinking about a way out.
Not having our cane certainly
limits the options, so.
- No, I don't like what
happens when we use magic.
Every time we use it, I
can feel us merging faster.
I'm not ready for that.
- [Ozpin] I don't blame you.
Honestly, I think you're
doing just fine on your own.
- [Winter] Listen up everyone.
We're keeping this LZ
clear for the payload
we're going to put aboard that thing.
If we can't hold this line,
it will continue to spit out
Grimm and we lose the city.
Is that understood?
- [All] Yes ma'am.
- You wouldn't happen to
know a tune for this, huh?
- I don't know that anybody does.
- [Vine] Another wave incoming.
Keep them back.
- But, they're just kids.
- You can hash out your issues later.
Right now, just kill Grimm.
- Why did you bring me here?
- I've been thinking about what you said.
If it's a lie and I took
that lie to Salem,
the punishment would fall
on my head before yours.
If what you said is true and
I used the password myself,
well, I don't know what happens
when this thing activates.
So let's see if you're bluffing.
- You want me to summon her?
- Either way, it'll tell
me what I need to know.
- [Emerald] What are you doing?
- Let's find out.
- Jinn.
- Why, hello again, old man.
Did you have a question for me?
- Actually, I think all my
questions are answered now.
- What are you going to do?
- What Gretchen would have done.
And that starts with
getting you away from here.
Both of you.
- I'm going to need something before I go.
- So just to be clear, none
of you have a question for me?
- No, but we'll be bringing you with us.
- The moment we move that thing,
this place goes on high alert.
Better to get you out first.
- But.
- I'll come back for it.
Not like she knows the password anyway.
- Sorry.
- It's not your fault.
I'm masking and tracking at the same time.
- Do you guys need a minute?
- We don't know how much longer we have.
Why don't you give masking a break?
Give me directions and I can scout ahead.
- Thanks. We should be
heading straight for awhile.
- Well at least you
guys being friends again
takes the sting out of impending doom.
- It's okay to be afraid, you know.
You don't always have
to hide it with a joke.
- Glad I'm not the only one who's scared.
- Of course I'm scared,
him on the other hand.
There's no fear at all.
I can see it, he believes
we're going to get this done.
- Then I do too.
- Mask us, Ren!
- You sure he'll be okay on his own?
- I don't know, we just need to get, wait.
- Ah, Hazel, have you
gotten what we need yet?
- I, I, uh.
- The Seers, seems we have guests.
The lamp, find them!
- What now?
- Let's do what we do best,
charge blindly into danger.
- Would've gone with keep
moving forward, but sure. Ren.
- Forward, no matter what.
- Stay!
- How much longer for the payload?
- [Winter] It's approaching the LZ now.
- Come on, Juan.
- You.
- No, wait, stop!
- Oscar!
- [Emerald] I knew I sensed
some weak minds nearby.
- What's going on here?
- It's a long story.
- You're gonna have to
try and summarize it.
Why should we trust you?
- Because she's scared,
just like us.
- Or maybe because I know
how to get out of here.
Anybody coming?
- This is it, everyone.
We're going to clear a
path to that monster.
We get the payload aboard,
set the timer, and then we're out.
- They might still be alive in there.
- I gave them their window.
We can't wait any longer.
- Would you say the same thing
if it was your sister inside?
Are you gonna tell her what
you did to her friends?
- Yes, Marrow, because that's my duty.
Now you do yours.
(somber music)
- We're almost out!
What is that?
- It's her.
- You really have been honing
that Semblance of yours.
- [Oscar] Let them go!
- What did you do with the lamp?
- Nothing.
- It's missing.
Where is it?
- I didn't do anything with it.
- Where is it?
Look how you've diminished.
How you've lessened
yourself, and for what?
These children, this ruined world?
Why do you keep coming back?
- [Yang] Why do you?
All of this endless death
because something bad happened
to you once upon a time?
Nobody gets a fairy tale ending.
Everything I've lost,
every person I've lost
is because of you.
- And who is it I've taken from you, girl?
- Summer Rose, my mom.
- Her again.
- [Hazel] Your grace.
- Ah, Hazel. I found our guests.
- No!
- This one was helping them.
Take the boy back to his chamber.
I have work to do with this one.
- Yes, of course.
No more Gretchens, boy.
- I really don't know.
- [Hazel] Go now!
- [Emerald] Hazel.
- Go.
- So, you've decided against vengeance
for your sister after all this time.
- I'm doing what Gretchen would have done.
- Come on, everyone out!
Wait, Oscar?
- She'll just come after us.
- Do it.