We said goodbye
To all the things we loved
Gave up our lives
Just to find that it was not enough
We leapt in faith
Left our solitude, our carefree peace
What we thought would change the world
Was just a childish dream
We fail to stop our own demise
The tragic end's before our eyes
Hope has no place here
Maybe the path that leads our way home will finally clear
Maybe the end we tried to avoid is already here
Some roses will never bloom
Some dreams will rot on the vine
Some lives will end much too soon
Some evil will never ever die
Some wars will not end in peace
Some heroes choose the wrong side
Sometimes it's worth it all to risk the fall
And fight for every life
- [Ironwood] If anyone tries anything other than
what I’ve ordered,
Mantle is gone.
You have one hour to respond.
I hope you live up to
the title I gave you.
- [Elm] Of course he's not gonna do it.
- So what, he's bluffing?
With the whole city?
- It may finally push
the kids to see reason.
- Who cares?
- Good,
you're here.
I need a squad of drones in standby
to drop the payload.
- Sir,
what for?
- I believe I was clear in the broadcast.
If they give me a reason, I'm gonna
remove Mantle from the equation.
This is how we save Atlas.
- You call this saving Atlas?
Doing Salem's job for her?
I believed in you!
I thought we could work
towards something better.
But now you're throwing it all away.
- If you don't shut your mouth,
I'm going to do it for you.
- If this is what gets
the children to cooperate,
then it's worth it.
- I don't like this either,
but the top priority is...
- Do you even believe what
you're saying anymore?
Do any of you believe in anything?
I used to wear this rank with pride.
Now I see it for what it really is:
a collar.
- Ah!
- You want a collar? Fine.
I'll throw this traitor in the brig
where he belongs.
- Okay, Ironwood wants Penny,
otherwise, Mantle is done for.
So, how do we stop him?
- Qrow and Robyn are still in his custody,
and May said that Atlas security drones
are watching the crater,
so they're trapped too.
- And Salem isn't going to stay gone
for much longer.
- So then, it's impossible.
- See?
If Miss Hero with all the answers
doesn't have an answer, then we have ours.
- Shut up.
- Okay, then why don't just leave?
- Can we please just
give each other a chance?
Emerald's not with Salem anymore,
and Ozpin is back.
All of this doubt and worry and distrust,
it isn't getting us anywhere.
- Then nothing has changed!
We're in the exact same
place we were yesterday.
Arguing over what to do while
the kingdom waits to die.
- I'm...
glad you're alright.
- Ah, sorry.
No matter how much I boost you,
they won't go away.
- Don't apologize. I got
hurt doing what I always do,
just another ditsy move from Nora.
- Th-that's not true.
- How would you know?
We were supposed to be a team,
but that didn't matter to you.
When things went wrong you pushed us away.
You shove people out
so you don't have to feel
things that are hard.
- You're right.
I should be apologizing,
to both of you.
W-when we lost Oscar and
things got difficult,
I said terrible things.
I've been so... angry, at myself.
For not being as good as the Ace Ops,
for what happened at Robyn's rally,
for losing the lamp.
I thought if I just
focused on working harder,
getting stronger,
that we,
I, wouldn't fail.
But,
my biggest failing
was as a teammate and as a partner.
- Ah ha! Ha ha! Uh...
All water under the bridge, buddy!
Ha ha!`I'm uh...
Gonna go see if Klein
needs any help with Penny.
- Ren,
I just wish,
I mean,
why didn't you say anything?
So we failed as a team, but
we succeed as a team too.
- I was the one holding us back.
Not Jaune,
not you.
Me.
- Well, you're wrong.
All I do is make dumb jokes
and smash things with a hammer.
- What? That's not true.
- You put everything you
have into what you do.
You support everyone around you,
you help without worrying
about how it might hurt.
And that's what I love about...
Th-that's why I...
I love you.
- When my mom ran from the Grimm
and left me behind,
you found me.
We became Ren and Nora.
But I realized on this mission apart,
I don't know who "Just Nora" is.
And if I'm ever going to find out,
then I have to do it alone.
Because I've always loved you, Lie Ren,
and that pretty head on your shoulders
seems like its it's doing a lot better.
But I still got to get mine's sorted out
before I can be the partner you need.
Is that...
okay?
- It's definitely okay.
Boop.
- Heh heh.
- You get those hallway cameras on a loop?
- He's really gonna do it.
- Not if we stop him first.
- There might be a better way.
- I'm telling you there isn't.
- Well, this isn't just about you.
It's about everyone.
- I'm going straight up to the academy
and I am ending this.
- Or we fail and people get killed.
- He deserves this!
- Listen,
I get it.
You are hurting.
You've been hurting for a long time.
But let's stop pretending
that what you're trying to do here
is for anyone but yourself.
Clover was a lot of things.
You respected him, but I gotta tell ya,
I think you're the better Huntsman.
Not because you're the
one who walked away,
but,
because you're the one who was
fighting for what was right.
Don't go telling me that's changed.
- You know, that giant hound kicked
us around like we were nothing.
But Blake said you and the Schnees managed
to take it down.
Still having to one-up your big sis, huh?
- Did she tell you what
it was? Underneath?
- Yeah.
- You know what that means then.
- I wouldn't worry about that.
- That's what happened to Mom.
- When I saw its eyes,
I knew.
Salem used to kill
people with silver eyes,
like Maria.
But she's always wanted me alive.
But why would that change unless,
when she met Mom,
she learned she could do something new.
- Ruby.
- We shouldn't lie to ourselves.
I wasted our time getting Amity up,
thinking help would come, but it didn't,
and Amity fell.
I was being childish.
- You were being optimistic.
Look, blind optimism isn't great
but no optimism means we already lost.
We need hope.
We need to take risks.
- But mine didn't work.
- It still got a warning out.
Ruby, they're not called sure things,
they're called risks, and
in case you didn't notice,
my plan for Mantle didn't work either.
But we got Oscar back,
and did a lot more that
was never in the plan.
Mom took a risk the day she left,
and I don't think,
I don't think it went
the way she wanted it to,
but she's still my hero.
- Hurry!
- I can no longer be delayed.
- Penny, please!
- I...
I must open the vault.
I, I do not want...
Ah!
Ruby, stop me!
- Penny!
- I must open the vault
and self-terminate.
- I've got her!
- What do we do?
- I must
open the vault,
and self-terminate.
- Do something!
- Ah!
- Penny, please.
Tell me how to help you.
- Kill me.
Kill me.
I can make sure the power goes to you.
Please.
Please!
I cannot fight it!
- Yes, you can.
It's just a part of you, remember?
if you were only a machine,
you never could've fought
back for this long.
- She's right.
She's right!
Jaune! Boost her Aura!
- Did... I stop the virus?
- No.
It's still there.
But you've got an Aura, Penny,
a soul.
That's who you are,
our friend,
not a machine.
- [Emerald] I think you're wrong,
by the way.
I highly doubt you're in
the same place you started.
I, I mean, yeah, y-you guys
have been getting your asses kicked,
some of that, my fault, but like,
you're at war.
You're gonna take hits.
Look, I'm just going to be super pissed
if you all finally decide to give up
the moment I switch sides.
- Switch sides, huh?
- [Yang] Aww!
- Or like, whatever.
- If you all wouldn't mind,
I really think Ozpin would
like to say something.
- Go ahead.
- I was recently reminded
of an old fairy tale.
A young girl flees the
consequences of a choice
to a magical place.
But, having never learned
from her initial failure,
she only succeeds in spreading it.
I failed
all of you.
I should have trusted you with the truth,
and should never have run
the day you discovered it.
- It was rough
but...
- I think after everything
that's happened here,
we understand.
Trust is...
- Trust is,
risk.
- And I hope it's a risk
you can take on me again.
- I can still feel it fighting me.
- I can't just keep amping her forever.
- And we can't keep Ironwood waiting.
- Ah!
- Guys, she has to go to the vault.
- That's actually a risk
we haven't considered.
- She'll do it.
- The academy entrance.
Penny comes alone.