We said goodbye
To all the things we loved
Gave up our lives
Just to find that it was not enough
We leapt in faith
Left our solitude, our carefree peace
What we thought would change the world
Was just a childish dream
We fail to stop our own demise
The tragic end's before our eyes
Hope has no place here
Maybe the path that leads our way home will finally clear
Maybe the end we tried to avoid is already here
Some roses will never bloom
Some dreams will rot on the vine
Some lives will end much too soon
Some evil will never ever die
Some wars will not end in peace
Some heroes choose the wrong side
Sometimes it's worth it all to risk the fall
And fight for every life
- [Robyn] This is your fault. You
realize that. Don't you?
All I wanted was to bring people together.
To give them a chance at a better life.
But you-
- Me? I am a victim.
I'll admit I was duped. Used!
And although my hands may not be clean,
at least I am not a murderer.
- He didn't kill anybody.
And I am not gonna stand
here and be lectured
by some snake with a mustache who helped
that man tear us all apart!
- [Watts] Yes, well...
- I suppose we're
all stuck in it together now.
- Just speak for yourself.
I know the right people.
I'm sure Whitley has
reached out to my legal team
and will have me out of
here before you can say-
- [Robyn] Shut up.
(barrier thuds)
- You do realize you've already caught me.
- I hate not being able to do anything.
- We can do something.
We can kill the man who put us here.
- [Reporter] With still no word
from General Ironwood, Mantle
citizens are frightened
and perplexed by the sudden withdrawal
of military personnel,
especially given the massive Grimm horde
outside the kingdom.
I've never seen anything quite like this.
It truly feels like the end of days.
But the Atlas Eye is committed
to updating the public,
until our dying-
Hey, wait!
- Citizens of Mantle! General
Ironwood has abandoned you,
but we have not.
If you can hear this, gather
any food and supplies you need
to stay warm then head
to the Mantle Crater.
The Grimm are starting to make
their way back into the city,
but we can hold the line
(guns firing)
if we all come together.
(body thuds)
If we don't, well, you've all
seen what's waiting for us out
in the storm.
It's time to show your teeth Mantle.
- All right. The others
are definitely missing out.
- [Oscar] Yang! Yang no! No!
- Only take what you need.
- The crater? Are you
sure it's safe out there?
- Absolutely ma'am.
- Heads up!
- Way better than a hover bike.
- Have the Grimm already
pushed this far in?
- No, I think those were
more from last night.
Still...
Ren! If Jaune hits you
with his Aura Amp, think
you can mask everyone?
- [Ren] We can give it a shot,
but it is a lengthy trip through Mantle.
- No, no, that's a great idea.
We'll have a Grimm free journey
all the way to the crater.
- Do we really got a shack
up with those animals down
in the slums? I'd feel a
lot safer being up in Atlas.
- Yeah, I'm sure you would.
But the people up top
have decided
you're not worth the trouble.
The Faunus, on the
other hand, have been willing
to lend all the help they can.
Regardless of whether or not you deserve it.
- So, I'll just... I'll
go get our things then.
- [Civilian] I don't want to go to the slums.
- [Civilian's Daughter] Mother!
- [Civilian] General Ironwood said we
were going to Atlas.
- [Civilian's Daughter] You're setting a bad example!
- [Oscar] It should not be this
hard getting people
to just cooperate.
- [Civilian] She didn't need to yell at me.
- [Civilian's Daughter] Mother, it's fine. It's fine.
- [Ozpin] And yet,
it's something I'm becoming
increasingly concerned about.
- You know I really don't need
your additional commentary
right now.
- [Ozpin] You all have
every right to be upset,
especially you Oscar.
I'm sorry I left you.
- I'm not upset that you left.
I'm upset you came back.
I started to feel like me.
Not the same me I was before all of this
but, the me I always wanted to be.
I felt, like I was actually part the team.
- [Ozpin] I understand.
But even though it may not have felt
like I was with you, I
was never truly gone.
You're gaining control
of my remaining magic,
recollecting my longest held memories.
Which means our two souls are still
on the inevitable path to becoming one.
- But, I don't want that.
- [Ozpin] Neither do I.
- Hey, you good?
- It's just a lot to focus on.
- You can do it Ren.
We're almost to the Crater-
- I don't need a pep talk.
I need to focus.
- Right.
- [Ozpin] We need to find
a way to work together,
not just the two of us,
all of us.
[May] - All right, come on.
- Thanks again for coming.
- [May] Don't mention it.
Once Robyn learned
about Amity Tower, she
wouldn't shut up about it.
Wherever she is, I'm sure
she would want us doing
what we can to get it up in the air
and get the world talking again.
Besides, Fiona's got your
friends helping out in my stead.
- Yeah.
- [Ruby] Are you sure this is safe?
- [Weiss] Snowshoe Shipping is an SDC subsidiary,
meaning all the drones here report
to the company, not the general.
The pneumatic tubes allow for
Dust refined in the crater
to be sent straight up to Atlas.
We just need to find the
one for the military base.
- Are there any buildings in Atlas
that your family doesn't own?
(Nora chuckling)
- That isn't relevant at the moment.
- [Ruby] Hey.
- I do not like it when friends fight.
- I know.
Yang and I might not agree on
how best to save Mantle but-
- [Penny] No.
I mean Winter. The general.
They were our friends.
But then the Ace Ops attacked you.
And the general, he said
people were going to die,
because of me.
- That was a lie.
And he was only saying it to hurt you.
- I was the protector of Mantle,
but now, I am much more than that,
and I wish I was not.
- But, you're still you Penny.
By becoming the Winter Maiden
you did protect Mantle.
- Thank you Ruby.
- [Nora] I found it!
- I suppose there's no turning back now.
- Between our secret weapon
and my semblance, you all
couldn't be in better hands.
- So how do we use this thing?
- It should be simple.
If you lie back in the tube
and press launch-
(Weiss screaming)
- No Crimson, I need you and
your team over in Sector 11.
Mantle police are helping
us clear the hospital,
but they're going to need backup.
- You're doing great Fi.
Robyn would be proud.
- I feel like you should
be doing this after flexing
on the news like that.
- (chuckling) How else was I
supposed to get the word out?
Besides it seems to be working.
Where's this group coming in from?
- [Yang] That would be Sector 7.
- You cleared 7 already? That's great!
To be honest, I wasn't
sure how you'd be doing
without all of your teammates.
- Well, as you can see
we're doing just fine.
- But where are you putting everyone?
- We're working to get
most of them settled
in houses or other shelters.
A large portion of the
community is also trying
to get old mine shafts
into a livable condition.
- [Joanna] We've got a lot of people to keep warm.
Looting the SDC refineries
is our best source of dust.
Fortunately no one's getting
arrested during the apocalypse.
Just knowing those Grimm are circling
out there doesn't feel great.
What are they waiting for?
-[Fi's Uncle] Fi!
(man panting)
- We got another fight breaking out.
- Crap. Thanks uncle. We'll
handle it.
- I'll handle it. You've
got enough to worry about.
- [Crimson] Fiona? Crimson again.
We spotted a decent sized
group of Grimm moving in
from the east. Can't take
them with all these civies.
- Oh, for crying out loud.
- [Yang] Did he say east?
- Ready?
- [Yang] Now.
- [Jaune] Woah!
- Okay Fiona. That's one
more problem taken care of.
- [Fiona] Good, cause
we're getting reports
of more Grimm coming in from the West.
The Huntsmen there could
really use some backup.
- Okay. We're on our way.
- It's all the negativity.
Salem's forces aren't moving in,
but it's enough to start
attracting the stragglers.
- Guys, we're not finished.
- All right. We need to
hurry this up and take-
- What just happened?
- They ran. I've never seen
Grimm act that way before.
- But what were they running from?
- Oscar!
(engine revving)
- Wait! It's using Oscar as a shield.
- But grim aren't that smart?
- Give him back!
[Grimm] - No.
- Did it just?
- [Fiona] Kids, what's your status?
West side's taking damage.
- What do we do?
- [Fiona] Kids. what's your status?
- [Yang] We've got an emergency,
we're not going to make it.
- [Fiona] What? What kind of emergency?
- You wouldn't believe me if I told you.