We said goodbye
To all the things we loved
Gave up our lives
Just to find that it was not enough
We leapt in faith
Left our solitude, our carefree peace
What we thought would change the world
Was just a childish dream
We fail to stop our own demise
The tragic end's before our eyes
Hope has no place here
Maybe the path that leads our way home will finally clear
Maybe the end we tried to avoid is already here
Some roses will never bloom
Some dreams will rot on the vine
Some lives will end much too soon
Some evil will never ever die
Some wars will not end in peace
Some heroes choose the wrong side
Sometimes it's worth it all to risk the fall
And fight for every life
- [Nora] Ow! Ow! Come on,
that was a once in a lifetime experience.
Ow.
- Good, because I never
wanna do that again.
- [May] All right, robo-girl, you're up.
Which way?
- We'll cross the bridge,
then go left, straight, right, straight,
left, up, up, right,
straight, right, right,
straight, left, left.
And my name is Penny.
- [Ruby] Heh.
- [May] Tch.
- I don't think even the squad captain
knows what's going on up there.
They can't get close to that storm
without getting shocked
right out of the air.
- It's creepy.
All those Grimm just waiting.
Worse than if they'd attacked.
- Hey, don't say that.
You'll jinx us.
- I just hope the C.O. can get
us some answers soon, or-
- What?
- Cool.
- [Computer] Welcome back, Dr. Polendina.
- All right, where to next, Penny?
- Right through Central Command.
- Of course.
- I can't maneuver us through all that.
- Do not worry.
Ruby is capable of traveling
at an extreme velocity
from one point to another
by breaking herself down
to her molecular components,
thus negating her mass,
and then reassembling
them at the destination,
theoretically making it
possible for her to transport
all of us in the same way,
as mass no longer matters.
- I, uh, what?
- You can use your semblance on all of us.
- Did Penny just figure
that out before you did?
- Blake, she knew you were
a Faunus before I did.
- Apologies for the delay.
Today has been... busy.
Have you made any progress?
I'd hate for us to have to
try motivating you... again.
- Given what we're after,
I've got all the motivation I need.
Sadly, it doesn't make
taking down Pietro's
magical science project
any less cumbersome.
- Oh, I trust you can
come up with something.
- Oh, the trust is palpable.
Speaking of the man,
are you aware that dear Dr. Polendina
is gallivanting around
your military compound?
Unless, of course, someone
else is using his credentials.
- [Ironwood] A security threat has
been detected in the compound.
Status alert Level 3 -- Red.
Lockdown initiated.
Authorization granted
to handle any threats
with lethal force.
- You've got to be joking.
- The pneumatic tubes
have all been closed off.
- We're trapped.
- We passed a hangar.
I can hijack an airship
and get us off this floating rock.
- Wait. We can still succeed.
We are so close.
- Hmm.
(sighs)
- Read the sign, Bill.
Read the sign!
Why don't you ever just pay attention?
- Another thing I don't
wanna do ever again.
- Stand back please.
- [Ruby] Uh, where is everyone?
- [Penny] This is a highly classified area.
- Hey, dad? I'm ready.
- [Ruby] Huh?
- [Pietro] This process
is a little complicated,
so I'm remoting into Penny
from Amity Colosseum.
- I see.
- Hmm.
- I hope the others are okay.
I've never seen Yang and
Ruby fight like this.
- Don't worry, they're sisters.
Sometimes sisters just
have very different ideas
about what's right.
- Yeah, they'll be fine.
Jaune's a great leader,
Oscar's grown a ton,
and Yang is more than capable
of protecting them all in a fight.
- Hmm.
- Oh, and of course, Ren is, um...
I don't know what he is.
Every time I think the two of
us are making progress, he...
We've been together our whole lives,
but I feel like I understand
him less now than ever,
and I don't know if
that's his fault or mine.
- When you've been at
someone's side for so long,
after a while they become a part of you.
But that's just it.
They're only a part of you.
Don't forget about the rest.
- I don't actually know who
I am (chuckles) without Ren.
(chuckles)
Pretty sad, huh?
- Well maybe take this
opportunity to find out.
Do something only Nora can do.
- Like what?
Be strong and hit stuff?
- [Pietro] I just have to... there.
Downloading the cloned imprint now.
When Penny gets to Amity,
we'll run the launch sequence.
Amity's computer will try to connect
to the general's terminal,
but get Penny instead.
- And after the launch,
I'll return to help you
all with the evacuation.
- [Pietro] About that, Penny.
When Amity goes up,
I think you should be
on it with Maria and I.
- But they need me here.
Right?
- Well, if you stay far
out of Salem's reach,
then she can't open the vault.
She can't get to the relic.
So...
- Maybe it is for the best.
- Um, we should probably
head to the hangar.
- I guess we all have to do some things
we would rather not.
- [Harriet] Hello, kids.
Time to come home now, Penny.
- So your first time
losing to us wasn't enough?
- We were holding back.
- We have all said some things we regret,
but please hear me out.
I know you thought you
were doing the right thing
when you left with the maiden power,
but Salem is here now.
Things have changed
- If General Ironwood plans
to leave Mantle behind,
nothing has changed.
- I thought you were supposed
to protect the people,
not hurt them.
- I would never hurt anyone.
- Well Winter's in critical
condition because of you.
- And you repaid her by stealing the power
that should've been hers.
- But taking the maiden power
was the only way to stop-
- If you keep refusing
to do the right thing,
people in Atlas and
Mantle are going to die.
- You could stop all of this, Penny.
Just open the vault, hand over the relic,
and you'll save Atlas.
- But it won't save Atlas.
Salem will find her way to the
relic no matter where you go.
Once Ironwood opens the vault,
the relic is as good as-
- One more word
and I'm throwing you in jail
right next to your uncle.
- [Penny] Wait.
Leave her alone.
- And what are you gonna
do about it, tin can?
- Penny, no!
- You will not hurt my friends!
- Harriet! Elm!
- Hmph.
- Four versus one?
Cowards.
- Penny's the winter maiden.
I'm sure she can hold
her own for a little bit.
- Marrow!
- Ah!
- Stay!
- We have to get out there.
Be strong
and hit stuff.
- Nora, wait!
- Hurry up, Elm!
I can't-
(door explodes)
- That was pretty awesome.
- Nora!
- Dammit, that was our chance!
I need all available
squads to converge on-
- Wait.
I have a message for your operatives.
- But general, we-
- We understand, sir.
- Huh?
- Tch, let's go.
- Uh, that was-
- Very suspicious?
- [May] You coming or what?
All ready to-
(gasps)
- She's in bad shape.
We need to get her somewhere safe.
- [Penny] I'm so, so sorry.
It is time for me to go, isn't it?
- We'll see each other again
really soon. I promise.
- [Ironwood] Good work.
- Tch, good work would've
been capturing Penny.
- Well, you know what they say.
If you can't beat them,
then make them join you.