We said goodbye
To all the things we loved
Gave up our lives
Just to find that it was not enough
We leapt in faith
Left our solitude, our carefree peace
What we thought would change the world
Was just a childish dream
We fail to stop our own demise
The tragic end's before our eyes
Hope has no place here
Maybe the path that leads our way home will finally clear
Maybe the end we tried to avoid is already here
Some roses will never bloom
Some dreams will rot on the vine
Some lives will end much too soon
Some evil will never ever die
Some wars will not end in peace
Some heroes choose the wrong side
Sometimes it's worth it all to risk the fall
And fight for every life
- Winter do not blame me.
I've sacrificed everything.
- No, you have sacrificed everyone else.
You closed the borders.
You squeezed Mantle until it broke.
- I've only done what's best for Remnant.
And no one is grateful.
- [Penny] Ahhh!
- [Jaune] Priority one.
- [Penny] Weiss, all she's ever
wanted is the maiden power.
I can buy you all time.
- But, Penny...
(both groan)
- [Penny] I'm right here.
I'm what you want.
- I want it all.
- [Blake] Gahhh!
- Get up!
- You're making a mistake, Harriet.
What happened to Clover, I regret-
- Shut up already!
Get out of the way!
- Hare, please don't do this.
They're still evacuating in Mantle.
- Why can't you just let me do my job.
- Because you're our friend!
And we won't let you go through with this.
- No!
- [Weiss] Leave her alone.
- Wait!
- Come on, we have to do this for Yang.
- [Ruby] No!
(blasting)
No!
(beeping)
- [Qrow] The autopilot's locked.
We've gotta go.
- There's no time to make
it out of the blast range.
I've killed us all.
[Harriet] I'm sorry.
- [Elm] No.
You can't!
- I can, if it means saving all of my friends.
- No!
- [Ruby] Whatever you wanted
I hope it was worth it.
- [Cinder] You should've never threatened me.
And you...
should have never been born.
- [Penny] Ruby!
- [Blake] Ruby!
- No!
[Weiss] Get back!
- May, Joanna, any Huntsman
that went through that gate,
bring 'em here.
- It figures that a Schnee
would be the last one standing.
Letting all her friends die first.
- You wouldn't know
anything about friends.
- She's back.
- Ahhhh!
- [Jaune] Penny!
Hold on, my Semblance-
- No.
There's not enough time to heal me.
She can't get the staff and the power,
but there is something you can do.
- No, I- I don't know where the others are,
but Weiss will give us time.
- [Penny] Let me choose this one thing.
Trust me.
- Salutations!
You made it.
- Where...
What is this.
- I thought of you and here we are.
- Oh, Penny.
- It seemed fitting that it should be you.
It was your power after all.
No, Penny, you were always
the real Maiden at heart.
I was just the machine.
Just following orders.
- You were my friend.
- Thank you for trusting me with this.
When you're gone...
- I won't be gone.
I'll be part of you.
- Good, I'm glad.
- So the destiny I chose
for you has arrived.
- You chose nothing.
This was a gift,.
- Where did it go?!
- No.
[Winter] Weiss!
- We need to go.
Now!
- You are going to pay for
everything you've done.
- I failed you again, master.
They used the staff to save thousands
before our allies fell,
Neopolitan...
killed Ruby.
And before Ruby and her teammates fell,
they use the lamp's final question.
I couldn't stop them.
I couldn't even stop
the Maiden from escaping
without putting the relics in jeopardy.
I'm...
I'm sorry.
- [Salem] In pursuit of a new
world no cost is too great.
You've done well, Cinder.
Our work here is done.
You said they used the staff.
I assume you rid the
world of their creation.
What did you create in its stead?
- I merely added more flames
to the fires of Atlas.
And that's checkmate.
Darkness like midnight
Moonless there's no light
Another lonely day
Is ending
Searching forever
Waiting but never finding
The only thing
I dream of
The warmth of a smile
That stays for a while
The face of a friend
That won't leave
I heard a song once
It posed this point of view
That wishes made on stars
Are likely to come true
So here's my secret
At bedtime every night
I searched the sky and hoped to find
A star who'd send a light
To me
The one thing I need
Just one kind soul
With a heart of gold
Then my dreams became real
And I finally feel not alone
Do hugs always make you feel this warm?
My wish came true
The day that you appeared
And called me friend
An answered prayer
A chance to share the world
To be a girl
Who fin'lly felt alive
I'm so excited
We'll do so many friendship things
Paint our nails
Try on clothes
Talk about cute boys
Attached but not by strings
And when you've got problems
Woah! Then I've got problems too
You'll never face this world alone
I'll be right here it's you
And me
Protectors of each other's what we'll be
You saw my soul
Through the nuts and bolts
You're the friend I can trust
Helped me see I'm not just a machine
And is this what "all the feels" means?
I've been combat-ready since the day dad made me
Now I'll fight for something more
Might sound wholesome, but strangely
I've got friends I'm fighting for
But I found that humanity
It came with sacrifice, a pact
To shield you from the wicked even if I can't
Like for real, it was worth it to know you
My wish came true
The day that you appeared
And called me friend
An answered prayer
A chance to share the world
To be a girl
Who fin'lly felt alive