We said goodbye
To all the things we loved
Gave up our lives
Just to find that it was not enough
We leapt in faith
Left our solitude, our carefree peace
What we thought would change the world
Was just a childish dream
We fail to stop our own demise
The tragic end's before our eyes
Hope has no place here
Maybe the path that leads our way home will finally clear
Maybe the end we tried to avoid is already here
Some roses will never bloom
Some dreams will rot on the vine
Some lives will end much too soon
Some evil will never ever die
Some wars will not end in peace
Some heroes choose the wrong side
Sometimes it's worth it all to risk the fall
And fight for every life
- Yep, not getting much sleep here either.
Sounds bad out there.
- Wait, that doesn't sound like-
Get down!
- No need to worry, miss.
You and your friend are
going to be just fine.
- She lost consciousness
and she's... leaking.
- Set her down, set her down.
- Can you help her?
- Even based on what you've told me,
I hardly know what she is.
But her basic anatomy
seems similar enough.
I can at least stitch up that wound.
- Oh, that's just rich.
- [May] Everyone okay back there?
Just saw another bombing
run light up the kingdom.
- Looks like part of the city lost power.
We're okay though.
- [May] Sorry, I couldn't stick around,
but time's running out for
everyone in the crater.
- [Ruby] No, we're sorry.
Once we know what's wrong with
Penny, we'll... we'll do something.
- Don't beat yourself up kid.
- [May] At this point,
I don't know how much is left to be done.
- It's all just too much.
The Grimm, the crater, Nora, Penny.
How do we fix all of it?
- One step at a time, my dear.
You can't worry about fixing everything.
Simply focus on what's in front of you.
If you'd like some place to start,
I'd be able to work faster
If you could bring the power back on.
- Well how would we-
- We have a generator near
the edge of the estate.
- So kind of you to join us, mother.
- Believe it or not,
I am above drinking in the dark.
Oh,
hello, Klein.
- SDC Executives have their
own auxiliary power supplies
in case of a city-wide blackout.
It's extremely unfair,
but perhaps now isn't such a
bad time for company perks.
- We don't just have perks.
- [Weiss] Hm?
- We have the company.
The people you mentioned in the crater,
they need a way out, right?
There are rows and rows of cargo ships
just sitting in the hangers
because of the embargo.
- And our own automated drones.
Like the ones at Snowshoe Shipping.
- We can order as many as
we need to pilot our ships
down to the crater and
get people to safety.
While the Grimm are occupied
with the general's forces
- We can?
- I can.
I just need Father's computer.
- Then we definitely need
to get the power back on.
- [Ruby] Oh, come on, come on.
- Don't worry.
It'll work.
- Nothing else has.
- I know you don't always know what to do,
but that's never stopped
you from doing something.
I was like that as a girl,
but time and a lot of other things
took their toll on me.
And then I wasn't sure
if that kind of girl
could actually survive in the world,
until I met you.
It was a little strange at first
because you were younger
but I've always looked up to you, Ruby
and I still do.
- Thanks, Blake.
- [Ruby] What?
- What was that?
- Ruby!
Blake!
- [Ruby] Weiss! There's a Grimm that-
Look out!
- Can you handle this?
- Assuming you can handle that.
- Ugh.
We still need to work on your attitude.
- What is this thing?
- It's just a Grimm.
Just focus.
- Take the girl.
- Ruby!
- Klein!
There's a Grimm here
and others might be nearby.
Keep everyone together and
call if there's trouble.
- [Klein] Of course.
- Madame,
please try to calm yourself.
- [Willow] I can't do this.
I can't do this!
- Willow, please come back!
Goodness, try not to-
- No, not again!
- No!
- It's not here for me,
it's here for Penny!
- Ruby!
Help the others, I've got her.
- You're okay.
Please!
- I don't want to do it.
- Hey...
No one's going to make you do
anything you don't want to do.
- But there is a part of me...
It's making me...
- It's just a part of you.
Don't forget about the rest.
- [Weiss] Klein, it's coming inside.
Stay quiet.
I'm on my way.
- Do hurry.
Whitley and Willow have yet to return.
- [Weiss] What?
Where'd Mom go?
- Oh!
(electronic beep)
- [Willow] Above you!
- [Weiss] Mom?
- I...
I can see it.
It's outside Winter's old room.
I- You can kill it?
Can't you?
- [Weiss] What is it doing?
- I'm not sure.
It's acting strange.
Why is it here?
- It doesn't matter.
Just keep an eye on it
so I can track it down.
- Right.
Right.
Okay.
It's moving again.
Heading towards...
Oh dear, no.
- I can do this.
(keyboard clicking)
- [Willow] Whitley.
- You are the last thing I need.
All that's left should be...
- [Electronic Voice] Credentials verified.
Click to proceed.
- [Grimm] I know
you're here.
- Run!
- [Electronic Voice] Thank you.
- I didn't forget you.
Go!
- Why did it get more disgusting?
I don't know if you can hear me,
but I need you Ruby.
We all need you.
Ahhh!
Please,
get up.
- I could hear you.
- It's coming!
- I'm sorry!
- What are you doing?
- I must open the vault,
and then self terminate.
- [Grimm] Take
the
girl.
- [Ruby] Penny!
- That's enough.
- Take
the girl.
Take
the
girl.
Take
the
girl!
Take
the
girl!
Take
the
girl!
- [Weiss] What was that?
- That was
a person.
- You know, this may be the first time
I've ever been happy to see you.
- Cinder.
What are you-
- It's my turn to ask for something.
- It's her!
- [Cinder] Huh.