We said goodbye
To all the things we loved
Gave up our lives
Just to find that it was not enough
We leapt in faith
Left our solitude, our carefree peace
What we thought would change the world
Was just a childish dream
We fail to stop our own demise
The tragic end's before our eyes
Hope has no place here
Maybe the path that leads our way home will finally clear
Maybe the end we tried to avoid is already here
Some roses will never bloom
Some dreams will rot on the vine
Some lives will end much too soon
Some evil will never ever die
Some wars will not end in peace
Some heroes choose the wrong side
Sometimes it's worth it all to risk the fall
And fight for every life
- Sir, we have confirmation that Dr. Watts
has escaped military headquarters
with the assistance of Cinder Fall.
We do have Jacques Schnee in custody.
- I don't give a damn
about Jacques Schnee.
What about the other two?
- Sir? Branwen and Hill
have evaded capture.
But we are monitoring every exit,
so they must still be inside the compound.
- [Atlas Soldier] We're moving you to another--
- Damnit!
Search everywhere for them.
Do not return to this office until
you have Qrow Branwen in custody.
- [Atlas Officer] Of course, sir.
- What's the status of our--
- Is everyone all right?
- No injuries here.
- What?
- They were still inside.
- [Ironwood] Target destroyed. Good work.
But no time to celebrate.
Return to the Academy at once.
We've got a new problem.
- But, that wasn't us.
- Then we can tell him in person.
Load it back up, we're leaving.
- [Watts] Did... Did anyone respond?
- No.
- Well, she'll come back.
In the interim we need a plan.
- Plan?
The plan hasn't changed.
I'm going to rip the maiden
power out of Penny Polendina
because you're going to bring her to me.
- I beg your pardon?
- You said in your message that
you have control over Penny.
- I said I had Penny under control.
Not that I could
telekinetically force her to
do whatever I want.
- What?
- I implanted a virus in her, you dimwit.
She's on a set path now.
At least she should be.
As much as I hate to admit it,
there seems to be some part of her
capable of resisting.
Regardless, it's only a matter of time
before her mechanical body
succumbs to the virus.
She'll open the vault,
then she'll destroy herself
and our little Penny problem will be done.
- What do you mean she'll destroy herself?
How am I supposed to take
her power if she's dead?
- You know it's impressive that you
haven't realized this yet
but I don't work for you.
Please.
You can't just threaten
me like everyone else.
- [Cinder] You think you're
so clever, don't you Arthur?
- Salem sent you to bring me back.
- Salem isn't here right now,
but I think we can still come
up with a plan while she's
pulling herself together.
First, I'm going to watch you plummet
to an unremarkable end.
And then I'm going to burn a path directly
to the vault where I will wait
to tear that magical puppet
to pieces and take what is mine.
- (Watts laughing)
Oh, of course you are because
that's just what you do.
Isn't it?
And how has that worked out for you?
You stormed into Fria's
room thinking you can take
on Ironwood's top fighter and war machine.
But you couldn't.
And that machine became the Winter Maiden.
Oh, and let's not forget
your deal with Raven Branwen.
Get all your enemies in one place
so you'd have a shot at revenge.
If only someone could have warned you
against such a miserable idea.
Oh wait, I did.
But you pushed ahead and you lost it
when all you had to do was your job.
You think you're entitled
to everything just
because you've suffered, but
suffering isn't enough.
You can't just be strong,
you have to be smart.
You can't just be deserving,
you have to be worthy.
But all you have ever
been is a bloody migraine!
- [Yang] Blake?
- Yang! Are you okay?
Where are you?
- Yeah, we're fine.
Is everyone there all right?
- [Blake] We're... alive.
This'll help though.
Guys! They're okay.
- What do we do about her?
- Hazel?
- [Weiss] I'm sending you a map.
You're in the agricultural area.
Just head to this access
point to reach the red line
subway tunnel then follow
the route I've drawn for you.
- Got it.
We'll see you soon.
- [Yang] You can't be serious.
You want us to work with her?
- I'm just saying it makes the most sense.
We're all enemies of Salem, including her.
- No, I'm with Blondie.
You don't like me, I don't like you.
So how about we just part ways
and you never have to see me again.
- You're not going anywhere.
Not after everything you've done.
- We can't let all of our
actions stem from fear.
If she could help us, I
think we should consider it.
- She is part of the reason I have this.
I'm not going to just forgive her.
Everything that happened at Beacon.
She lied to us, tricked us.
She is dangerous.
- You don't have to forgive her.
You have every reason to feel that way.
Just maybe give her a second chance.
We've already gotten quite a bit
of help today from someone we
don't exactly trust right now.
- [Ren] Do you mean Ozpin?
I had a feeling.
- [Yang] Wait, what?
- [Jaune] Oz is back?
- I know how you feel
but he saved my life.
When we were tortured, he took it.
So I wouldn't have to.
He entrusted me with this.
And the massive amount of
power he had stored up in it.
Kinetic energy that he spent lifetime
after lifetime accumulating
in the cane he built.
- So that's how you did that?
Using all of the stored up power.
- Not all, but most.
We have to be careful
with how we use the rest.
He trusted my judgment and it saved us.
I want to reciprocate that trust.
There's a lot to sort out,
but Oz really wants to help.
- [Ozpin] Thank you, Oscar.
- All of Atlas is down here.
- I've seen what you can do, Emerald.
However this fight ends,
we could really use someone like you.
- It's about time.
While we dealt a decisive
blow to Salem today--
- Actually that wasn't our payload, sir.
I brought it back with us.
- Then who could have?
But you still have it.
This may be useful.
Penny still hasn't come to the Vault,
meaning Watts was either
incompetent or he betrayed us.
At this point, we'll never know.
Cinder Fall has attacked
command and escaped with him.
And that's not all we've lost
- Sir?
- Qrow and Robyn have also escaped.
Salem's creature was destroyed,
but that doesn't mean we've stopped her.
She will return and she will
throw everything she has
at us until there is nothing left.
And we are perilously
close to that already.
I need the Winter Maiden, now.
It's the only way Atlas can survive.
Schnee, bring me Arc, Ren, and Xiao Long.
- What for, sir?
- I had Qrow in my hands and I didn't do
what needed to be done.
I will not make that mistake again.
I know.
I'm ashamed I didn't think of it earlier.
Leveraging the lives of her
friends is the only way to
make Penny listen to reason.
- Sir.
I'm sorry, but we don't have them.
Operative Schnee let them go.
- You what?
- [Harriet] Winter allowed
them to go on board
the creature to rescue their friend
and they never came back.
- They were our last chance.
Now. Now I have nothing.
- [Commander] Sir! We are
detecting non-military
ships on radar, dozens of them!
- Ships? Whose ships?
- They appear to be Schnee
Dust Company freighters, sir
They're heading straight for Mantle.
- Weiss, I see.
They're trying to save Mantle.
This has always been
about Mantle, hasn't it?
I need to make a call.
- Who is it?
Did someone survive?
Night and day I've waited
For the moment when I'd see your face
And feel you near
- I missed you too.
All alone in crowded rooms
I'm incomplete, my life is paused
When you're not here
- Where's Nora?
- Oscar, you--
- No, she's okay, I can--
- Kids, the cargo ships
you sent just made it
but they're not alone.
- May? What are you talking about?
- Oh my gods, run!
Everyone, into the mines (explosion)
- [Blake] Were those...?
- [Female CCT Voice] This is
an emergency CCT broadcast.
- What's going on?
- Those ships, they were
going to save people.
- Why would-
- I have always promised
to defend this kingdom.
Its technology, its future, from those who
would see it destroyed.
Our enemy is crippled, but one individual
still denies Atlas its salvation.
The Protector of Mantle.
Penny, wherever you and your friends are,
I need you all to listen.
I know how much Mantle means to you.
So I'm going to give you a choice.
You can bring yourself to Atlas Academy
and do your duty, help me
save as much of Atlas as I can
and Mantle will be left
to fend for itself.
Or you can all watch as I destroy it.
I have one bomb.
That's all it will take.
If there is no Mantle
then there is no reason
for you not to work with me.
Neither of us want it to come to that,
but one of us is willing to do it.
If anyone tries anything other
than what I've ordered, Mantle is gone.
You have one hour to respond.
I hope you live up to
the title I gave you.