We said goodbye
To all the things we loved
Gave up our lives
Just to find that it was not enough
We leapt in faith
Left our solitude, our carefree peace
What we thought would change the world
Was just a childish dream
We fail to stop our own demise
The tragic end's before our eyes
Hope has no place here
Maybe the path that leads our way home will finally clear
Maybe the end we tried to avoid is already here
Some roses will never bloom
Some dreams will rot on the vine
Some lives will end much too soon
Some evil will never ever die
Some wars will not end in peace
Some heroes choose the wrong side
Sometimes it's worth it all to risk the fall
And fight for every life
- You should have seen
the look on Joanna's face.
I don't think she'd ever
lost a fight before that.
At least, not fair and square.
Tough crowd tonight.
Guess Ironwood should have paid
for better cell block entertainment.
And he smiles. Did I win?
- Hey, it's your game.
I don't make the rules.
- I'm sorry, for what happened.
It wasn't your fault.
- It was though.
I made a deal with the darkness,
and he paid the price.
It was all happening so fast,
but Clover wouldn't let up.
We could have worked against
Tyrian if Clover just...
But the thing that really stings,
for the first time in a
while, I thought maybe,
maybe I could be around somebody. Anybody.
Without my semblance
making it complicated.
And now it just feels like
a childish dream.
Gone
like everybody else.
- Believe it or not, I know
a little of what that's like.
When people are worried
you're gonna sniff out
their secrets, they tend to push you away.
It makes a real connection(barrier
buzzing) difficult.
- I never thought of it that way.
- You don't get to keep that.
- I didn't kill him.
- You keep saying that,
but it was your weapon
covered in his blood.
- [Robyn] If you really want
to know what happened
mohawk, why not open the cell
and take my hand.
- If I open this cell, it
won't be to shake hands.
- Yeah. Because you don't
care about the truth.
You just want someone to be mad at.
Easier than taking an honest
look at what side you're on.
- Hare, what are you doing?
- Nothing.
- Well, that was almost exciting.
- He's going lose us in these mountains.
We can't keep up.
- I don't know how much longer these bikes
can stand the cold.
- I'm really wishing one
of us could fly right now.
- Wait. Hold on.
Ren! I'm going to get you up there.
- Nice!
(hands clap)
Okay, not as nice.
- Slowing him down. Hold on Ren!
- I don't have much of a choice.
- Did it just call for back up?
Here comes another nightmare
Another fever dream
The horror just won’t stop
An endless scream
But this is not subconscious
We’re not imagining
We’re wide awake
This is reality
Our world’s
Lost without a soul
We’re losing all control
Not getting closer
Every step is just another dose of torture
Torture
Better cover up your eyes my friend
The sky is falling
Can’t outrun the ruin of our lives
Be prepared we’re near the end
The final days are calling
Hold on now
The sky is falling down
- Oh, you've picked a fine time to-
- [Weiss] Not another word.
We're coming in.
- [Whitley] Things are already bad enough
after what you did to father.
Now you want us to harbor fugitives too?
Our family has a reputation.
- That's what you're worried
about? Your reputation?
- I'm just saying
that we've already lost
all the house staff,
and mother locked herself in her room.
- Maybe you haven't figured
out what's going on, Whitley,
but we're busy trying to save Atlas.
- Look. Our friend is hurt.
We just need a place to
lay low while she rests,
and then we'll be out of your way.
- Fine. What do you expect me to do then?
- Go to your room.
This way.
- Ruby?
- I hope everyone's doing all right.
- If you're worried
about Yang, you could
always try calling her.
- But that's the thing. I did.
- [Jaune] I repeat, if anybody can hear me.
We need transport back to Mantle.
- [Yang] We need to get out of this weather
before the cold drops
our Auras completely.
How much farther to the outpost?
- Ren? How much-
- I don't know.
- I thought you said you saw
it when you were up in the air?
- I did. Before I had to cut
myself loose to help you guys.
- Yeah. You've brought
that up a couple times now.
Something you need to say?
- Not really. Wouldn't want
to waste any more time.
- Hey, what is your deal?
- Don't worry about it.
- Well, I'm sorry things
aren't going smoothly enough
for you.
- Guys.
- They're not going smoothly at all.
- I hate to break it to you,
but that's part of being a Huntsman.
- Are you kidding?
We don't know the first
thing about being Huntsmen.
We clearly weren't ready.
- Guys, stop it.
- Were we not ready when we saved Haven,
when we took down a Leviathan?
We got the lamp to Atlas.
- And then we lost it.
And after that, when we had
to make real decisions, we
got every single one wrong.
- I'm not going to pretend like
we did everything perfectly,
but if we'd done nothing,
things would be even worse
than they are now.
- How could they possibly be worse?
We are stuck out here while
Salem has the lamp and Oscar.
We've got no plan, no army.
- We've got the Maiden.
- And by keeping her
from opening the vault
for Ironwood, we're just trapping
the whole city, for Salem.
People are going to die, because of us.
- So what? We should just
give Ironwood what he wants?
Abandon Mantle?
You think Atlas is still
going to be able to float
to safety now that she's here?
- I don't know.
But these aren't the kinds of
decisions we should be making
because we have no idea what we're doing.
- [Jaune] Okay. Both of you, cut it out.
- I'm just saying what
nobody else wants to.
We are in way over our heads.
Ruby is barely more than
a kid, I'm just an orphan
from the middle of nowhere-
- Ren, I-
- You cheated your way
into Beacon.
- You don't think we
should be Huntsmen? Fine.
But I'm getting out of the cold.
Still gotta job to do.
- Seriously, is your goal
just to push everyone away?
- [Ozpin] Oscar?
Don't panic. We're going to be okay.
- [Oscar] What?
- [Salem] My long lost Ozma.
Found, at last.
So small this new host of yours.
It's a wonder my hound didn't break you.
It's been how many years
since we saw each other
like this, face to face?
And nothing to say?
- I'm sorry the reunion isn't living up
to your expectations.
- You can pretend boy,
but you're not fully him.
Not yet at least.
Well, perhaps you
and I can have a better
working relationship.
Oscar, was it?
The Beacon Relic.
My forces have been unable
to locate the relic beneath the school.
If I know my Ozma, he has
used some means of deception
to hide its location
differently than the others.
I need to know where it is.
- I...
That's not something I know about.
- Of course, you would
keep that one guarded
as long as possible.
How about something easier, then?
The password for the lamp.
- The lamp is all out of questions.
- The lies come out of you so easily.
Like-minded souls indeed.
One of you is going to
tell me what you know.
I don't much care if it is you, or Ozma.
Either way, I'll finally have the relic.
- I won't tell you anything.
-Hm.
- Hazel?
Wait, wait!
- [Hazel] That was for Haven Academy.
Everything that follows,
will be from my sister.
- Your grace, I...
What, is that?
- An experiment.
So far I am pleased with the results.
Did you need something Cinder?
- Yes. I, I want to search
for the Winter Maiden.
I think-
- Do you hear that my pet?
She thinks. She wants.
As if she's done something
that warrants me caring
about either of those things.
- We're just sitting and waiting.
Without the Maiden Power,
the vault means nothing.
Let me claim it for you.
- I will tell you when
and where you are needed.
- But your grace.
- I'd like to think I have
shown a great deal of patience
over my many years walking remnant...
but I do hate repeating myself.
You will remain here.
Is that clear?
- Yes.
Yes, of course.
Without you, I am nothing.
I know what she said.
I just want to check on something.
We'll be back before anyone realizes.
I want to see if anything
is still going on
at Amity Colosseum.
Salem doesn't know those
children like I do.
They wouldn't just abandon
their misguided attempt
to save the world.
- [Emerald] If she doesn't want to, I'll come.
I've been working on my Semblance.
I can help.
I won't tell anybody.
- (grunts) How much did you overhear?
- You're right Ren. I..
I did cheat my way into Beacon.
And I'm glad I had people
around me to help me see
that, I was bigger than that mistake.
You've got people around you too.
You don't have to force
yourself to be strong.
The more you hide
from what you're feeling,
the more alone you're going
to feel.
Trust me.
- If anyone cares, I found
a part to fix the bike.
So, yay.
Good news.
For what it's worth, I'm
sorry he said that to you.
I know you've had to work
hard to get here Jaune.
- We're all under a lot
of stress right now.
I used to push people away too.
- Do you think she thinks less of me?
for not helping out with Amity?
- Ruby is your sister. She's
always going to love you,
even if you disagree with each other.
- Yeah.
Ruby.
- I need to get some sleep
but, I can't stop thinking about Oscar.
- Go on. I'll make sure
Ren doesn't brute himself
to death out in the cold.
- Thanks. I just have a bad feeling.
Things always seem to get
worse before they get better.