We said goodbye
To all the things we loved
Gave up our lives
Just to find that it was not enough
We leapt in faith
Left our solitude, our carefree peace
What we thought would change the world
Was just a childish dream
We fail to stop our own demise
The tragic end's before our eyes
Hope has no place here
Maybe the path that leads our way home will finally clear
Maybe the end we tried to avoid is already here
Some roses will never bloom
Some dreams will rot on the vine
Some lives will end much too soon
Some evil will never ever die
Some wars will not end in peace
Some heroes choose the wrong side
Sometimes it's worth it all to risk the fall
And fight for every life
- [Oscar] What do we do now?
- We stick to the plan.
- How?
Without the CCT there's no way we can tell
all of Atlas
to just step into a bunch
of freaky, magic doors.
- [Ren] But there is.
We use the portals ourselves,
and spread the word on foot.
- Are we positive these things work?
- Okay, we can do this.
Nora and I will get
people through the gates.
Everyone else, keep to your roles.
Remember, the evacuation is priority one
no matter what else happens.
- You sure you won't need more help?
- Shade is armed to the teeth
with Huntsmen and Huntresses.
but we're about to
throw a kingdom's worth
of negativity on their doorstep.
If anyone will need help, it's them.
- [Civilian] What is it?
- Everyone.
Ow!
I'm uh- gonna need your attention.
- [Jaune] Keep moving, come on.
- [Nora] That's it, watch your step.
- [Joanna] Hey, no pushing.
Figured you wouldn't let us down.
- [Weiss] I thought there'd be more people by now.
Our job is getting Penny and the Staff
to Vacuo.
Until then, we
have to trust the others.
I'm sure they can handle it.
- We should end up just outside
the city limits of Vacuo.
Enough space for refugees
but still within range of communication.
- All right, I'll focus
on masking emotions
for as long as I can.
Call for help as soon as we cross.
- You've gotta be kidding me.
- [Ren] Which way is the city?
- It has to be here somewhere.
- Guys, the sandstorm isn't
just killing visibility.
- Where are we?
- Welcome...
to Vacuo.
- Head down and follow
everyone else to the exit.
No.
- Keep going, we'll handle this.
- [Cinder] Your little friend Oscar was right.
But the easy part ends here.
- How did you know about that?
- Neopolitan, was it?
Now isn't the time to hold grudges.
- No, she's right to be angry.
I know I haven't upheld
my end of the bargain.
I'm sorry.
I will get you Ruby Rose today.
But to do that, I need to
ask the lamp a question.
[Cinder] Jinn.
- [Jinn] You have a question for me?
- I do.
What have Ruby and her teammates planned?
(muffled)
- [Jaune] We've been so worried about
keeping the Vault closed that...
we never considered using what's inside.
the Staff of creation.
- Maybe we can use it to save Penny
and get everyone in Atlas
and Mantle back to safety.
(muffled)
- [Ruby] After you guys
broadcast the evac procedure,
- you'll walk through the
portal at the CCT Center.
And then we're done in the Vault,
we'll take Penny and the Staff.
- [Cinder] You tore this kingdom apart with nothing
but your intellect.
How about we finish what you started?
- [Cinder] You have everything you need?
- [Watts] Oh believe me, this
is everything I've ever wanted.
- You deserve this Arthur.
We'll be back.
- [Ren] You're live.
- [Emerald] Everyone can see you.
- [Jaune] Citizens of Atlas, Mantle,
what we have to tell you is very important.
(biting)
Atlas is falling.
But -
(beep)
- [Elm] They're using the Staff?
Are they crazy?
They'll destroy the kingdom.
- [Robyn] What do you think a kingdom is?
The people, or just the
chunk of land they live on.
- [Qrow] Either way, it's over now.
Ironwood's down.
=
- [Marrow] No!
(loud explosion)
- [Jacques] Well I see you're awake finally.
Atlas is falling under your watch.
How does it feel James?
- They- they've got the Staff.
- That's right.
You lose.
We both lose.
[Jacques] What?
[Jacques] You're - you're going to open mine too, right?
- Sure thing.
- I knew your plan would be bold.
But I never could have
predicted all of this.
At least not without a
little help from Jinn.
I suppose I have all of you
to thank for one last lesson.
Sometimes if you want to win,
you simply can't do it alone.
- Ruby!
- Yang!
- Yang?
- [Penny] Why'd you have to come back?
- Penny, no!
- [Penny] Why didn't you just learn your lesson?
- Oh, Penny.
- I did.
- [Harriet] Vine, glad someone made it.
Watch for a tail,
I need to make sure this
thing is still armed.
- I'm no longer certain
this is the most logical course of action.
- Do you really wanna do this, Zeki?
- No, I don't.
Harriet, the general
is no longer in charge.
Ruby and the others have used the Staff.
Atlas is falling, but
it's people will be safe.
Unless you-
(metal clanging)
- It's the principle, Vine! It's about loyalty.
Clover understood that.
Clover would see this through.
- Then perhaps Clover was wrong too.
- Don't you dare!
Clover was, he was-
- Important to you.
Harriet, you are not the only one.
- Looks like you're getting
that fight after all.
- I repeat.
Is anybody receiving these messages?
Can anyone report status
on the evacuation?
- I chased a lot of shadows over the years.
Always expecting betrayal.
But never once did I think
it would ever come from you.
I know what's best for Atlas.
And I'm going to do whatever
it takes to get that Staff.
So, consider this my last order.
Step aside.
- I've never wavered
in fighting the enemies of this kingdom.
And I won't start now.
- I'm spent.
- Where's Penny?
Couldn't she deal with this storm?
- Wait, Penny should've been here by now.
Something's wrong.
What?
Why can't I-
- [Ozpin] Oh dear...
Ambrosius.
- [Weiss] People enter from Atlas
and Mantle on one side,
and leave on the other side,
with a one-way ticket to Vacuo.
- We can't go back.
The portal won't let us.