We said goodbye
To all the things we loved
Gave up our lives
Just to find that it was not enough
We leapt in faith
Left our solitude, our carefree peace
What we thought would change the world
Was just a childish dream
We fail to stop our own demise
The tragic end's before our eyes
Hope has no place here
Maybe the path that leads our way home will finally clear
Maybe the end we tried to avoid is already here
Some roses will never bloom
Some dreams will rot on the vine
Some lives will end much too soon
Some evil will never ever die
Some wars will not end in peace
Some heroes choose the wrong side
Sometimes it's worth it all to risk the fall
And fight for every life
(beep)
- Yes, sir?
- I am evacuating all
citizens to the subway.
Prepare Manta Squad Omega, and dispatch
to every part of Atlas.
- But sir--
- Now!
- [Ironwood] Citizens
of Atlas, please proceed
to the nearest underground
subway station for shelter.
- Dad? Look!
- We need to go!
- [Commander] We can't get the hard
light shields back up, sir.
The generators took too much damage!
- [Ironwood] Then don't
waste resources on them.
Beta Squad, the creature?
- [Commander] We tried bombs, missiles,
but we can't make a dent, sir.
- Sir, Schnee here.
Penny is still MIA, but
we've apprehended Arc,
Xiao-Long, and Ren.
- [Ironwood] Stand by for further orders,
and don't let those
fugitives out of your sight.
- Yes, sir. Of course.
- Still just following orders.
- That's where the Grimm took Oscar.
It's even bigger than I thought.
- Grimm don't take prisoners.
- This one did.
- If you would just let us go--
- [Ironwood] Cease fire.
Manta squads, concentrate
on secondary hostiles.
Command is working on a
solution for the creature.
- What do you have in mind, sir?
- [Ironwood] We aren't making any progress
attacking the thing from the outside.
But from the inside,
it could be vulnerable.
Science team is putting together a bomb.
When it's ready, we'll drop it off
as close to the target as possible.
Then, your team will deliver it on foot.
Sending your rendezvous coordinates now.
- Of course, sir,
we will hold the point
and we will get it done.
- But Oscar's in there!
- You can't do this!
- [Hazel] That stunt you pulled.
She'd have killed you if you didn't
just pop up somewhere else.
Still, you can make
things easier on yourself
if you start telling the truth.
- You've never wondered
why she recruited you?
You, specifically, to
help her find the relics.
- We share a vision.
She's gonna create a new world order,
no kingdoms and no Huntsmen Academies.
- (chuckles) New world order.
No.
When Salem gets all four relics,
there will be no world left at all.
Don't you get it?
She's been alive longer
than you can comprehend.
All she craves now is release.
Death.
- Stop lying!
(grunts)
Salem can't be killed.
When she came for me, I killed
her over and over again.
The longest she was gone
was only a few hours,
before she put herself back together.
When I couldn't lift my arms anymore,
she showed me that, through her,
I could have the vengeance I needed.
- Oh, Hazel, don't you see?
That is why she came for you.
Because she could make you believe
that this is what you needed.
- This is what you deserve!
- Yes, but Oscar?
The people of Atlas, Remnant?
You haven't done what
you've done for justice.
You've done it for yourself.
Because she pushed you to
think it would help you.
Well, has it?
- Now what
am I good for?
- How is she?
- I've done what I can,
but she needs a doctor.
- Hopefully, May's able
to reach the others.
I'm...
I really hope they're okay.
Salem's monster is making Grimm faster
than the Atlas military can kill them.
The city won't stand a
chance unless we stop it.
- It's massive. Way
bigger than a leviathan.
What can we even do?
- Penny launched Amity
and our message went out.
Do we just wait for someone to come?
If they even come.
- [Ruby] How did it all get like this?
- Fiona said your friends
haven't been heard from in a while.
Unfortunately, the last
thing they're worried about
is a couple of kids.
Come on, I've got the ship
ready to head back and--
- What?
We can't leave.
- It's chaos at the crater.
Atlas has its army,
but Mantle only has us.
People are dying.
- People are dying here, too.
Don't you have family in Atlas?
- No.
Mantle needed me, and to the Marigolds,
that meant I wasn't their son anymore.
And I made sure that everyone knew
that I wasn't their daughter.
So forget 'em.
They've got Henry, yours have Whitley.
You get what I'm saying.
- I don't know about--
- Which side are you on, anyway?
- We've heard that before.
- There are no sides!
We want to help everyone.
We're all facing Salem together.
And together is the only way
we're going to get out of it.
- So, how exactly do we get out of it?
- "So long as this world turns,
you shall walk its face."
That was the curse cast upon her.
But if Salem can divide
humanity beyond repair
and bring all four relics back together,
she believes that maybe
her curse will be broken.
The gods will rule against
us and destroy Remnant,
once and for all.
- Nice story.
But if Gretchen's death
taught me one thing,
it was never to trust you.
- [Oscar] Please, let me.
- But, Oscar--
- You want 'em to trust us?
Then trust me.
Her name is Jinn.
You want her to come out of the lamp?
Just say her name.
She can still answer one more question.
After all that, you're just going
to give Salem the password?
- No, I'm giving you the password
and hoping you'll find
the truth for yourself.
- [Mercury] He's a prisoner, Em.
He'll say what he thinks will get him out.
- So you're still going to Vacuo,
after what I just told you?
- Those are Salem's new orders,
and I know better than to disobey Salem.
- But--
- Look, even if what he said was true,
we can't stop Salem.
You told me yourself, Hazel tried.
He failed and he got in line.
Big guy's not going to
pick fights he can't win,
and neither should we.
And all of this is pointless, anyway.
Salem's not ending the world.
- (laughing)
[Tyrian] Of course she is!
You're surprised?
Salem is destruction incarnate! (giggling)
Our mistress wishes to see the end of it all!
There is no ideal more beautiful.
If you couldn't see that from the start,
you must be out of your mind.
Now come along, Mr. Black.
You and I have a date with the desert.
- You can't blow it up
with Oscar still in there!
- That creature causes
more damage every minute.
We cannot wait.
- Please, Winter, give us a chance
to try to rescue him first!
We...
We could be your test run.
You don't know what'll be
waiting for you inside, right?
So we can go ahead to check it out,
and look for Oscar while we're inside.
- You want to go inside that thing alone?
- Wouldn't you do it
for Elm? Harriet? Vine?
- We don't let feelings get in the way
of making the right call.
Trading three lives for one is stupid.
- No, it's not.
He's our friend.
We will do whatever it takes to find him,
because we care about him.
- (scoffs) I really had you
pegged as the most level-headed
of the bunch, but I guess
you're just as naive.
Feelings don't matter, the job matters.
When you lose someone on
your team, you move on.
Replace them, like Marrow replaced Tortuga
and Winter replaced--
- No!
No one is replaceable.
You don't really believe that.
You are furious about losing Clover,
and you, you miss him.
- You don't know anything about me!
That's why you lost against Team RWBY.
You, you try to fight how
you feel about each other,
so you'll never truly work as a team.
- Shut up!
You don't know what you're talking about!
(grunting)
- Everyone, calm down.
Fine.
We will drop you as close
as we can to the monster.
- You can't be serious.
They're fugitives and traitors!
- I outrank you.
If you aren't out in
time, we drop the payload.
No matter what.
- We understand.
- You don't like this either.
In fact, you don't want to be
a part of it at all anymore.
- I...
I have a job to do,
and I'm going to do it.
- I know you don't, either.
- Wait, what about Qrow and Robyn?
Well, maybe if we get them out of wherever
they're being held, they could--
- No, see, you just don't get it!
This is not a situation
where everyone wins.
Now, you all can come
with me to help in Mantle,
or I can drop you off
near the front lines,
if you still want to help Atlas.
Your uncle and Robyn can't save us.
We have to choose.
So choose.
- (gasps) Klein!
- Miss Schnee!
I heard there was a patient
here who needed my help.
- I, I am so sorry, Klein.
It's my fault that Father...
- Please don't worry, my snowflake.
It had nothing to do with you
and everything to do with Jacques.
- Well, that's sweet of you.
But wait, how did you know--
- Ah, young Whitley.
I'm so glad that you rang!
May I please see the patient?
I understand it's urgent.
- Yes, she's in Weiss's room.
Just go up the--
- I haven't been gone
that long, Master Whitley.
I believe I can find it.
- You called Klein?
- That girl needs a doctor.
I didn't do it for you.
- I know.
That's why it means so much to me.
Did you call anyone else?
- I'm, I'm sorry.