Back to the fairytale, back to the show
Back to the wall and there's nowhere to go
Hopeless and desperate, all paths adverse
Things looking bleak, and they're bound to get worse
Helpless and doomed, and there's no way to win
Goals unachievable, faith running thin
Lost and forlorn, impossible odds
That's when you'll learn you've been messing with gods!
Send in your grimm, tear off my limb
Strike me with bolts of lightning
I won't die
The battle seems unwinnable, but all we need's a miracle
We're going up we'll never be denied!
Can't wish away the dismal days
Can't bring back what is gone
Won't waste more tears on yesteryears
Instead we'll carry on
We'll win, we're sure we will endure
And though our goal is far
We'll be the ones to touch the sun
The Triumph will be ours!
Why hello.
Thank you for…
…coming.
There…
…seems to be more of you than last time
Eh, you know what they say, "The more the merrier".
So what’s going on with the council?
Why…
.. did you bring your weapons?
What?
Leo,
we're Huntsmen.
You okay?
Of course!
Of course, sorry.
Just haven’t had my evening coffee.
Look, it's nice to see you, but we got work to do.
Are we getting support from the council or not?
Mom?
Raven…
They…
They really are magic…
If you’re going to shoot me, shoot me.
That was insulting.
What are you doing here?!
I could ask you the same thing.
You’ve been scheming, little brother.
Planning to attack your own sister.
Leo…
What have you done?!
I…
Leo did what any sane person would in his position -
- he looked at all the information he had in front of him,
assessed the situation,
and made a choice.
And it seems you all have too.
You have the Spring Maiden.
I do.
Then hand her over and let's work together!
We can beat Salem!
All that time spent spying for Ozpin and you still have no idea what you’re dealing with.
There is no beating Salem!
You're wrong.
We've done things that most people would call impossible,
and I know the only reason we were able to do it is because we didn't do it alone!
We had people to teach us,
people to help us,
we had each other.
Work with us.
At least I know we'll have a better chance if we try together.
Please.
You sound just like your mother.
Ruby!
Hello, boys and girls
Cinder…
C’mon guys, is that any way to greet your old friends?
Everybody, stay calm.
Oh no…
The White Fang is prepping demolition
and securing the school grounds.
No one's getting in,
and no one's getting out.
Once the charges are set, move back to perimeter watch.
Tonight,
Haven falls.
This was all just a trap?
It appears so…
Raven,
tell me…
How long have you been with them?
Aww, don’t take it personally, little bird.
Your sister was a recent addition.
The lion on the other hand…
Entrance into the Vytal Festival was a real treat,
but Leonardo’s been sending Salem all sorts of information for a very,
very long time.
Isn't that right, professor?
Stop it…
It was you…
You sit on the Mistral Council.
You had information on every Huntsman and Huntress in the Kingdom,
and you gave it all to her.
I…-
I couldn’t find any of them,
because you let her kill them!
Aw now, don’t beat yourself up about it, Lionheart,
I’m sure Tyrian and Hazel would’ve found them on their own eventually.
What is wrong with you?
How can you be so broken inside…
To take so many lives,
and then come here and rub it in our faces like it’s something to be proud of?!
Jaune…
All with that damn smile on your face!
Everybody, stay calm!
I’m gonna make you pay for what you did!
Do you hear me?
Kid!
Well?!
Say something!
Who are you again?
Jaune!
You’re not getting near her.
Hey there, blondie.
I'm thinking you owe me an apology for my leg
don’t you think?
Take out the heiress.
Don’t bother wasting your power, she’s not worth it.
Running away was one thing, but this…
You’ve crossed the line!
Sorry, brother.
Sometimes family disappoints you like that.
We’re not family anymore.
Were we ever?
I thought so,
but I guess I was wrong.
Let's see what the Schnee name really means.
I’m more than a name.
Prove it.
I don’t wish to fight either of you.
Nor I you.
But we will if you’re with her!
Very well, then.
Young man,
I don’t know who you are or what you think you’re doing,
but for your sake,
I suggest you leave.
Now.
I’m warning you!
That’s enough!
Ozpin?
Not quite.
This can’t be…
I knew you would be back, but…
You made it here! You found Qrow!
How?
Leo…
What happened to you?
Wait.
You can’t have had this form for long.
You’re…
…not really Ozpin right now
Boy.
Child.
f I deliver you to Salem, she’ll have to be pleased with me,
and I can finally get out of all of this!
I can finally be free!
What do I do?
Fight.
Don’t think I’m going to let you take the easy way out.
I’m starting to remember you,
you’re the dense one that can’t tell when he’s out of his league.
Why are you doing this?! Salem’s?
I don’t care about Salem!
But I owe Cinder everything.
You want to fight her that bad?
Be my guest.
Are you going to let her die too?
Stop messing with me!
If that’s what you want…
NOOOOOOOOOOOOOO!
Did you think you actually had a chance against me?!
You?!
You’re just a failure with a death wish.
If I die buying them time,
then it’s worth it.
They’re the ones that matter.
You think so?
No…
NOOOOOOOOOOOOOO!