Back to the fairytale, back to the show
Back to the wall and there's nowhere to go
Hopeless and desperate, all paths adverse
Things looking bleak, and they're bound to get worse
Helpless and doomed, and there's no way to win
Goals unachievable, faith running thin
Lost and forlorn, impossible odds
That's when you'll learn you've been messing with gods!
Send in your grimm, tear off my limb
Strike me with bolts of lightning
I won't die
The battle seems unwinnable, but all we need's a miracle
We're going up we'll never be denied!
Can't wish away the dismal days
Can't bring back what is gone
Won't waste more tears on yesteryears
Instead we'll carry on
We'll win, we're sure we will endure
And though our goal is far
We'll be the ones to touch the sun
The Triumph will be ours!
You're up early.
Hey sis.
Boop.
What are you doing up?
Can't fall back to sleep.
Ah, me neither.
Well, fortunately,
coffee exists.
No, please!
Don't worry, I put in blasphemous amounts of cream and sugar, just for you.
Oh yeah! Nice Weiss strikes again!
I will pour this on you and it will burn.
Can't believe we're actually in Mistral.
That's what you can't believe?
Well, yeah!
And all the other magic and stuff.
But...
Okay, you know what I mean!
I honestly wasn't sure if I'd ever see you two again.
Well,
here's to defying expectations.
I just wish Blake could be here with us.
Yeah, well,
she made her choice.
What's that supposed to mean?
I mean she could've been here if she just stuck around.
It's no big deal though. We'll be fine.
Don't you want her here?
Why would I want her here?
Are you still mad at her for leaving?
Oh, whatever gave you that idea, Ruby?
No, I'm totally fine. I'm great.
Okay, calm down.
Don't tell me to calm down!
Whoa
Yang...
Whatever.
Hey Blake!
You ready to go?
Be right there!
We going recruiting or what?
We've got the entire nocturnal section to hit up!
You okay?
Yeah, I'll meet you there.
I need to take care of something first.
Yeah?
Look Ruby, I really don't want to talk about it, okay?
Can you just leave me alone for a bit?
Oh.
Hey Weiss.
Did you need something?
I know she's our teammate,
but I'm not just going to change my mind.
I'm sorry, I just...
I don't think you know what it's like to be left.
You have a giant family,
recitals to perform at,
dinners to attend.
I didn't have any of that.
My mom...
...left me.
Ruby's mom left too.
Tai was always busy with school and Ruby couldn't even talk yet.
I had to pick up the pieces.
I had to keep things together.
Alone.
Weiss, if you have something to say, then say it.
When I was ten, my dad finally admitted to my mom that the only reason he married her
was for the family name.
It was actually on my birthday.
He missed the big dinner,
she got mad,
he finally snapped.
I think she already knew.
Looking back, I think I knew too.
But hearing him say it finally pushed her over the edge.
First it was separate lunches and dinners,
opposite balconies at my recitals,
a glass of wine here, a glass of wine there.
Then, it was no dinners,
no recitals,
a bottle of wine here and...
well, you get the idea.
I'm really sorry.
I shouldn't have assumed.
You're right though. I don't know loneliness like you do.
I have my own version.
And,
I'll bet Blake has her own version too.
She doesn't have to be alone though.
I was here for her.
We all were!
She chose to leave us.
Why do you think she did that?
The entire time Blake was at Beacon, she was afraid to open up to people.
She tried to keep her past separated from us. She tried to protect us.
Eventually, those walls she put up came down.
And the moment they did,
the one thing she was afraid of actually happened.
The universe proved her right.
No one blamed her for anything!
If she had just talked to us, she would've known that!
How could I be there for her if she doesn't let me?
What if I needed her here for me?
I know it's not easy.
I wish she hadn't left too.
The only thing we can do now is be there for her when she's ready.
When she comes back.
If she comes back.
She will.
Yang...
You, Ruby, and even Blake
are more like family to me than my brother or even my own father.
I would do anything for you three,
and I'm willing to bet Blake feels the same way.
So, when she's ready,
I'll be there for her.
And...
...I know we're not as close,...
...but...
I'm here for you too.
Is, uh...
everything okay?
Yeah, it is.
Ilia?
I'm here.
Ilia,
I know you're scared, but you don't have to be.
My family and I, we can keep you safe.
I'm sorry.
You can make it up to me by helping us stop Corsac and Fennec.
No.
I'm sorry.
Wait-
I've got her.
Well done, Sister Trifa
- and to you, Ilia.
Ilia!
What are you doing?!
I tried to warn you, Blake.
I'm sorry.
Don't tell me you're sorry!
But I am.
I am sorry it has to be this way,
but you and your family are holding the Faunus back!
Because we're trying to protect people?!
In what world do you live in where attacking the innocent is the right thing to do?!
The same one as you!
There's no such thing as innocent!
There's no right thing to do! Only what's best for us!
There's the humans that still hate the Faunus,
and there's the others who stand by and let the hate happen!
But you know what snuffs out hate?
Fear.
I don't like hurting people.
But I'll tell you this...
...it's gotten us results.
Yeah,
look where it's gotten you.
We all have to make sacrifices for the greater good,
no matter how much it hurts.
And you think killing me is really for the greater good?
No,
but getting rid of your family is.
You wouldn't!
You can't! I won't let you!
I know.
That's why you're being sent to Mistral.
To Adam.
Ilia, please!
You don't have to do this. This isn't you!
Yes. It. Is!
But I guess back then you were just too busy falling for Adam to notice.
I was always jealous of the way you looked at him.
I wanted you to look at me that way.
But we can't always get what we want!
Yuma, with me.
You two,
get her to the docks.
Let's go, traitor.
Now!
What?!
Thanks for the backup.
Thanks for the invitation. You okay?
No.
You heard Ilia, my family is in danger.
Call the police and let's go!
Right!
Come on, mom, pick up!
Get down!
Get out of my house!
Ghira!
Go find my wife!
I believe it's time our dear chieftain stepped down, brother.
Yes brother, I'm afraid I'm inclined to agree.