Back to the fairytale, back to the show
Back to the wall and there's nowhere to go
Hopeless and desperate, all paths adverse
Things looking bleak, and they're bound to get worse
Helpless and doomed, and there's no way to win
Goals unachievable, faith running thin
Lost and forlorn, impossible odds
That's when you'll learn you've been messing with gods!
Send in your grimm, tear off my limb
Strike me with bolts of lightning
I won't die
The battle seems unwinnable, but all we need's a miracle
We're going up we'll never be denied!
Can't wish away the dismal days
Can't bring back what is gone
Won't waste more tears on yesteryears
Instead we'll carry on
We'll win, we're sure we will endure
And though our goal is far
We'll be the ones to touch the sun
The Triumph will be ours!
Raven, we have a problem.
What is it?
Salem's found us.
Salem...
Okay.
Four of her followers are waiting to speak with you.
Right.
We planned for this...
Bring me my helmet.
I don't recall inviting so many guests into our home.
Either I'm losing my memory,
or you've all lost your spines!
Don't be too upset with them, Raven.
Your men simply recognized the power of a Maiden when they see it.
Which is why we'd like to have a word with you.
Leave us.
Pack your things, then break down camp. We're moving.
Little late to run and hide.
You've been on our master's list for some time, so you must understand that we cannot allow you to slip away.
I know all about your master,
but I don't believe we've met.
We're the guys you should be afraid of.
I doubt anyone should be afraid of you.
Oh yeah?
– Tell that to-
– Quiet.
That's what I thought.
I'm Cinder Fall.
This is my associate, Arthur Watts,
and my disciples,
Emerald and Mercury.
Two children you've tricked into following you,
a disgraced Atlesian scientist,
and a Fall Maiden with a surname so appropriate, she probably picked it herself.
Something tells me you've got more than a slight case of egomania,
is that about right?
Technically, I was also a doctor, but I must say, the rest was spot on.
Aren't you perceptive.
It's what's kept me alive.
I'm afraid the only reason you're still alive is because you have something our master wants.
Of course, if I'm wrong...
Vernal!
So,
this is the long lost Spring Maiden.
Prove it.
Vernal has done well under my guidance.
I'd take that into consideration before you try anything.
Raven, I won't underestimate you, so please don't insult my intelligence.
There is a slim chance you and your Maiden could escape today,
but if you know our master as well as you claim to,
then you know you could never truly escape her.
But we come bearing an olive branch.
The Maidens are merely a means to an end.
Salem's true desires are the Relics locked inside the Huntsman Academies.
Come with us. Allow Vernal here to unlock the Relic of Knowledge,
and all previous acts of defiance against Salem will be forgiven.
It's the best deal either of you are going to get.
You talk as if walking straight into Haven will be easy.
That's because it will be.
Headmaster Lionheart is loyal to Salem.
And now, all we need is the key to the vault.
You're not the only one to turn your back against Oz, Raven.
I'm not helping Salem,
I'm not helping Oz!
I don't want a part in any of this!
That ship sailed when you chose to harbor a Maiden.
But if you come with us to Haven,
we'll leave you, your tribe,
and your little secret to live out the rest of your lives squabbling in the wilderness.
We just...
...need...
...the Relic.
I need time to think this over.
You don't have time.
In two days, Haven Academy will be destroyed by the White Fang.
You're going to choose now.
Backed me into a corner, huh?
So,
are you with us,
or against us?
Agreements like these are built on trust.
And forgive me for saying, but I don't trust a single one of you.
You're going to need to give me more.
You are in a poor position to negotiate.
I want my brother dead.
Qrow?
That's right.
He knows I have Spring.
And if you get your Relic,
he's going to become a problem.
I have enough problems to deal with.
Qrow doesn't trust me, but he does trust Ozpin's other lieutenants.
If Leo really is loyal to you,
then you can order him to invite Qrow into an ambush.
He arrives at Haven, you take him down, you get your Relic,
and we all leave happy.
Now this is a proposition I can get behind.
Alright ladies, let's pause for a moment.
We have one objective -
- retrieving the Relic of Knowledge.
Now Qrow Branwen may be on our list of individuals we would very much like dead,
but he's not going to go down without a fight, and he's not going to go down quietly.
Our advantage here is just as you said - we walk straight into Haven,
no resistance, no one the wiser.
A battle with your brother throws that all out the window.
He's good, but not that good.
All of us against him?
It'll all be over in a heartbeat.
But it's not just him.
He has the students with him.
He has Ruby!
He certainly does.
If we leave the school a bloody mess, we will draw the attention of the authorities!
The Kingdom will be on high alert, and the White Fang's attack will be ruined!
Then we wait.
We wait until the full moon.
Leo invites Qrow and his little fighters to Haven the same night Hazel and Adam arrive with the White Fang.
As soon as the battle is won, the White Fang demolishes Haven,
and any evidence we may have left behind is lost along with the school.
Then, Salem leaves my people alone.
For good.
You have yourself a deal.
Wait.
Don't think I don't see what you're after.
If this falls to pieces over your grudge with a child, I will not be taking the blame.
Then what are you worried about?
Fly back home and tinker with your machines.
And tell Salem
she'll get what she wants
- and more.
Brother!
Hurry!
Dad!
Where's mom?
I'm not sure, I got ambushed right away.
Once we take down Corsac and Fennec...
No, go now.
But-
You keep assuring me your friend isn't a complete waste of space!
Let's see him prove it.
We got this, Blake.
I've wanted to sock these creeps since the day we met!
You'll have to get in line.
Blake, go!
I won't let you down, sir!
Shut up.
You got it!
Yes, Vernal?
I followed them as you asked.
Did they spot you?
Of course not.
They have a ship two klicks west of here,
looks like they're staying there for the night.
Thank you, Vernal.
Anything else?
Do you... actually believe they'll let us go once they have the Relic?
Of course not.
They'll never leave us alone.
Once our purpose has come and gone, we'll be discarded.
Salem only uses people until they are no longer useful.
If we want to have any chance of defending ourselves against her,
then we need this Relic.
If Qrow and those brats want to follow Ozpin, then let them.
When the chaos reaches its peak, we'll grab the Relic and make our escape.
And the fact that your daughter will be a part of all that?
Doesn't matter.
I warned her.
She made her choice.
This path won't be easy for us either,
but we must do what's right for the tribe.
I know.
I'll do whatever it takes.
Good.
Hey, Qrow?
Oz needs to talk to you.