Alright, and you said there were no cameras?
– Yeah, I'm pretty sure-
– Pretty sure?! You work here!
I work in labor! I'm not even allowed near processing.
Ugh, this doesn't feel right.
Maybe we should just leave.
No.
It's time we stood up for ourselves.
Adam!
Our kind's been beaten,
murdered,
treated like dogs!
Taking this Dust is only illegal in the eyes of the same people that call us animals.
Yeah, you're right.
Hey, what's with the custom mask? It kinda makes you look like a Grimm.
We may not want them to know who we are,
but we should make sure they never forget what we looked like.
Now -
it's time we got what we deserved.
Please! We're just trying to pass through!
Well you animals passed through the wrong town!
There's no need for violence!
Surrounded by weaklings
Pathetic and oppressed
Satisfied to gnaw on scraps
Afraid to leave the nest
You'll see
I'm their hero
I'll be lionized
I have the strength to do what's needed
Unify our people
With no compromise
Champion the truth
Until they recognize
Lead them to salvation
And regain our lives!
You're all freaks!
That wasn't necessary.
– This is the very reason they think they can treat-
– Ghira!
He saved your life! He's a hero!
– That was amasing!
– Yeah!
– Awesome!
Blake, I'm sorry.
I told you it was an accident.
Was it?
This wasn't the first time humans have died on missions you led.
How many more accidents are there going to be?
I don't know. I'm out there fighting for us, and when you fight, people get hurt.
What, do you want me to just abandon our cause? Like your parents?
No!
I'm not saying that! I...
I don't know.
I'm sorry. I shouldn't have brought them up.
I just get scared when I feel like you don't believe in me anymore.
I never said that.
Thank you, Blake. It's good to know I've still got you...
Behold your flaccid leaders
Too weak to take the prize
Replace them with a warrior
It's time we mobilize
Depose the feeble cowards
Heed this battle cry
Vengeance on the human filth
The time is now we'll rise
I'm here
I'm your savior
I'll be lionized
I am the path to reclamation
This world will have no peace
Til our dream's realized
No mercy no compassion
Our fate's justified
Time to turn the table
On who's tyrannized!
Adam!
Let's move.
You continue to be an extraordinary resource to this organization.
Everything I do is for the Faunus.
I'm sending you back to Vale.
You are to assume control of the brotherhood there.
Thank you, High Leader.
Adam.
If you continue along this path,
you might just find yourself standing beside me at my throne.
High Leader!
We received a message from Hazel.
The raid on Haven's gonna be a little more complicated than we thought.
Don't worry. Nothing will stop us now.
It's time I got what I deserved.