Red like roses fills my dreams and brings me to the place you rest.
Strawberry Sunrise.
No ice.
Oh, and one of those little umbrellas.
Aren't you a little young to be in this club, Blondie?
Aren't you a little old to have a name like Junior?
So you know who I am.
You got a name, sweetheart?
Yes, Junior, I've got several.
But instead of sweetheart...
...you can just call me sir.
People say you know everything.
Tell me where I can find her and I'll let you go.
I've never seen her before, I swear!
Excuse me?
I swear, sir!
Hmm, looks like we have an audience.
This must kind of embarrassing for you, huh?
Awkward...
Listen, blondie sir.
If you want to make it out of this club alive...
...I suggest you let me go.
Now!
You'll pay for that!
Oh Junior, I was just playing with you!
Don't be so sensitive!
Come on, lets kiss and make up, okay?
White is cold and always yearning, burdened by a royal test.
Huh?
Uh, okay.
Black the beast descends from shadows.
Yellow beauty burns gold.
Mirror, tell me something.
Tell me who's the loneliest of all?
Fear of, what's inside of me.
Tell me can a heart be turned to stone?
Melanie, who is this girl?
I dunno Miltia.
But we should teach her a lesson.
Born with no life... into subjugation
Treated like a worthless animal
Stripped of all rights
Just a lesser being
Crushed by cruel ruthless human rule
When it started
All we wanted was a chance to live our lives
Now in darkness
Taking everything we want and we will rise
We'll rise
From shadows
We'll descend upon the world
Take back what you stole
You're gonna pay for this.
Come at me,
And you'll see,
I'm more than meets the eye.
You think that,
You'll break me,
You're gonna find in time.
You're standing too close to a flame that's burning,
Hotter than the sun in the middle of July.
Sending out your army but you still can't win,
Listen up silly boy cuz I'm gonna tell you why.
I burn.
Can't hold me now
You got nothing that can stop me.
I burn.
Swing all you want.
Like a fever I will take you down.
Yang?
Is that you?
Oh! Hey sis!
What are you doing here?
It's a long story.