Can I ask you something?
Sure.
Why...
Why’d you join the White Fang?
Same reason as you.
But...
But why fight when I pass for Human?
It’s okay.
You're not the first person to ask.
I know I look just like any other Human girl.
And for years,
that’s how I was raised.
We lived in Mantle with the other Faunus working the mines.
But my parents wanted something better for me.
They managed to enroll me in an Atlas prep school.
Hm...
Imagine that -
- a little Faunus girl from Mantle going to the city of dreams.
I felt like a princess.
But I had to follow a set of rules.
No bringing friends home, no talking about my parents…
...and absolutely, under no circumstances,
was I allowed to change colors.
No one could know I was a Faunus.
Sounds terrible.
It wasn't.
It was confusing at first, but
it wasn't hard…
especially if it meant being in Atlas.
Sometimes, the other girls would say things about the Faunus.
That they were animals, that they were dirty, or they lied, and…
I’d say these things with them…
because I felt like I was one of them.
And then,
one day, there was a cave-in at the mines.
I was at school, when the news broke.
Apparently, one of the workers there tripped while handling some agitated Dust crystals.
The explosion caused a chain reaction.
And my...
...friends...
...snickered.
Go!
I lost control.
Every inch of me turned blue as I wept.
And suddenly all the girls that I’d laughed and played with…
...were scared of me.
I'm sorry.
Don't be.
I broke their teeth.
What happened?!
He got away.
I'm sorry.
Show them how you smile
It's only for a while
Take what you need
Leave them to bleed
Let them know bitter
While your revenge is sweet