Hello?
There doesn’t seem to be anyone here.
The White Fang was promised the destruction of Haven, and they’ll have it once we have what we need.
Your plan isn’t going to work, Blake.
Just leave Menagerie before it’s too late.
You’re going to have to make me.
And I’m uhm... looking for someone.
Mistral’s controlled territories are the widest reaching in the world, you know, and that makes it infinitely harder to protect.
We get one shot at this.
If Adam gets his way and Haven falls, it’s only going to make things worse for the Faunus.
We’re better than humans. We have everything humans have and more.
Things are bad, but we can figure this out.
My sister has the Spring Maiden, and I know where she is.
We need to go as soon as possible!
I always knew that I wanted to be more than a farmhand, but...
...who would ask for this?
Can I... help you?