Blake...
...it's time.
Okay.
Looks like we're gonna be doing this the hard way.
Don't be so dramatic.
Intruder, identify yourself.
From shadows
We'll descend upon the world
Take back what you stole
From shadows
We'll reclaim our destiny
Set our future free
And we'll rise
Let's do this.
Above the darkness and the shame
Above the torture and the pain
Above the ridicule and hate
Above the binding of our fate
Perfect.
Move up to the next car.
I'll set the charges.
What about the crew members?
What about them?
Born with no life... into subjugation
Adam!
Treated like a worthless animal
Stripped of all rights
Just a lesser being
Crushed by cruel ruthless human rule
When it started
We need to get out of here.
All we wanted was a chance to live our lives
Now in darkness
Taking everything we want and we will rise
We'll rise
Buy me some time!
Are you sure?
Do it!
Move!
Goodbye.